<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Web-tech | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/categories/web-tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-13T22:43:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discuz安装错误]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/an-error-when-installing-discuz/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-13T14:08:05+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/an-error-when-installing-discuz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>昨天在MBP上安装简体／繁体版本的时候遭遇这么一个错误：</p>

<p>“数据库连接错误”</p>

<p>“No such file or directory”</p>

<p>请返回修复。</p>

<p>除此之外没有任何的线索。这样的提示信息并对下一步解决问题并不能提供任何帮助。</p>

<p>搜索和尝试跟踪错误都无果。最后解决的办法是把缺省的 localhost 改成了 127.0.0.1 ，之后顺利安装！</p>

<p>Discuz，貌似并没有支持响应式，虽然有手机版。</p>

<p>正如Aby跟我说的，移动互联网时代，论坛可能是Out掉的东西了，除了在某些团体和领域局部留存之外。</p>

<p>前几个月用WordPress搭建的WeChat Blog根据访问数据来看，访问量里已经有超过70%的用户是通过移动设备访问的了。这即便对于我这样冲在互联网技术前沿的开发者来说，也是个难以想象的变化异常迅速的现象。Web从PC转到移动端，也就是短短的两年内发生的翻转。</p>

<p>移动端Web，目标响应时间1秒。</p>

<p>Docker容器式配置，极速扩展部署响应。</p>

<p>应用化部署，无感响应体验。</p>

<p>大数据挖掘，移动和社交营销，即时的用户反馈和沟通。</p>

<p>移动互联的时代，无不在追求响应的极速。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress, Golang & Swift]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T11:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;WordPress is web software you can use to create a beautiful website or blog. We like to say that WordPress is both free and priceless at the same time.&rdquo;  &ndash; <a href="http://wordpress.org/">wordpress.org</a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s welcomed worldwide with lots of themes and plugins to enpower its features and functions. WordPress has more than ten years history. But I setup and got into its details only at the end of June this year.</p>

<p>Customize one of its theme to our style, separated it into two versions - one is readonly without admin features as the live product for public, the other is the full version accessible only for internal network.</p>

<p>Cache, Share to facebook and sitemap.xml for SEO is also important features you cannot miss.</p>

<p>Make the blog online in 2 weeks, fixing bugs, improve SEO and share time to time in another 3 weeks.</p>

<p>Now, simple plugins, update themes, shortcode features, wordpress editor - tinymce plugin, facebook share metas &hellip; that&rsquo;s what i got from the one month project with WordPress. It&rsquo;s great to get such a project to get into WordPress, from its apache/nginx settings, .htaccess controls to some coding details all by myself.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the same time, I got another opportunity to practise <a href="http://golang.org">Go Language</a>. It&rsquo;s a simple internal management website with uploads, mysql database operation, oa authorization, handling JSON and sessions.</p>

<p>My first practice on golang is <strong>tof</strong> &ndash; a simple library to implement OA APIs of our company. In fact, it&rsquo;s a golang version from my former nodejs version.</p>

<p>The &ldquo;Notify Me&rdquo; in golang works like a charm. I enjoy coding in go.</p>

<p>I cannot stop learning those wonderful programming techs. I&rsquo;m reading on the Swift book on iBook. There&rsquo;s lots of coding styles of Swift and Golang are alike. As a Front-End JavaScript developer, It&rsquo;s a enjoyment.</p>

<p>Any opportunity to practise the Swift? I&rsquo;m so sure there will be one :-)</p>

<p>I like Golang, maybe Swift too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook Open Sourcing Paper Animation Engine Pop]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/facebook-open-sourcing-paper-animation-engine-pop/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T11:09:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/facebook-open-sourcing-paper-animation-engine-pop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Pop animation engine is responsible for all of the transitions and animations displayed on Paper, including all scrolling, bouncing, and unfolding effects.</p>

<p>source code: <a href="https://github.com/facebook/pop">https://github.com/facebook/pop</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Extract Strings From Source Codes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/how-to-extract-strings-from-source-codes/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T08:26:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/how-to-extract-strings-from-source-codes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;d developed a simple online tool (Using <a href="http://nodejs.org">Node.JS</a>) to extract Chinese strings and merge translations automatically before, in a global mail project.</p>

<p>The tool doesn&rsquo;t care about the source languages. it extracts non-ascii line-based strings, skipping something else - such as HTML codes.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a simple aid tool only, not much time to improve.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m always searching open source tools to extract strings from all kinds of source codes, but it seems no such a stuff.</p>

<p>Last month, I found one: the <a href="http://highlightjs.org/">highlightjs</a>!</p>

<p>Yes, it knows lots of programming languages - that&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m looking for.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I try to update the core js to testing the idea - it works: Using syntax highlight library to extract strings.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s great!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Kinds of 2048!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/all-kinds-of-2048/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T08:17:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/all-kinds-of-2048</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在 Flappy Bird 的疯狂Clone之后，又有了 2048 复制 three 的疯狂。</p>

<p>Exploring the open source 2048 game javascript examples</p>

<p><a href="http://learnjs.io/blog/2014/03/17/exploring-open-source-2048-game-javascript-examples/">http://learnjs.io/blog/2014/03/17/exploring-open-source-2048-game-javascript-examples/</a></p>

<p>2048玩法思路【果壳日志】</p>

<p><a href="http://www.guokr.com/blog/748078/">http://www.guokr.com/blog/748078/</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>More 2048
<a href="http://cyberzhg.github.io/2048/">http://cyberzhg.github.io/2048/</a></p>

<p>源码：<a href="https://github.com/CyberZHG/2048">https://github.com/CyberZHG/2048</a></p>

<p>从2 到 2048 需要</p>

<p>2 - 4 - 8 - 16 - 32 - 64 - 128 - 256 - 512 - 1024 - 2048 - &hellip;</p>

<p>即 2<sup>1</sup>  &hellip;. 2<sup>11</sup>， 需提供11种状态即可到2048</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
