<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web-tech | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/categories/web-tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-09T12:27:39+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress, Golang & Swift]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T11:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;WordPress is web software you can use to create a beautiful website or blog. We like to say that WordPress is both free and priceless at the same time.&#8221;  &#8211; <a href="http://wordpress.org/">wordpress.org</a></p>

<p>It&#8217;s welcomed worldwide with lots of themes and plugins to enpower its features and functions. WordPress has more than ten years history. But I setup and got into its details only at the end of June this year.</p>

<p>Customize one of its theme to our style, separated it into two versions - one is readonly without admin features as the live product for public, the other is the full version accessible only for internal network.</p>

<p>Cache, Share to facebook and sitemap.xml for SEO is also important features you cannot miss.</p>

<p>Make the blog online in 2 weeks, fixing bugs, improve SEO and share time to time in another 3 weeks.</p>

<p>Now, simple plugins, update themes, shortcode features, wordpress editor - tinymce plugin, facebook share metas &#8230; that&#8217;s what i got from the one month project with WordPress. It&#8217;s great to get such a project to get into WordPress, from its apache/nginx settings, .htaccess controls to some coding details all by myself.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the same time, I got another opportunity to practise <a href="http://golang.org">Go Language</a>. It&#8217;s a simple internal management website with uploads, mysql database operation, oa authorization, handling JSON and sessions.</p>

<p>My first practice on golang is <strong>tof</strong> &#8211; a simple library to implement OA APIs of our company. In fact, it&#8217;s a golang version from my former nodejs version.</p>

<p>The &#8220;Notify Me&#8221; in golang works like a charm. I enjoy coding in go.</p>

<p>I cannot stop learning those wonderful programming techs. I&#8217;m reading on the Swift book on iBook. There&#8217;s lots of coding styles of Swift and Golang are alike. As a Front-End JavaScript developer, It&#8217;s a enjoyment.</p>

<p>Any opportunity to practise the Swift? I&#8217;m so sure there will be one :-)</p>

<p>I like Golang, maybe Swift too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook open sourcing Paper animation engine Pop]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/facebook-open-sourcing-paper-animation-engine-pop/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T11:09:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/facebook-open-sourcing-paper-animation-engine-pop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Pop animation engine is responsible for all of the transitions and animations displayed on Paper, including all scrolling, bouncing, and unfolding effects.</p>

<p>source code: <a href="https://github.com/facebook/pop">https://github.com/facebook/pop</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Extract Strings from Source Codes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/how-to-extract-strings-from-source-codes/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T08:26:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/how-to-extract-strings-from-source-codes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d developed a simple online tool (Using <a href="http://nodejs.org">Node.JS</a>) to extract Chinese strings and merge translations automatically before, in a global mail project.</p>

<p>The tool doesn&#8217;t care about the source languages. it extracts non-ascii line-based strings, skipping something else - such as HTML codes.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a simple aid tool only, not much time to improve.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m always searching open source tools to extract strings from all kinds of source codes, but it seems no such a stuff.</p>

<p>Last month, I found one: the <a href="http://highlightjs.org/">highlightjs</a>!</p>

<p>Yes, it knows lots of programming languages - that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m looking for.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I try to update the core js to testing the idea - it works: Using syntax highlight library to extract strings.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s great!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All Kinds of 2048!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/all-kinds-of-2048/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-02T08:17:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/05/02/all-kinds-of-2048</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在 Flappy Bird 的疯狂Clone之后，又有了 2048 复制 three 的疯狂。</p>

<p>Exploring the open source 2048 game javascript examples</p>

<p><a href="http://learnjs.io/blog/2014/03/17/exploring-open-source-2048-game-javascript-examples/">http://learnjs.io/blog/2014/03/17/exploring-open-source-2048-game-javascript-examples/</a></p>

<p>2048玩法思路【果壳日志】</p>

<p><a href="http://www.guokr.com/blog/748078/">http://www.guokr.com/blog/748078/</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>More 2048
<a href="http://cyberzhg.github.io/2048/">http://cyberzhg.github.io/2048/</a></p>

<p>源码：<a href="https://github.com/CyberZHG/2048">https://github.com/CyberZHG/2048</a></p>

<p>从2 到 2048 需要</p>

<p>2 - 4 - 8 - 16 - 32 - 64 - 128 - 256 - 512 - 1024 - 2048 - &#8230;</p>

<p>即 2<sup>1</sup>  &#8230;. 2<sup>11</sup>， 需提供11种状态即可到2048</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A false linkable text sample]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/03/20/a-false-linkable-text-sample/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T05:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/03/20/a-false-linkable-text-sample</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found a link in a Google+ post failed to be opened someday. It&#8217;s awkful, right? It&#8217;s on Google+! The Google - who leads the web tech.</p>

<p>Then I confirmed the same false link sample showing up in BlackBerry 10.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve double checked it in my WeChat under Android - it&#8217;s there too. But not in the WeChat for BlackBerry 10.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The false link sample is like this:</p>

<p><strong>(http://mindon.github.io?testing)&#8230;something-else</strong></p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a snapshot from Google+</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/false-link.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The case is showing up almost everywhere - we are using the same library to detect links.</p>

<p>Our test team and I could not accept this result in WeChat for BlackBerry 10, then here comes my customized linkable text detecting code in JavaScript.</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/mindon/9317393.js"></script>


<p>It helps to avoid this issue and provides you the customized possibility.</p>

<p><span id="link-tags">WeChat;BlackBerry 10;Google+</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
