<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Light-Air-Water-M-Sci | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/categories/light-air-water-m-sci/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-19T16:07:06+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The eye limits the brain's learning potential]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/the-eye-limits-the-brains-learning-potential/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T08:12:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/the-eye-limits-the-brains-learning-potential</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The concept of a critical period for visual development early in life during which sensory experience is essential to normal neural development is now well established. However recent evidence suggests that a limited degree of plasticity remains after this period and well into adulthood. Here, we ask the question, "what limits the degree of plasticity in adulthood?" Although this limit has been assumed to be due to neural factors, we show that the optical quality of the retinal image ultimately limits the brain potential for change. We correct the high-order aberrations (HOAs) normally present in the eye's optics using adaptive optics, and reveal a greater degree of neuronal plasticity than previously appreciated.</p>

<p>[<a href="http://www.nature.com/srep/2012/120413/srep00364/full/srep00364.html">read the full version article</a>]</p>

<p>Nature集团新刊《Scientific Reports》于4月16日在线发表了中国科学技术大学脑功能与脑疾病中科院重点实验室及生命科学学院周逸峰研究小组和中国科学院成都光电技术研究所自适应光学重点实验室张雨东研究小组的合作研究成果。</p>

<p>他们通过实验证明，即便是发育成熟之后正常成年视觉神经系统仍具有相当程度的可塑性，但这些可塑性的发挥受限于人眼的光学系统质量。在使用人眼自适应光学矫正仪提高人眼光学系统质量后进行知觉学习训练可以大幅度提高正常成人的视觉功能。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>视觉神经科学中的一个基本理论是“视皮层的发育具有关键期”，在关键期关闭之前视皮层较容易被改变，而关键期关闭之后则较难被改变。目前，很多知觉学习上的证据表明，即使是成年的视皮层也存在一定的可塑性。然而，对正常成人而言，这种在知觉学习过程中体现出的可塑性虽然存在，其程度却非常小。这极大的限制了知觉学习在提高成人视功能中应用。</p>

<p>另一方面，视光学领域的研究者发现：人眼并非一个完美的光学系统，除了大家所熟知的近视、远视和散光等在内的低阶像差外，还存在大量的难以用普通光学手段测量和矫正的高阶像差。近些年来，使用原先应用在天文学上的自适应光学矫正技术，视光学领域的研究者们通过矫正人眼高阶像差部分提高了成人视功能。但对正常成人而言，这种视功能上的提高很微弱，远达不到理论期望值；且无法脱离自适应光学矫正仪器而存在，因此也无法有效应用于成人视力的提高中。</p>

<p>尽管视知觉学习与人眼自适应光学这两个领域的研究者们对如何更好的提高视功能都报以极大的研究热情，但限于研究手段的单一，目前两方面的研究都在一定程度上达到了瓶颈。双方都迫切需要跨学科的先进技术与之结合来扩展思路。而到目前为止，结合自适应光学技术研究视知觉学习的学习效果、相关机制及应用的研究鲜有报道。在此背景下，周逸峰研究小组和张雨东研究小组将视知觉学习与人眼自适应光学技术相结合，取得了创新研究成果。</p>

<p>他们比较了在矫正人眼高阶像差情况下（此时有较理想的人眼光学系统）对比度检测任务的知觉学习和不矫正人眼高阶像差情况下（普通的人眼光学系统）同样任务的知觉学习中，被试者对比敏感度和视力提高程度的差异。结果发现，在知觉学习训练后高阶像差矫正组在对比敏感度和视力上都有了显著的提高，而且这种提高至少可以维持5个月以上；而非高阶像差矫正组对比敏感度只有少量提高，视力水平无显著提高。</p>

<p>他们的结果表明，发育关键期之后的正常成年视觉神经系统仍具有相当程度的可塑性，但这些可塑性的发挥受限于训练时人眼的光学系统成像质量。只有当高阶像差被矫正时，视觉系统的可塑性才能得到发挥。该发现可以用于探索新的治疗方法来提高视力低下患者的视功能。同时，还为结合人眼自适应光学矫正技术和视知觉学习来达到“超视力”提供了可能。</p>

<p>这项研究工作是在国家重点基础研究发展计划973项目、国家自然科学基金重点项目、成都光电所前沿研究项目等基金的共同资助下完成。加拿大McGill大学视觉研究所所长Robert Hess教授一起合作完成了部分实验设计、数据处理及论文写作工作。本工作的技术部分于2011年9月20日获得两项美国发明专利授权。</p>

<p><a href="http://biox.ustc.edu.cn/xydt/201204/t20120417_133360.html">来源 - 中科大生命学院</a></p>

<p><a href="http://211.157.104.87:8080/sipo/zljs/hyjs-yx-new.jsp?recid=CN200910262470.4&amp;leixin=fmzl&amp;title=%C8%CB%D1%DB%D7%D4%CA%CA%D3%A6%B9%E2%D1%A7%CA%D3%D6%AA%BE%F5%D1%A7%CF%B0%D1%B5%C1%B7%B7%BD%B7%A8%BA%CD%D1%A7%CF%B0%D1%B5%C1%B7%D2%C7">国家专利链接</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lasers Can Be Used to Steer Lightning In Mid-Strike]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/lasers-can-be-used-to-steer-lightning-in-mid-strike/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T22:23:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/lasers-can-be-used-to-steer-lightning-in-mid-strike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Laser light can not only trigger lightning but redirect it, causing it to strike in the same place over and over, according to new research. This means lasers could serve as lightning rods. Because that would be awesome.</p>

<p>Laser lightning rods have been a research subject for several decades, because they could trigger lightning and guide it to a specific place. Firing a laser would create an ionized channel in the atmosphere, which could conduct the lightning to the ground. Laser lightning rods could be an alternative to lightning rockets, according to Aurlien Houard of the Laboratoire d'Optique Appliquée in Palaiseau, France, a co-author of this study. Lightning rockets can apparently trigger a lightning strike by bringing a conductive material, like some type of salts, toward the static layer of a thunderhead. But a laser would be easier to control than a rocket.</p>

<p>A team of French researchers set out to test how well lasers can harness and control lightning. They sent a laser beam past a spherical electrode toward an oppositely charged flat electrode. The laser stripped away the outer electrons from the atoms in its way, ionizing the pathway between the electrodes and creating a plasma filament — like lab lightning — that channeled an electrical discharge from the flat electrode to the spherical one.</p>

<p>Then the team added a longer, pointed electrode to their set of electrode shapes and watched what happened. Left to its own devices, lightning follows the path of least resistance, striking the first thing it comes across — in a thunderstorm, that’s the tallest thing, and in this experiment, it’s the nearest thing. With no laser lightning rod, the discharge predictably hit the tall pointed electrode first. But when the researchers used the laser filament to guide it, the electrical discharge followed the ionized path and hit the spherical electrode instead.</p>

<p>The team found they could pull this off even after the discharge was already on its way, meaning they could divert the path of lightning. The research appears in the American Institute of Physics journal <a href="http://aipadvances.aip.org/resource/1/aaidbi/v2/i1/p012151_s1?bypassSSO=1">AIP Advances</a>.</p>

<p>Original from POPSCI: <a href="http://www.popsci.com/technology/article/2012-03/lightning-can-strike-twice-if-you-have-some-lasers">Lasers Can Be Used to Steer Lightning In Mid-Strike</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inside the Lytro: Light Field Camera]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/05/inside-the-lytro-light-field-camera/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-05T21:32:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/05/inside-the-lytro-light-field-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times: <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2012/03/01/business/inside-the-lytro.html">Inside the Lytro</a></p>

<p>The Lytro camera is the first consumer “light field camera.” It uses a new technology to create photos that can have their focus changed after they have been taken. Because of this, there is no need to auto-focus, resulting in virtually no shutter delay. Here’s how it works.</p>

<h2>Camera Overview</h2>

<p>A Lytro camera is made up of two sections. An anodized aluminum shell contains the lens assembly, while the electronics are housed within a silicone rubber grip.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/lytro-cross-section.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Capturing Light</h2>

<p>Lytro’s light field sensor captures not only the color, intensity and position of the light, but also its direction, which is lost in traditional cameras.</p>

<h2>Changing Focus</h2>

<p>Because all the directional information of the entering light is captured, software can change the focal plane. Clicking any point on the image brings that area into focus, whether raindrops on the surface of a window or buildings beyond.</p>

<h2>Light Field Sensor</h2>

<p>Consists of a standard digital camera CMOS sensor coupled with a micro-lens array. The array contains thousands of miniature lenses.</p>

<h2>Micro-Lens Array</h2>

<p>Tiny lenses divide the CMOS sensor’s pixels into multiple areas, each showing the image at a slightly different angle. Software uses this data to triangulate the image in 3-D space.</p>

<h2>Controlling the Camera</h2>

<p>Lytro uses a 1.46-inch touch screen. Swiping back and forth allows you to view previous or later photos, while swiping up brings up a menu bar. The shutter button and a slider for the zoom are molded into the top of the unit, while the power button and a USB connector are on the bottom.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.lytro.com/science_inside">Lytro: Science Inside</a>, <a href="http://www.lytro.com/">Lytro</a></p>

<p><a href="http://graphics.stanford.edu/papers/fourierphoto/">http://graphics.stanford.edu/papers/fourierphoto/</a></p>

<h2>Lytro Light Field Camera</h2>

<p><strong>GOOD STUFF</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Light Field technology is amazing</p></li>
<li><p>Gorgeous, conversation-starting design</p></li>
<li><p>Fast and reliable performance</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>BAD STUFF</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Aside from the focusing effect, image quality is mediocre</p></li>
<li><p>Only works really well in a few situations</p></li>
<li><p>Desktop software is a bear</p></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/2/29/2821763/lytro-review">Lytro Review</a></p>

<p>Lytro是一家位于硅谷的创业公司，源于公司CEO Ren Ng在斯坦福的一项研究，其目标很简单：凭借其光场（light field）相机「硬件和软件」，Lytro可以从很多方面改变照相技术，因为有了它你无需对焦。</p>

<p>与此同时，这家公司的投资方包括Andreessen Horowitz和Greylock等知名投资机构，其技术团队包括Silicon Graphics联合创始人以及Palm webOS的首席架构师。那么Lytro的魅力到底在哪里呢？</p>

<p>答案是「光场（light field）照相」或者说「全光（plenoptic）照相」。Lytro背后的核心思维源于斯坦福的一篇论文「PDF文档」，原理非常简单。普通相机的工作原理和肉眼差不多，前面的镜头可以收集来自前方的光线，然后通过传感器上的光圈「单反相机上的硅胶套或眼睛里的视网膜」。为了聚焦眼睛或普通照相机，你通过不同方式调整镜头，以捕捉来自不同方向的光线，将其收集到传感器中。这会带来很多副作用，其中之一就是只能有一个焦点。这让问题变得复杂，当然如果手法得当的话可以拍出漂亮的照片。</p>

<p>但Lytro的技术之一就是在相机传感器前面布有大量微镜头。你可以把它们想象成苍蝇眼睛上的数千个微型镜头。其中的物理学和数学知识有点复杂，但最后的结果是这样的：相机传感器记录下的不是单一的图像「由镜头、光圈等设置决定」，Lytro相机可以用复杂的方式记录下来自前方场景各个部位的光线，而不仅仅是普通相机那样只能记下聚焦范围中的光线。然后Lytro软件会对图像进行解码。</p>

<p><embed src="http://player.youku.com/player.php/sid/XMjc5NDc5NDY4/v.swf" allowFullScreen="true" quality="high" width="480" height="400" align="middle" allowScriptAccess="always" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"></embed></p>

<p>这就是神奇之处。因为这个系统可以捕捉有关场景光线方向的信息，因此它可以“聚焦”照片中的任何深度，哪怕在拍照后数年。一瞬间你就可以获得理想的照片，相机可以去掉笨重、耗电和昂贵的聚焦系统，你可以更快地完成拍照，即便非专业摄影师也不必担心对焦问题。镜头还可以捕捉弱光环境下的光线。这会产生很大的影响，可能会对整个相机业带来巨大变革。</p>

<p>... 36氪<a href="http://www.36kr.com/p/30873.html">Lytro光场相机原理和应用浅析</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Really Can Catch Lightning in a Bottle]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/you-really-can-catch-lightning-in-a-bottle/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T14:41:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/you-really-can-catch-lightning-in-a-bottle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>一群材料学家发现，从工业玻璃中抽出极细的一根玻璃丝，可以用来储藏和释放惊人的电量。</p>

<p>这事听起来有点荒诞，但其结果经过证明，确是千真万确。一群材料学家发现，从工业玻璃中抽出极细的一根玻璃丝，可以用来储藏和释放惊人的电量。把玻璃丝夹在两块金属板之间用作为电容器的一部分，该玻璃丝可为像心脏震颤器等设备提供大量的能量，甚至可以为新一代电动汽车提供能量。</p>

<p>【译言网】全文: <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/289907/255207">捕捉瓶中闪电</a></p>

<p>Here's something that sounds preposterous but as it turns out, it's actually true. Take a very thinly drawn piece of industrial glass, and you can use it to store and release a surprising amount of electricity, a group of materials scientists has found. When sandwiched between two metal plates as part of a device called a capacitor, the glass slivers could provide large bursts of energy for devices such as heart defibrillators, and they could even help power the next generation of electric vehicles.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Usually a rectangular plate of material, capacitors are essential to electronics because they can perform tasks that batteries can't. Each contains a material called a dielectric, which can store electrical energy and then release it in a large burst. Capacitors are much faster than batteries at charging and releasing electricity, which makes them ideal for providing the pulses of power required by camera flashes and diesel engine starters. They can also endure millions of cycles of charging and discharging, compared to mere thousands of cycles for conventional rechargeable batteries.</p>

<p>To meet the power demands of modern devices, researchers have been looking for materials that can store more and more electricity. That's where the use of industrial glass comes in. Industrial glass is stronger and more durable than the glass in household windowpanes and mirrors, and it's more resistant to repeated chemical reactions. Materials scientists at Pennsylvania State University, University Park, have now found that an extremely thin piece of the industrial glass called barium boroaluminosilicate--which is used in flat-panel TV displays--can hold more than twice as much electrical charge as polypropylene, which is currently the most common material for high-energy capacitors.</p>

<p>Reporting online this week in Materials Letters, the researchers say they used samples of the glass about 50 micrometers thick, or about half the diameter of a human hair, which they etched in acid until the samples eroded to a thickness of only 10 to 20 micrometers. Then they hooked the samples to two electrodes and applied an increasing voltage to test the material's breakdown strength: its ability to withstand electrical energy. When the material reached this breakdown limit--at about 22,000 volts--the stored energy was released in what resembles "a lightning bolt conducting through air," says co-author Nicholas Smith.</p>

<p>The ability of the glass to hold so much charge renders it "of prime interest to people who make capacitors and other energy storage devices," Smith says. He adds that the low cost of the material adds to its attractiveness, because researchers have been looking mainly at materials, such as specialty polymers and nanocomposites, that tend to be more expensive.</p>

<p>This could be a breakthrough, says chemical engineer Richard Wool of the University of Delaware, Newark. Wool, who specializes in the chemistry of glass, says the ability of the material to combine high energy storage and high breakdown strength, as well as its low cost, gives it an advantage over currently used materials.</p>

<p>Orignal form <strong>Science Magazine</strong> <a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2009/05/05-02.html">You Really Can Catch Lightning in a Bottle</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty and the Beast: The rare moment a tornado and a rainbow come head to head in Colorado sky]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/beauty-and-the-beast-the-rare-moment-a-tornado-and-a-rainbow-come-head-to-head-in-colorado-sky/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T14:06:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/beauty-and-the-beast-the-rare-moment-a-tornado-and-a-rainbow-come-head-to-head-in-colorado-sky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这是一个罕见的瞬间：一条美丽的彩虹和猛烈的暴风云的短兵相接在天空中创造了一副绚丽的景象。</p>

<p>当巨大的龙卷风开始覆盖美国科罗拉多州上方的天空时，人们大部分都已经关好了门窗。</p>

<p>但是当龙卷风的威胁变小时，一群幸运的风暴追逐着们看到了罕见的一幕：一条彩虹看上去似乎和龙卷风仅仅相隔了几英里。</p>

<p>【译言网】全文: <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/281379/254395">美女与野兽：美国科罗拉多州天空的罕见瞬间——龙卷风与彩虹的短兵相接</a></p>

<p>This is the rare moment a beautiful rainbow and violent storm cloud came head to head creating a stunning scene high in the sky.
As the monster tornado began to dominate the skies over Colorado, USA, most people would have been locking their doors and windows.
But as the threat diminished one lucky group of storm chasers saw the rare sight of a rainbow and tornado seemingly just a few miles apart.</p>

<p><img src="/law-ms/tornado-rainbow.jpg" alt="Tornado and Rainbow " />
Rare sight: As the monster tornado began to dominate the skies over Colorado, USA, most people would have been locking their doors and windows, but one lucky group of storm chasers saw the rare sight of a rainbow and tornado</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The magnificent moment was captured by dedicated Dutch storm chaser Peter Gude, 47, who couldn't believe his eyes as he spotted the unusual scene.</p>

<p>With the month of March looming, United States tornado chasers are already watching the Southeast as a nasty storm brews with the potential to spin off a batch of tornadoes.</p>

<p>But if funnel clouds develop Thursday or Friday as some forecasters believe, they won't be the first.</p>

<p>This tornado season got an early and deadly start in late January when two people were killed by separate twisters in Alabama.</p>

<p>Preliminary reports showed 95 tornadoes struck last month, compared with 16 in January during a particularly stormy 2011.</p>

<p>The season usually starts in March and then ramps up for the next couple of months, but forecasting these storm seasons is even more imprecise than predicting hurricane seasons.</p>

<p>Tornadoes are too small and too short-lived for scientists to make seasonal predictions.</p>

<p>They don't develop like blizzards and hurricanes, which are easier to project.</p>

<p>They pop in and pop out. The storms that give them birth may last only a few hours. Hurricanes and blizzards are lumbering beasts that spend days moving across the satellite maps.</p>

<p>When a hurricane approaches, coastlines get days warning to evacuate.</p>

<p>With a tornado, if the weather service can let people know 20 minutes in advance, it's considered a victory.</p>

<p>'The Joplin (Missouri) tornado (that killed 158 people last May) wasn't violent until just about the time it got to the hospital," said Harold Brooks, a research scientist at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration's National Severe Storms Laboratory, in Norman, Oklahoma.</p>

<p>'Even when you're in the field, there are still times when you're surprised by the intensity of the event and how quickly it started.'</p>

<p>If a forecast for a hurricane or blizzard is off by a mile, it's still bad weather. But a mile difference means no damage in a tornado, Brooks said: 'It's so much finer in time and space on the tornado, it does make it a harder problem.'</p>

<p>It takes a piece of debris only a few seconds to fly around an entire tornado; it takes hours to circle a hurricane. But tornadoes, though smaller, can have stronger winds.</p>

<p>Since 1950, there have been 58 tornadoes in the U.S. with winds exceeding 200 mph; six last year alone. Only three hurricanes have made U.S. landfall with winds more than 155 mph.</p>

<p>Original from <strong>MailOnline</strong> <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2105422/Beauty-Beast-The-moment-twister-rainbow-battle-space-sky.html">Beauty and the Beast: The rare moment a tornado and a rainbow come head to head in Colorado sky</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
