<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-25T23:56:14+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web-Drawing Throwdown: Paper.js Vs. Processing.js Vs. Raphael]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-dot-js-vs-processing-dot-js-vs-raphael/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T23:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-dot-js-vs-processing-dot-js-vs-raphael</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before drawing anything in a browser, ask yourself three questions:</p>

<ol>
<li><em>Do you need to support older browsers?</em></li>
</ol>


<p>If the answer is yes, then your only choice is Raphaël. It handles browsers all the way back to IE 7 and Firefox 3. Raphaël even has some support for IE 6, although some of its underlying technology cannot be implemented there.</p>

<ol>
<li><em>Do you need to support Android?</em></li>
</ol>


<p>Android doesn’t support SVG, so you’ll have to use Paper.js or Processing.js. Some rumors say that Android 4 will handle SVG, but the majority of Android devices won’t support it for years.</p>

<ol>
<li><em>Is your drawing interactive?</em></li>
</ol>


<p>Raphaël and Paper.js focus on interaction with drawn elements through clicking, dragging and touch. Processing.js doesn’t support any object-level events, so responding to user gestures is very difficult. Processing.js can draw a cool animation on your home page, but the other tools are better for interactive applications.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Paper.js, Processing.js and Raphaël are the leading libraries for drawing on the Web right now. A couple of others are up and coming, and you can always use Flash, but these three work well with HTML5 and have the widest support among browser vendors.</p>

<p>Choosing the right framework will determine the success of your project. This article covers the advantages and disadvantages of each, and the information you need to make the best choice.</p>

<p>All of the code in this article is open source and can be run on the demo page that accompanies this article.</p>

<p>[Note: Have you already pre-ordered your copy of our Printed Smashing Book #3? The book is a professional guide on how to redesign websites and it also introduces a whole new mindset for progressive Web design, written by experts in the industry for you. Pre-order now and add your name into the book!]</p>

<h2>Overview</h2>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th></th>
<th align="left"> Paper.js </th>
<th align="right"> Processing.js </th>
<th align="center"> Raphaël.js </th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left"> Technology </td>
<td align="right"> canvas tag </td>
<td align="center"> canvas tag | SVG |</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left">  Language </td>
<td align="right"> PaperScript </td>
<td align="center"> Processing script | JavaScript | </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left">  Browsers </td>
<td align="right"> IE 9 </td>
<td align="center"> IE 9 | IE 7 | </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left">  Mobile </td>
<td align="right"> Yes </td>
<td align="center"> Yes | iOS only | </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left">  Model </td>
<td align="right"> Vector and raster </td>
<td align="center"> Raster | Vector | </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td align="left">  Size </td>
<td align="right"> 56 KB </td>
<td align="center"> 64 KB | 20 KB | </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>Full article could be found from <em>Zack Grossbart</em>&#8217;s <a href="http://coding.smashingmagazine.com/2012/02/22/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-processing-raphael/">Web-Drawing Throwdown: Paper.js Vs. Processing.js Vs. Raphael</a></p>

<p>with demos <a href="http://zgrossbart.github.com/3gears/">http://zgrossbart.github.com/3gears/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 Things You Didn't Know About... Magnetism]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-dot-dot-dot-magnetism/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-24T13:37:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-dot-dot-dot-magnetism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li><p>Magnetism is familiar to every fifth grader, but describing it can confound even the most brilliant physicist.</p></li>
<li><p>Take the case of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Richard Feynman</a>. When asked to explain magnetism, he <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wMFPe-DwULM">urged his BBC interviewer to take it on faith</a> (video). After seven minutes of stonewalling, he finally said, “I really can’t do a good job, any job, of explaining magnetic force in terms of something else that you’re more familiar with because I don’t understand it in terms of anything else that you’re more familiar with.”</p></li>
</ol>


<!--more-->


<ol>
<li><p>He did break down and try for a few seconds before abandoning the attempt. Those seconds were packed with oversimplifications: “All the electrons [in a magnet] are spinning in the same direction.”</p></li>
<li><p>But who better than Feynman would have known that not all electrons spin in the same direction?</p></li>
<li><p>And they don’t actually spin. “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spin_%28physics%29">Spin</a>” is just a physicist’s term for the little magnetic north and south poles baked into every electron. The orientation of those poles defines the direction of the electron’s (somewhat imaginary) rotation.</p></li>
<li><p>Why does every electron have those poles? As soon as someone finds out, we’ll get back to you.</p></li>
<li><p>Here is what we do know. Within an atom, each electron is usually paired with an opposite- oriented electron so that their magnetic pulls cancel each other out.</p></li>
<li><p>But if some of the electrons are unpaired, they can be induced to move around so that their poles line up, creating a net magnetic field. The arrangement of the electrons in metals makes them particularly open to magnetic peer pressure.</p></li>
<li><p>DIY refrigerator magnet: Apply an external magnetic field to some hot metal. Cool it so the aligned electrons get frozen in place. Slap on your local plumber’s business card, and—voilà!</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/653297/yinyang">Yin Seeks Yang</a> for Magnetic Relationship. All magnets have north and south poles, and opposite poles attract: North poles seek south poles seek north poles seek south poles seek . . .</p></li>
<li><p>You are standing on a magnet right now. The earth’s magnetic field is created by electric currents in an ocean of molten iron at its core. That’s why the north pole of a compass needle points . . . er . . . why north? Since north poles are attracted to south poles, the “north” arrow on your compass actually points toward the earth’s south magnetic pole, which is the one up north. Got it?</p></li>
<li><p>And the earth’s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Magnetic_Pole">magnetic south</a> (aka “north”) pole isn’t even precisely at the geographic north pole. Right now it is in the Arctic Ocean, near northern Canada.</p></li>
<li><p>Worse still, it is constantly drifting in response to currents in the earth’s core. It is moving toward Siberia at a rate of up to 35 miles per year, according to the U.S. Geological Survey. Hey, shift happens.</p></li>
<li><p>Ancient mariners navigated by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lodestone">lodestone</a>, naturally occurring magnetic rocks.</p></li>
<li><p>Where lodestones come from is another mystery of magnetism. Some geologists think they are created when lighting strikes iron-rich rocks.</p></li>
<li><p>Microbes, birds, and some other animals have magnetic crystals inside their bodies that allow them to orient themselves.</p></li>
<li><p>That is probably why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loggerhead_sea_turtle">loggerhead turtles</a> can migrate 8,000 miles in unfamiliar waters while humans can get lost looking for the restroom at Olive Garden.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetic_resonance_imaging">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</a> (MRI) machines generate a field 60,000 times as intense as the earth’s to vibrate the hydrogen atoms in your body; in response, the atoms emit radio waves that are analyzed to produce a map of your insides.</p></li>
<li><p>Using a sensor the size of a sugar cube, researchers from the <a href="http://www.nist.gov/index.html">National Institute of Standards and Technology</a> can <a href="http://www.nist.gov/pml/div688/magnetic_101310.cfm">track the magnetic pattern of a human heart</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>The signal is faint, but the good news is that science has proved attraction is quantifiable. Word up, Hallmark.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>from <a href="http://discovermagazine.com/2011/jul-aug/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-magnetism">http://discovermagazine.com/2011/jul-aug/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-magnetism</a></p>

<p>Chinese version (中文: 关于磁&#8211;你所不知道的二十件事) <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/159732/253517">http://article.yeeyan.org/view/159732/253517</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water Walking]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/water-walking/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T13:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/water-walking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A water layer was sprinkled with Thymol Blue, which established the Marangoni convection responsible for the evident fine-scale texture. The layer was lit from below, giving the flow a natural luminescence. Stopping vortices shed during the deceleration phase of the strider&#8217;s motion are evident in Figure 2.  The dipolar vortices shed by the driving legs during each stroke are evident in Figure 3, and mark the path of the strider. The starburst in Figure 3 is associated with the relatively large particle of thymol blue evident at its centre: the Thymol Blue reduces the local surface tension, thus prompting surface divergence that clears the surface of blue dye.  The water striders are light-seeking, and so drawn to the starbursts.</p>

<p><img src="http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/icarus.jpg" alt="Water Walking" /></p>

<p>Read detail from <a href="http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/striderweb.html">http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/striderweb.html</a>
<a href="http://www.me.gatech.edu/hu/">http://www.me.gatech.edu/hu/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dive into Node.JS]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/dive-into-node-dot-js/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T15:29:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/dive-into-node-dot-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Node.js is a platform built on Chrome&#8217;s JavaScript runtime for easily building fast, scalable network applications. Node.js uses an event-driven, non-blocking I/O model that makes it lightweight and efficient, perfect for data-intensive real-time applications that run across distributed devices.
<a href="http://nodejs.org">http://nodejs.org</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Felix&#8217;s Node.js Guide
<a href="http://nodeguide.com/">http://nodeguide.com/</a></p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/beginner.html">Node.js Beginner Guide</a>
If you are new to node.js, this guide will take you from hello world to deploying your first app.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/style.html">Node.js Style Guide</a>
The general JavaScript style I recommend to use with node.js. A lot of this is personal preferences, but hopefully rather consistent.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/community.html">Node.js Community Guide</a>
Get to know some of the node.js community and find out where they hang out.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/convincing_the_boss.html">Node.js Convincing The Boss Guide</a>
Find out where node.js makes sense, and how to get management to see the benefits.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>NodeJS – The what, why, how and when
<a href="http://blog.xebia.com/2011/08/16/nodejs-the-what-why-how-and-when/">http://blog.xebia.com/2011/08/16/nodejs-the-what-why-how-and-when/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Images Optimization]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/web-images-optimization/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T15:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/web-images-optimization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Use PNG! with ImageMagick</p>

<h2>GIF Animation</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://www.lcdf.org/gifsicle/">GitSlice</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  gifsicle -o  test-optimized.gif test.gif</p>

<h2>PNG</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://pmt.sourceforge.net/pngcrush/">PNGCrush</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  pngcrush -rem alla -brute -reduce test.jpg test-optimized.jpg</p>

<h2>JPEG</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://jpegclub.org/jpegtran/">JPEGTran</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  jpegtran -optimize -progressive -copy none -outfile test-optimized.jpg test.jpg</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Reference from <a href="http://www.welefen.com/image-optimization.html">前端优化之图片优化自动化</a></p>

<p>12 Really Useful Image Optimization Tools For Web Designers
<a href="http://www.webdesignbooth.com/12-really-useful-image-optimization-tools-for-web-designers/">http://www.webdesignbooth.com/12-really-useful-image-optimization-tools-for-web-designers/</a></p>

<p>Optimizing Web Graphics: Compression
<a href="http://www.webreference.com/dev/graphics/compress.html">http://www.webreference.com/dev/graphics/compress.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picking the right NoSQL Database]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/nosql-databases/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T13:22:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/nosql-databases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NoSQL = Not Only SQL</p>

<p><a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/271351/239915">8种Nosql数据库系统对比</a></p>

<p><a href="http://kkovacs.eu/cassandra-vs-mongodb-vs-couchdb-vs-redis">Cassandra vs MongoDB vs CouchDB vs Redis vs Riak vs HBase vs Membase vs Neo4j comparison</a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.monitis.com/index.php/2011/05/22/picking-the-right-nosql-database-tool/">Picking the right NoSQL database tool</a></p>

<h2>Key-values Stores</h2>

<p>Tokyo Cabinet/Tyrant, Redis, Voldemort, Oracle BDB</p>

<p>Content caching (Focus on scaling to huge amounts of data, designed to handle massive load), logging, etc.</p>

<p>Strengths: Fast lookups
Weaknesses: Stored data has no schema</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Column Family Stores</h2>

<p>Cassandra, HBase, Riak</p>

<p>Distributed file systems</p>

<p>Strengths: Fast lookups, good distributed storage of data
Weaknesses: Very low-level API</p>

<h2>Document Databases</h2>

<p>CouchDB, MongoDB</p>

<p>Web applications (Similar to Key-Value stores, but the DB knows what the Value is)</p>

<p>Strengths: Tolerant of incomplete data
Weaknesses: Query performance, no standard query syntax</p>

<h2>Graph Databases</h2>

<p>Neo4J, InfoGrid, Infinite Graph</p>

<p>Social networking, Recommendations (Focus on modeling the structure of data - interconnectivity)</p>

<p>Strengths: Graph algorithms e.g. shortest path, connectedness, n degree relationships, etc.
Weaknesses: Has to traverse the entire graph to achieve a definitive answer. Not easy to cluster.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mindon GitHub Blog Start]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/mindon-github-blog-start/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T16:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/mindon-github-blog-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Frameworks &amp; tools for web developer.</p>

<p>Javascript, NodeJS, Chrome App, CorelDraw plug-in &#8230;</p>

<p>Learning web tech &amp; apply them to solve daily problems!</p>

<p>Air off, Mind on ~ :-) 2012</p>

<p>with following tech &amp; tools:
Git tool
github pages
Ruby &amp; Ruby DevKit
RubyGem
Octopress</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
