<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-02T17:17:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[时间和先进]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/time-and-advanced/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T12:26:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/time-and-advanced</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>某些无知的人否定一些东西的时候，总喜欢拿已知的知识和时间是否更靠近现在来作为判断标准。</p>

<p>其实，我们应该意识到3点：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>科学技术一直都是往未知的方向发展的；</p></li>
<li><p>即使是时间也没有否定未知的能力；</p></li>
<li><p>人类的知识还是非常有限的。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>不多说，对比一下 21世纪 Touch Bionics 用尽最先进的科学技术生产的智能仿生手 i-LIMB Hand 和大自然数百万年前生产的人类手</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/ilimb-pulse.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://www.sdmuseum.com/lx_show.aspx?id=5737&amp;cid=60">“手”的进化</a></p>

<p>在绝大多方面，现代医学的技术和人体自身的修复能力还是不能同日而语的，要认识几百万年进化的成果还需不少时日的。</p>

<p>人类的科技还在持续不断发展，而且已经取得了难以置信的成果，然后，相对于大自然和浩瀚宇宙来说，还只是沧海一粟，和大自然数十亿年的积累和进化对比，距离不是一点点。不要再自以为是地否定未知，特别是拿时间来衡量是否先进了。</p>

<p>展望一下医疗的终极未来：身体修复方案和知识共享，并能够自行修复任何损伤和破坏。</p>

<ol>
<li><p>身体能够自动积累和改善修复方案；</p></li>
<li><p>身体能够自行根据修复方案修复问题；</p></li>
<li><p>身体能够自动分享和获取修复方案，并根据自身状况有效调整修复方案；</p></li>
<li><p>身体根据修复方案引领自身寻找修复资源或获取协助；</p></li>
<li><p>身体对环境的威胁给出预警和建议。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>从这5点看来，目前的医疗科技还是相当落后的，挖据身体的潜能，读懂身体的状态指示，协助身体自身的修复才是医疗的未来。</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">Touch Bionics;i-LIMB Hand;手的进化</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[科技+健康生活环境]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/tech-helps-needed-for-a-good-health/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T12:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/tech-helps-needed-for-a-good-health</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>居住在一个大城市里，对生活环境的获取和牺牲都是必然的，科技在这方面能帮到的并不多。</p>

<p>健康的生活环境，以下几点是必须的：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>清新干净空气</p>

<p>这个貌似非常困难，大环境看来，工业/汽车是最大的威胁。</p>

<p>小环境看来，窗户还做不到只让空气进出，把灰尘和有害毒物挡在窗外或直接消化掉。</p></li>
<li><p>安静</p>

<p>环境噪音主要来自汽车，这个也是大环境，暂时是无法消灭的。</p>

<p>小环境来看，对付噪音污染，可以安装隔音玻璃窗，或者搬家，要不就塞住自己的耳朵，此外也别无他法。</p></li>
<li><p>黑夜</p>

<p>大环境光污染更是没办法了，部分昼夜的城市的必然产物。</p>

<p>小环境，拉遮光窗帘还是可以解决的。</p></li>
<li><p>干净安全的饮水和食品</p>

<p>大环境下这个东西只能靠社会良心了。</p>

<p>小环境，可以自己种，或者多花些钱和精力找安全和有良心的来源。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>要对付这些环境对健康的威胁，所谓高速发达的科学技术还是无能为力的。确切地说，这些威胁都来自科技发展的副效应。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>目前唯一能够解决所有这些问题的办法就是，搬到一个远离科技，有大片绿树隔离的村落。</p>

<p>或者，期待科技更进一步，提供更可行的避免过滤尘灰、空气污染、噪音和光污染、食品污染的技术方案。（其实希望并不大，看看北京突破500的PM2.5就知道了）</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">光污染;食品污染;噪音污染;PM2.5</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[在地铁出口离世的年青女子]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/the-young-woman-died-at-the-exit-of-metro/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T20:10:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/the-young-woman-died-at-the-exit-of-metro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>两个星期前的周一（2月17日，2014年）的上午10点29分，在我居住的地方南边约5公里，靠近海边的地铁站——水湾站C出口，一位年仅35岁的未婚女子倒下了，再也没有起来。</p>

<p>一个留英归来在IBM工作的女子生命逝去，其父母已年迈七八十，白发人送黑发人。这不能不说是一个令人心酸、心寒、心痛的悲剧。</p>

<p>女子从倒下到专业救护人员到场，经历了50分钟左右，得不到及时抢救是丢掉性命的关键。</p>

<p>又一条宝贵的生命就这样离去了，给我们带来了什么样的反思呢？</p>

<p>从一个程序员的角度，是系统出故障了，对于这样的状况失去了修复能力。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>人类社会，作为生态系统的一部分，应该具有高度的自我修复能力，就如人类的身体本身一样。</p>

<p>虽说人类的科技能力已经发展飞快，但是女子身上的手机救不了她的性命，随身带者的笔记本电脑也没有任何帮助…</p>

<p>系统故障在于，没有作出最快最有效的能够救助女子性命的响应。附近没有可提供救助的服务，可能有（据说附近20米左右有一间中医理疗店）但获取需要救助信息的人没能有效并及时地把需要救助的信息带到可能提供救助服务的点。</p>

<p>救助信息传到120救助中心，救助人员到达中间过程消耗了30分钟以上，这中间对于出现状况女子的生命来说，每一分每一秒都是至关重要的。</p>

<p>理想的救助系统响应应该是怎样的呢？</p>

<ol>
<li><p>女子倒下，马上激活周边目击行人；</p>

<p>这次事故中，激活救助行为是在3分钟的点，响应迟钝。</p></li>
<li><p>目击人群可能能力：a）普通人：传播需要救助信息到救助服务点；b）半专业人士：提供有利于救助的即时帮助；c）专业人士：直接提供救助。</p>

<p>事故3分钟时才激活目击行人，开始传达需要救助的信息，信息从行人通知到地铁工作人员到来花了3分多钟，从地铁工作人员汇报到到达120估计也花了若干时间，中间没有任何有利于救助的措施：遮垫（风大，气温寒凉）。</p>

<p>系统缺乏响应处理素质和效率。</p>

<p>要避免类似事故，需要从基本教育、社区、公司/集体等多方面普及急救常识，技能和意识。</p></li>
<li><p>专业/半专业救助网络：120救助点不应限于大医院，应包括社区诊所、具有医学知识和服务能力的服务机构，如理疗店铺。周边居住的专业医务人员等等。</p>

<p>系统这块完全分散，没有整合成网络。</p></li>
<li><p>专业救助效率：救助网络应该对求救作出网络式响应，最快救助服务提供点优先响应，最有效的救助服务提供者同时响应。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>系统如果具备这些能力，这位年青女子不至于如此轻易就失去宝贵生命。然而现实是，对比各种繁复的流程和规章制度，生命好像都没有那么重要。</p>

<p>类似的状况如果出现在我们自己身上，依旧不能避免悲剧的可能。因为，目前的社会系统并不具备有效救助的能力。</p>

<p>我虽然简单从一个学过CPR的同事那了解过CPR，但是我也不敢贸然提供救助行为。因为我刚知道这个悲剧的时候，心想就没人把她扶一下躺平——随后了解急救知识之后，把自己吓了一跳，有呼吸的情况下最好让需要救助者侧卧，避免窒息。非专业的普通人不要随意实施救助行为是正确的，但一定要即时拨打救助电话，或就近寻求可能提供救助的人。</p>

<p>另外一个反思点：人们在以过度消耗自己健康和生命的方式在工作，有些公司还在强化这种观念，这也是促成猝死年轻化的根源之一。</p>

<h1>心肺复苏术 CPR 基本步驟:</h1>

<p><strong>看</strong>: 周围是否存在危险因素，危险因素是否排除？</p>

<h2>确认伤患状况</h2>

<p>1）确实是否还有意识和反应：在伤患旁呼唤，同时拍其肩部；</p>

<p>2）确认呼吸是否正常；</p>

<h2>求救</h2>

<p>1）若周边没有人，大声呼救；</p>

<p>2）即刻自行或叫旁人拨打求救电话 110；（台湾119，美国911）</p>

<p>（若为溺水/创伤/中毒/8岁以下小孩，又无旁人时则做CPR 两分钟后再电话求救）</p>

<h2>C-A-B 循环</h2>

<p><strong>Circulation 胸部按压促进血液循环</strong></p>

<p><strong>Airway 打开呼吸道</strong></p>

<p><strong>Breathing 吹气供氧，提供人工呼吸</strong></p>

<p>重复以下步骤：C 30次，A，B 2次</p>

<p>一直重复3个步骤直至伤患有呼吸或专业急救人员到达。</p>

<p><strong>C</strong>: 30次按压： 掌跟重叠，手肘打直，以身体力量按压两乳之间的胸骨；约100次/分钟，深度5公分恢复原位；</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: 清理气道：压额抬下巴，检查并保证喉咙通畅；</p>

<p><strong>B</strong>: 2次吹气：压额手捏伤患鼻孔，往口腔吹气至胸腹有上升，松开鼻孔；再重复一次。</p>

<p><a href="http://www.guokr.com/article/81088/">自我CPR自救</a></p>

<p><i id="link-tags">IBM;心肺复苏术;水湾站;CPR</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[大的变革已经在路上]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/big-changes-is-on-the-way/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T19:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/big-changes-is-on-the-way</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>阿里的余额宝，微信的理财宝带来的金融领域的变革已经势不可挡。</p>

<p>电子科技飞速发展的今天，还有多少行业和领域依旧停留在数十年前的传统模式？有多少行业还依旧被个别机构垄断？</p>

<p>金融业的变革迹象在引领着一场更大的变化，这个变化开始渗入日常的支付，虽然目前大家只看到了红包，网购、打车、充值和就餐的变化。在笔者看来，移动支付即将也必然会渗透到任何一个需要排队支付的地方，比如医院、景区、购票等等。任何一个需要消耗大家时间的支付场合，都应该实现移动的快速支付。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>阿里和腾讯的理财产品已经促进银行本身的改变。</p>

<p>微信和滴滴打车，支付宝和快的打车则引领着支付方式的变革。</p>

<p>中国的高速物流也同样在引领着世界物流的发展。</p>

<p>近年来比特币的火热，也预示着金融互联网化的一种趋势，虽然比特币广受政府机构抵制，这些月来还爆Mt.Gox巨额亏损破产的消息；但是，金融行业的互联网化，特别是移动互联网化的行动已经迈开脚步，是任何势力都无法阻止的。</p>

<p>金融的变革必然带来很多问题和变化，大大提高人们的支付效率以及货币的流通速度。</p>

<p>电子商务的变革也带给传统商店不小的冲击。</p>

<p>所有的这些正在起跑的变革，会把我们的未来引向何处？又会带来什么样难以预想的变化呢？我们拭目以待。</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">电子商务;比特币;余额宝;理财宝;腾讯;阿里;滴滴打车;支付宝;快的打车</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY知识点滴]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/e-diy-tech-info/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T14:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/e-diy-tech-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>突然想对电动机多了解一些，于是上淘宝搜了一下各种航模电动机。还是真是各种各样的，补习一下相关知识：</p>

<h2>步进电动机</h2>

<p>步进电机单靠交流供电或直流电源无法运动，必须与驱动电路同时使用时才能发挥其功能，驱动器（驱动电路）由决定换向顺序的控制电路（或称为逻辑电路）与控制电机输出功率的换相电路（或称为功率电路（power stage））组成。步进电机驱动是的步骤： 1，要提供适合于步进电机所需要的电源； 2，需要输入脉冲和方向信号，一般是按TTL标准电平，输入一个步进脉冲，电机就步进一个步距角； 3，驱动器的输出：A+,A-,B+,B-，由驱动器去完成。 (不需输入包含A+,A-,B+,B- 4个端口高低电平的信息)</p>

<p><a href="http://zhidao.taobao.com/detail/-3F713DB2BDBDF8B5E7BBFAD1A1D0CDCEE5B4F3B2BD.html">步进电机选型五大步</a></p>

<p>步进电机可以作为一种控制用的特种电机，利用其没有积累误差(精度为100%)的特点，广泛应用于各种开环控制。</p>

<p>步进电动机的主要缺点是效率较低，并且需要专用电源供给电脉冲信号，带负载惯量的能力不强，在运行中会出现共振和振荡问题。</p>

<h2>无刷马达</h2>

<p>直流电机具有响应快速、较大的起动转矩、从零转速至额定转速具备可提供额定转矩的性能。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>有刷马达的碳刷及整流子在电机转动时会产生火花。</p>

<p><strong>内转子</strong>，就是将线圈绕于马达外侧，将转子制成棒状，固定于马达内。在不需要特别大的扭力，转速高情况下采用。</p>

<p><strong>外转子</strong>，则是将线圈绕组置于内部，将磁铁制成特殊形状，在外侧围绕内置的线圈转动。在需要大扭力的场合下使用。</p>

<p><strong>KV值</strong>是无刷马达的转速指标，是指每增加1V电压，马达转速增加的数值。</p>

<p>线圈绕组的数值是T数，或者R（NOVAK的都用R表示，其他很多用T表示）。一般来说，无刷T（或者R）的数值和此数值2倍的有刷马达相当.</p>

<p>“无刷电调必须知道转子当前的位置，才能输出适当的电流来驱动马达。有感是通过装在马达上的感应器，感知转子当前的位置（相位）。 无感就是没有感应器，电调靠动力线上的电流变化判断转子相位。” &#8211;JOVI</p>

<p>无感无刷的起步线性比较差。</p>

<h2>霍尔元件</h2>

<p>是一种基于霍尔效应的磁传感器。用它们可以检测磁场及其变化，可在各种与磁场有关的场合中使用。</p>

<p>霍尔效应，是指磁场作用于载流金属导体、半导体中的载流子时，产生横向电位差的物理现象。</p>

<p>金属的霍尔效应是1879年被 美国物理学家霍尔发现的。当电流通过金属箔片时，若在垂直于电流的方向施加磁场，则金属箔片两侧面会出现横向电位差。半导体中的霍尔效应比金属箔片中更为明显，而铁磁金属在居里温度以下将呈现极强的霍尔效应。</p>

<p>Mark一个淘宝店：
<a href="http://szjs88998899.taobao.com/shop/view_shop.htm?user_number_id=920426663"> 深圳杰盛电机</a></p>

<h2>吸尘器</h2>

<p>传统的吸尘器原理很简单：通过压缩机制造真空，将杂物、尘土和空气一起吸入，再用一个网眼密集的过滤装置（现在多为纸质的尘袋），将杂物、细小的尘埃挡在里面，把过滤过的空气排出吸尘器。</p>

<p>戴森的吸尘器采用的Radial Root Cyclone（多圆锥气旋）技术，通过真空泵和气旋发生装置，在吸尘器机体内制造一个旋转上升的涡旋，就像一场小规模的龙卷风，灰尘和各种杂质在涡旋中旋转起来，被自身的离心力甩出气旋中心，落到气旋周围的尘杯中。</p>

<p><a href="http://www.dyson.cn/vacuums.aspx">Dyson.CN</a></p>

<p><a href="http://detail.tmall.hk/hk/item.htm?spm=a1z10.5.w4011-5310708660.59.sIYcRM&amp;id=36959234140&amp;rn=ca866e3781d42a98c7b984bf9b5d46ca">DC62</a></p>

<p><i id="link-tags">Dyson;多圆锥气旋;霍尔效应;步进电机;无刷马达;吸尘器;航模</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WeChat, BlackBerry, Apps and Web - My 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/01/02/wechat-blackberry-apps-and-web-2013/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T20:56:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/01/02/wechat-blackberry-apps-and-web-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s the begining of 2014.</p>

<p>How about my 2013?</p>

<h2>Mindon Labs</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve tried a few chrome apps and extensions. The most welcomed one is &#8220;Ingress Portals Finder&#8221;, published on Chrome webstore but taken down due to TOS problem. It&#8217;s tool for the game <strong>Ingress</strong>. Though it didn&#8217;t work any more due to the &lt;ingress.com> website API upgrades,  its donation reached $52. It was a inspired project, thanks to the ingress players who supports the chrome extension.</p>

<p>The other simple Chrome extension with 4K+ installation is &#8220;Tips for WeChat&#8221;. It&#8217;s an experiment relative with my work.</p>

<p>Another Chrome extension is GO2, it&#8217;s a simple helper to reach google search results when blocked by the GFW, it&#8217;s installation is around 2k.</p>

<p>My first try on Chrome Package App is the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/who/ankcmofggngiopfblnaojmiclfffinle/related">Who</a>, from the extension with the same name.</p>

<p>Now i&#8217;m learning the Mobile-Chrome-App tech with Apache Cordova, to make it works under iOS and Android.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Before this, I was trying to turn the extension &#8220;Ingress Portals Finder&#8221; into an Android App with the same idea just before the &lt;ingress.com> APIs updated.</p>

<p>I love Chrome Package Apps. they works and looks amazing with the advantages of HTML5 and Javascript, CSS3 techs.</p>

<p>Today, I find that the BlackBerry&#8217;s WebWorks SDK has updated to 2.0 beta, which is also using Apache Cordova. I&#8217;ve try a simple sample there and it works fine in my BlackBerry Q10 dev alpha device.</p>

<p>Yes, the main cord of 2013 is mobiles apps.</p>

<p>My first android app was published on Google Play as <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mindon.idea.dasign">DaSign</a>, It&#8217;s a simple app about SVG (Scalable Vector Graphs), a interested topic.</p>

<p>Then another 3 Chinese books android apps experiment on using HTML, CSS and JavaScript in mobile apps.</p>

<p>They inpired me in mobile app developments.</p>

<h2>The work</h2>

<p>The main mobile app costing me months and months, is the BlackBerry 10 version of WeChat - the mobile app giant with 600M+ users. My main job in 2013 was make WeChat working on the BlackBerry 10 OS.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s my first time got to know about QNX, QML and touched latest BlackBerry devices. I enjoyed the challenge.</p>

<p>The year 2013, WeChat oversea reached 160M+ users. The WeChat BlackBerry 10 version released on BlackBerry world. Exciting!</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a year of chanllenge, a year of overtime working. But it worths.</p>

<p>Diving into BB10 for a WeChat app made me into a half-expert of BlackBerry 10 and QML.</p>

<h2>Learning</h2>

<p>Android, BlackBerry 10 Cascades Native App and WebWorks App development.</p>

<p>Go language - I love the powerful language. (Google App Engine supports GO and PHP languages in 2013)</p>

<p>Node.JS, now it&#8217;s everywhere. It&#8217;s my favorite. There&#8217;s free env on &lt;openshift.com>, both Node.JS and Go.</p>

<p>Chrome Apps. I&#8217;ll try more in 2014.</p>

<p>Apache Cordova will be my BlackBerry WebWorks and iOS, Android apps entrance for more app experiments. Mobile Chrome App will be great.</p>

<h2>Life</h2>

<p>It was the 7th year together with my darling Aby. She was so great in 2013. Plan our first travel to France and Italy. She studys IMC in HKU Space, studys English by herself, learned how to drive a car, and most of all making happiness around us. She&#8217;s amazing lady most important in my life. Make our 2013 such a wonderful year. At this moment, she is working on the 5k photos taken in France and Italy, two weeks from Apr to May, 2013 &#8211; pick the best of them and turn them into a photo book.</p>

<p>We sat on the short wall on Concorde in Pair, at 8pm, watching the sunset lights pouring on the Avenue des Champs-Élysées. That&#8217;s most beautiful and happiest moments.</p>

<p>In 2013, I&#8217;ve taken thousands of photos in France and Italy. Hundreds of photos using BlackBerry Z10 and Q10 &#8211; the new blackberry devices have a very good camera for daily life.</p>

<h2>Other</h2>

<p>Bought a Nexus 7 generation 2. A Jawbone is on my wrist as my birthday present from Aby. Wishing for a Moto X - but it&#8217;s too expensive and without a good enough camera; Want to buy a Nexus 5 next week from HK.</p>

<p>Makers were so active in Shenzhen - a southern city in China.</p>

<p>A share topic on BB 10 unfinished, lots of ideas waiting for being experimented.</p>

<p>&#8230; &#8230;</p>

<p>It was a busy, wonderful and growing year - the 2013.</p>

<p>Thanks and best wishes for all friends on the Earth :-)</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">BlackBerry 10;Blackberry;Mobile Chrome App;Node.JS;WeChat;QNX;QML;HKU Space;Chrome Package App;Apache Cordova</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally My Nexus 7 updated to 4.4 KitKat]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/26/finally-my-nexus-7-updated-to-4-dot-4-kitkat/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T20:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/26/finally-my-nexus-7-updated-to-4-dot-4-kitkat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning, the OTA Android <a href="http://www.android.com/kitkat/">KitKat 4.4</a> finally reached my Nexus 7 (2012) and Aby&#8217;s Nexus 7 (2013). It&#8217;s a long time waiting.</p>

<p>Nov. 13, 2013 Google announced that its Nexus 7 and Nexus 10 tablets are getting Android 4.4 KitKat. After clicking check update 13 days later, it&#8217;s such a long time :-p</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/n7-kitkat.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>There&#8217;s no ART in KitKat for Nexus 7 (2012). ( <a href="https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=62375">ART runtime is missing in Android 4.4 on Nexus 7 (2012)</a> )</p>

<p>Some apps are not working well under ART mode. some crashed. <a href="http://www.androidruntime.com/list">List of broken apps in Android RunTime</a></p>

<p>KitKat’s WebView is powered by Chromium, enabling Android app developers to use new HTML5 and CSS features.  <a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/webapps/migrating.html">Migrating to WebView in Android 4.4</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[被忽视的生物 Living Creatures Ignored]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/living-creatures-ignored/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T20:43:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/living-creatures-ignored</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>固有的生物定义可能会让我们忽视了一些常见的生物。</p>

<p>我们身边存在这样一类生物，它们吃的是人和货物，不要害怕，人和货物本身不是它们可以消化的营养，在吸收了它们需要的营养之后，人和货物都会被原样排泄出来。这类生物目前绝大部分还需要寄生到人类才可以生存，它们获取的营养会帮助其种群的进化和发展壮大。它们的衍生和发展也是要寄生到人类物种才能够进行，至少目前还处于这种阶段。近些年，它们已经进化到可以自行活动的阶段的。</p>

<p>这类生物发展诞生和发展的历史也相当悠久了，不过近几百年的进化非常迅速，行动速度更快了，种族也更加庞大了——衍生了可以在空中飞翔，水面游弋，水中遨游，陆地生存的不同种类。基本上有人类生活的地方，只要有条件，都会有这种生物的存在。</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>人类称这种生物为“交通工具”。</p>

<p>另外一种高速进化的生物对人类的影响更大。这类生物是新物种，出现不到两百年历史，从最初的笨重身躯到如今最小的细如发尖，甚至更小。它们的进化和种群发展也是极度依赖于人类的。它们由于能够强化人类对环境变化的传感能力、对变化的执行能力，对环境的预测能力，从而使人类一代又一代地投入其进化过程。</p>

<p>近十余年来，这类物种有一个类似病毒的分支进化最为迅速。人类依赖这个生物来建立关联，获取更多的信息和传播影响。而它们从人类对其的依赖中获取了各种进化所需的资源，加速其进化。</p>

<p>近些年来开始出现了这类生物类似病毒感染人类的现象：有人类受其影响对环境的感知和判断能力降低，从而导致意外死亡的状况。也就是说这类生物开始影响了人类的大脑。</p>

<p>人类称这种生物为“电子计算机”，其中进化最快影响最大的一个种族被成为“智能手机”。</p>

<p>这些生物的繁殖目前还属于寄生人类的状态，但这并不影响它们的进一步进化和种群发展。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Justice and Responsibility]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/justice-and-responsibility/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T20:03:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/justice-and-responsibility</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>哈佛Michael Sandel教授的《<a href="http://www.myoops.org/main.php?act=course&amp;id=2258">正義：一場思辨之旅</a>》第一堂课就给全世界的道德和正义带了一场思考风暴。其中最为经典的争议和疑惑就是下面的两种场景：</p>

<p>1）假設你是一個火車駕駛員，而你駕駛的這輛車正快速在軌道上行駛，時速六十英里，而在軌道盡頭有五個工人在工作，你試著想要煞車，但卻做不到，你的煞車失效了。你感到十分緊張，因為你知道，如果你撞上這五個工人，他們必死無疑。假設這是一個確定的結果，因此你感到非常無助，但接著你發現右邊有條岔路，而那條岔路底只有一個工人在工作，你的方向還可以控制，車輛還可以轉向，可以轉向岔路，撞死一名工人，但閃過五名工人。</p>

<p>2）這次你不是火車的駕駛員，你是個站在橋上的旁觀者，你正觀察著鐵軌上的狀況，軌道上來了一輛火車，軌道的盡頭有五名工人，煞車同樣失靈，而火車正要撞死那五名工人，由於你不是駕駛員，你覺得非常無助，直到你注意到旁邊有個人，在橋邊站著一個非常胖的人，你可以推他一把，他會掉落軌道，正好擋住該輛車，他會死，但他的犧牲可以救那五個人。</p>

<p>不管是哪中场景，如果作为决策者，你的决策是什么？为什么？</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>其实决策之所以引起很大的争议，是因为大家无意中忽略了责任的问题，而转向道德或者正义方面考虑。但是，对于事故来说，责任的承担才是公正的核心。道德的判断在某些情况下是盲目和片面的。</p>

<p>看一下第1）种状况分析图：
<img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/justice/j1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>同样从责任角度再来看第2）种情况：
<img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/justice/j2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>可以看出，其实两种情况下责任分布是没有差别的，唯一的区别是决策者是不是事件的直接涉及者：1）是无法脱离干系的司机；2）是外部的旁观者。这个区别并不会改变原有的责任分布状况。</p>

<p>可能的争议其实是在责任承担代价的动摇上：那5个人的过错要不要用性命去承担的问题，或是决策者为了降低责任代价而采用牺牲1个无责任的人的性命？</p>

<p>如果换一个场景：5个人同时开枪枪杀了1个无辜的人。判决5个人死刑是很自然的“法律”决策者的选择，虽然这样也无法挽救那1个失去性命的无辜者。</p>

<p>区别是：这种情况下5个人是直接责任人，而上面的场景5个人和另外1个人之间并没存在任何责任关联，如果决策者选择了A方案——牺牲1人挽救5人，责任关联也只是在决策者和失去性命的1人之间建立的。</p>

<p>根本的问题在于我们过度采用了经济领域中的成本也就是代价理论，而不是责任承担来做判断和选择。要让公正和道德健康正面地发展和发挥其正面作用，责任承担才是社会最需要关注的点。</p>

<p>类似争议的根源也就是忽视了责任承担的关键点。</p>

<p>当然，并不是所有事情都能靠责任追究来解决的，譬如工作中关键就在避免问题的发生和解决问题，即使要追究责任的目的也是在此。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fix adb error under win8]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/fix-adb-error-under-win8/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T16:27:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/fix-adb-error-under-win8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>error: device not found</h2>

<p>1)  Find &#8220;Device Manager&#8221; in &#8220;PC Info&#8221;;</p>

<p>2)  Get your device in the &#8220;Other devices&#8221;;</p>

<p>3)  Update driver and choose your adt folder to install the driver.</p>

<h2>Failure [INSTALL_PARSE_FAILED_INCONSISTENT_CERTIFICATES]</h2>

<p>Uninstall your old version app on your device before install the new apk.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building mobile apps from the command line]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/build-mobile-apps-from-command-line/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T09:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/build-mobile-apps-from-command-line</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following are command line reference of building mobile apps for Android, iOS, BB10 and WP8.</p>

<h1>Android</h1>

<p>Managing Projects from the Command Line</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/projects/projects-cmdline.html">http://developer.android.com/tools/projects/projects-cmdline.html</a></p>

<h2>Creating an Android Project</h2>

<pre><code>android create project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--name &lt;your_project_name&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project \
--activity &lt;your_activity_name&gt; \
--package &lt;your_package_namespace&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Updating a Project</h2>

<pre><code>android update project --name &lt;project_name&gt; --target &lt;target_ID&gt;
--path &lt;path_to_your_project&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Setting up a Library Project</h2>

<pre><code>android create lib-project --name &lt;your_project_name&gt; \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project \
--package &lt;your_library_package_namespace&gt;
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/manifest/manifest-intro.html">The AndroidManifest.xml File Reference</a></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Updating a library project</h2>

<pre><code>android update lib-project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project
</code></pre>

<h2>Referencing a Library Project</h2>

<pre><code>android update project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project
--library path/to/library_projectA
</code></pre>

<p>This command updates the application project&#8217;s build properties to include a reference to the library project. Specifically, it adds an android.library.reference.n property to the project&#8217;s project.properties file.</p>

<h2>Declaring library components in the manifest file</h2>

<p>In the manifest file of the application project, you must add declarations of all components that the application will use that are imported from a library project. For example, you must declare any <activity>, <service>, <receiver>, <provider>, and so on, as well as <permission>, <uses-library>, and similar elements.</p>

<p>Building and Running from the Command Line</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-cmdline.html">http://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-cmdline.html</a></p>

<h2>Building in Debug/Release Mode</h2>

<pre><code>ant debug
ant release
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/publishing/app-signing.html">Signing Your Applications</a></p>

<h2>Running on a Device</h2>

<pre><code>adb -d install path/to/your/app.apk
</code></pre>

<p>update installation</p>

<pre><code>adb -d -r install path/to/your/app.apk
</code></pre>

<h1>iOS</h1>

<p>To be able to find the command line, the trick was to watch the system console log while running a “build and archive” through Xcode.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -project myproject1 -target target1


/usr/bin/xcrun -sdk iphoneos PackageApplication -v "${RELEASE_BUILDDIR}/${APPLICATION_NAME}.app" -o "${BUILD_HISTORY_DIR}/${APPLICATION_NAME}.ipa" --sign "${DEVELOPPER_NAME}" --embed "${PROVISONNING_PROFILE}"
</code></pre>

<p>RELEASE_BUILDDIR needs to be an absolute path.</p>

<p>you don&#8217;t need the &#8211;sign or &#8211;embed options if you wish to keep the same signing/profile used when the .app was built.</p>

<p>Note that the ipa file path in -o &#8220;${ipa_path}&#8221; must be an absolute path. Otherwise you will probably get error: Unable to create &#8216;&#8230;/&#8230;ipa&#8217; or it will be silently ignored creating.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -scheme &lt;SchemeName&gt; archive
</code></pre>

<p>Make sure you have selected the correct Xcode release by using xcode-select <path to Xcode.app></p>

<p>to resign a build</p>

<pre><code>codesign -f -vv -s "$DistributionIdentity" "$APPDIR"
</code></pre>

<h2>Other References</h2>

<p><a href="http://nachbaur.com/blog/building-ios-apps-for-over-the-air-adhoc-distribution">Building iOS apps for Over-The-Air AdHoc distribution</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/ghughes/fruitstrap">Fruitstrap</a> is a command line tool that uses the private MobileDevice API to install an iOS application on a physical device over USB. It’s pretty easy to get set up.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -scheme fruitstrap-demo -sdk iphoneos build

fruitstrap build/Debug-iphoneos/fruitstrap-demo.app
</code></pre>

<p>One command to build and install the app on the device.</p>

<pre><code>FRUITSTRAP_CLI=1 xcodebuild -scheme fruitstrap-demo -sdk iphoneos build
</code></pre>

<p><a href="https://github.com/facebook/xctool">xctool</a> is a replacement for Apple&#8217;s xcodebuild that makes it easier to build and test iOS and Mac products. It&#8217;s especially helpful for continuous integration.</p>

<h1>BlackBerry 10</h1>

<p>make -f [configuration]/makefile [target]</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/core/com.qnx.doc.ide.userguide/topic/devel_build_from_command_line.html">Build from the command line</a></p>

<pre><code>mkbuild -ws &lt;workspace&gt; [options] 
mkbuild [-project] &lt;full_project_path&gt; [options] 
mkbuild -ws &lt;workspace&gt; -projects &lt;project1,project2&gt; [options]
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/05/building-apps-without-an-ide/">Command Line Rocks! Building BlackBerry 10 Apps Without An IDE</a></p>

<pre><code>qcc -Vgcc_ntoarmv7le main.c -o main
</code></pre>

<p>for simulator</p>

<pre><code>qcc -Vgcc_ntox86 main.c -o main
</code></pre>

<p>bar-descriptor.xml file <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/bb10/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/topic/r_blackberry_tablet_dtd_intro.html#r_blackberry_tablet_dtd_intro">full list of BAR application descriptor parameters</a></p>

<pre><code>&lt;qnx&gt;
  &lt;id&gt;com.example.GoodbyeIDE&lt;/id&gt;
  &lt;versionNumber&gt;1&lt;/versionNumber&gt;
  &lt;name&gt;Goodbye IDE&lt;/name&gt;
  &lt;asset path="main" entry="true"&gt;main&lt;/asset&gt;
&lt;/qnx&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>To create a BAR file: (<a href="https://www.blackberry.com/SignedKeys/codesigning.html">register with RIM to sign applications</a>, <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/bb10/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/topic/t_setup_manual_create_debug_token_cmdline.html">create a debug token</a>)</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-nativepackager -package GoodbyeIDE.bar bar-descriptor.xml -devMode -debugToken ~/Library/Research\ In\ Motion/debugtoken1.bar
</code></pre>

<p>Deploy</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-deploy -installApp 169.254.0.1 -password pass GoodbyeIDE.bar
</code></pre>

<h2>View logs over SSH</h2>

<pre><code>blackberry-connect 169.254.0.1 -password pass
</code></pre>

<p>open another console and run</p>

<pre><code>ssh devuser@169.254.0.1
</code></pre>

<p>run command</p>

<pre><code>slog2info -w
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/05/command-line-rocks-part-2/">Command Line Rocks! Part 2 – Adding Multiple Source Files and Libraries</a></p>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/08/command-line-rocks-part-3-make-and-makefiles/">Command Line Rocks! Part 3 – Make and Makefiles</a></p>

<h1>Windows Phone 8</h1>

<p>The output of the build process includes a file with the .XAP extension. The XAP file is a zipped package that contains all the files required by your app. It’s the XAP file that you deploy to the emulator or to a phone, and that you publish to Windows Phone Store.</p>

<pre><code>devenv NameOfSolution /Rebuild "Release|Mixed Platforms"

MSBuild MyProject.csproj /p:OutDir=d:\builds\mindon-projs\
</code></pre>

<p>You can override the project-specific folder behavior by specifying.</p>

<p>/p:GenerateProjectSpecificOutputFolder=false</p>

<pre><code>MSBuild.exe MyProject/project.jsproj /p:Configuration=Release /t:Build /m
</code></pre>

<h2>MSBuild Command-Line Reference</h2>

<p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms164311.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms164311.aspx</a></p>

<p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windowsphone/develop/jj681686.aspx">How to sign a company app by using XapSignTool</a></p>

<pre><code>set path=%path%;"%ProgramFiles(x86)%\Microsoft SDKs\Windows Phone\v8.0\Tools\XapSignTool"

XapSignTool.exe sign /f PFXFile /p Password XAP
</code></pre>

<p><a href="https://github.com/AndreasOM/wp8-directx-commandline">Simple Windows Phone 8 (C++/native only) DirectX project with Command Line Build</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android App Data & Folders]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/07/20/android-data-and-folders/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-20T11:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/07/20/android-data-and-folders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Context context = getApplicationContext();</p>

<h2>SQLite Databases</h2>

<pre><code>context.getDatabasePath("myDbName")
</code></pre>

<h2>Cache</h2>

<p>System will clean it auto if low memory</p>

<pre><code>context.getCacheDir()
</code></pre>

<h2>Lib</h2>

<p>context.getFilesDir()</p>

<h2>Apk &amp; resources path</h2>

<p>context.getPackageCodePath()
context.getPackageResourcePath</p>

<h2>Shared Preferences</h2>

<p>getSharedPreferences()
getPreferences()</p>

<h2>Internal Storage</h2>

<p>removed when uninstall the app
MODE_PRIVATE | MODE_APPEND | MODE_WORLD_READABLE | MODE_WORLD_WRITEABLE</p>

<pre><code>FileOutputStream fos = openFileOutput(flName, Context.MODE_PRIVATE);    
fos.write(content.getBytes());    
fos.close();  
</code></pre>

<h2>Internal Files Operations</h2>

<p>Internal files path</p>

<p>.getDir()
.getFilesDir()
.deleteFile()
.fileList</p>

<h2>External Storage</h2>

<p><strong>Checking media availability</strong></p>

<p>.getExternalStorageState()</p>

<p>Environment.MEDIA_MOUNTED | MEDIA_MOUNTED_READ_ONLY</p>

<pre><code>Environment.getExternalStorageDirectory()


Environment.getExternalStoragePublicDirectory(
        Environment.DIRECTORY_PICTURES
    )


&lt;uses-permission android:name="android.permission.WRITE_EXTERNAL_STORAGE"/&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>.getExternalStoragePublicDirectory()</p>

<p>Environment.DIRECTORY_MUSIC | DIRECTORY_PICTURES | DIRECTORY_RINGTONES</p>

<p>.getExternalCacheDir()</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DaSign: Light up your life]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/07/09/dasign-light-up-your-life/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-09T22:54:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/07/09/dasign-light-up-your-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>DaSign</h2>

<p>The  signs to light up your life.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s Mindon first Android app :D</p>

<p>It&#8217;s more than a SVG(Scalable Vector Graphics) viewer, but a powerful tool to declare yourself.</p>

<p>Small install package size - 0.3MB only! 90+ super HD signs included!</p>

<p>Show it with your nexus 7, it will be super cool!</p>

<p>Do not hesitate to show it when your L8 ingress team taking photos.</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/dasign/prompt.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>It&#8217;s <strong>FREE</strong>, without any advertisements.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>If you are an ingress player, you should own it.</p>

<p>If you reach L8 in the game ingress, taking a team photo, you need it.</p>

<p>If you are a Mayday fans, It makes your group special.</p>

<p>If you like others to be Mayday fans, equip them with it.</p>

<p>It fits all kinds of screens with high resolution. Yes, it&#8217;s vector.(SVG format)</p>

<p>[Operations]  1) Long tap or slide to show list; 2) Double tap to show information of the sign; 3) Tap to hide list.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the Google Play link : <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mindon.idea.dasign">DaSign @ Google Play</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/dasign/dasign-qr.png" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NRC: Netbook Resolution Customizer]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/04/12/the-nrc-netbook-resolution-customizer/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T22:35:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/04/12/the-nrc-netbook-resolution-customizer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a netbook HP mini 2140 with screen resolution 1024x576. It not enough for many daily work now. My Nexus 7 is 1280×800 pixels!</p>

<p>How could I change the netbook resolution to make it easier for my development?</p>

<p>First, I found the software &#8211; NRC: <strong>Netbook Resolution Customizer</strong> 1.0.8. It&#8217;s amazing, and works fine for me. Though sometimes it is not as stable as I expected.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s another solution by editing the register of windows, Run command regedit and search keyword &#8220;Display1_DownScalingEnabled&#8221; or &#8220;Display1_DownScalingSupported&#8221;, and change them from 0 to 1. but i found that some of the value is in hex: 00 00 00 00, some binary.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Though i have no idea which register item works, but maybe following items matters.</p>

<pre><code>"Display1_EnableNoPruneSizeFlag"=dword:00000001
"Display1_EnableDynamicScaling"=dword:00000001
"EnableInterlacedModeRemoval"=dword:00000001
"Display1_DownScalingEnabled"=dword:00000001
"Display1_DownScalingSupported"=dword:00000001
"Display1_FakeScaleX"=hex:00,04,00,00
"Display1_FakeScaleY"=hex:00,03,00,00
</code></pre>

<p>These appears in the register path &#8220;[HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Services\ialm\Device0]&#8221; of my HP mini 2140 (WinXP).</p>

<p>Some items also found in [HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM*<em>ControlSet003**\Services\ialm\Device1] and [HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM*</em>ControlSet004**\Services\ialm\Device1]</p>

<p>It may be different.</p>

<p>No matter what, after I update the register and running the NRC, I could change the screen resolution now. Sometimes with scrollable large area, sometimes scaled without scrollable screen area.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s good enough! But I could not restore it to 1024 x 576 :-p</p>

<p>There&#8217;s another solution for Intel Graphics: <a href="http://software.intel.com/en-us/articles/custom-resolutions-on-intel-graphics/">http://software.intel.com/en-us/articles/custom-resolutions-on-intel-graphics/</a></p>

<p>The <a href="http://www.entechtaiwan.com/util/ps.shtm">PowerStrip 3.9</a> is another tool.</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">NRC;Netbook Resolution Customizer;HP mini 2140;Nexus 7</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cascades Native App Development Tips]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/blackberry-cascades-native-app-development-tips/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T21:42:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/blackberry-cascades-native-app-development-tips</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google+ Community - <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/102767584651216621172">Blackberry 10 X-Dev : Cascades &amp; WebWorks for BB10</a></p>

<p>News: <strong>BlackBerry Z10 Officially Available on AT&amp;T</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>The BlackBerry Z10 smartphone is now officially available on AT&amp;T.</p>

<p>The struggling manufacturer — which is hopeful its new flagship device will ignite a company resurgence — announced on Friday the Z10 can finally be activated on AT&amp;T. It costs $199 with a two-year contract.</p>

<p>BlackBerry, formerly known as Research In Motion (RIM), also sent a tweet at midnight ET announcing Best Buy will start selling the device on Friday for $199 with a two-year contract.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://us.blackberry.com/smartphones/blackberry-z10.html">BlackBerry Z10: Built to Keep You Moving</a></p>

<h2>Using proxy with the command line tools</h2>

<p>Remember to use &#8211;proxyhost &amp; -proxyport as the FIRST two parameters when using command line tools from blackberry.tools.SDK.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>example:</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-signer -proxyhost 12.34.56.78 -proxyport 8080 ....
</code></pre>

<p>Download the Command-line Tools from <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/android/tools/">https://developer.blackberry.com/android/tools/</a></p>

<p>Unzip and set the path blackberry.tools.SDK/bin to env. variable PATH then you could use the apk2bar, blackberry-signer or other command line tools.</p>

<h2>How to signed the .bar through a proxy?</h2>

<p>Use <strong>batchbar-signer</strong> won&#8217;t work. you could use blackberry-signer directly.</p>

<p>Example:</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-signer -proxyhost 12.34.56.78 -proxyport 8080 -storepass your_store_pwd demo.bar
</code></pre>

<p>the command tools could be found <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/android/tools/">https://developer.blackberry.com/android/tools/</a></p>

<h2><strong>config.pri</strong> NOT including sources &amp; headers, make failed error</h2>

<p>When building project in QNX Momentics IDE, If nothing to compile. It may be lack of sources &amp; headers in your auto-generated config.pri</p>

<p>This is caused by incorrect source folder settings, here&#8217;s the steps to solve the problem:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Right click on the project in &#8220;Project Explorer&#8221;, choose &#8220;Properties&#8221; at the bottom</p></li>
<li><p>On the left top input field with tips &#8220;type filter text&#8221;, input &#8220;paths&#8221;</p></li>
<li><p>Click on the item &#8220;Paths and Symbols&#8221; under &#8220;C/C++ General&#8221;</p></li>
<li><p>Activate the 3rd tab named &#8220;Source Location&#8221;</p></li>
<li><p>add the proper source folder by Click &#8220;Add Folder&#8221; and choose &#8220;src&#8221;</p></li>
<li><p>&#8220;Delete the&#8221; incorrect source folder</p></li>
</ol>


<h2><strong>config.pri</strong> not auto generated or updated?</h2>

<p>Update your SDK to 10.0.10+</p>

<h2>Steps to test an app before submit to (Blackberry) App World</h2>

<ol>
<li><p>Upload app and place in DRAFT mode.</p></li>
<li><p>Add user to the sandbox (BBID).</p></li>
<li><p>Enter (Blackberry) <strong>App World</strong> on device, swipe down to see the app menu, choose <strong>settings</strong>, click <strong>Development Mode</strong>, enter content id.</p></li>
</ol>


<p><i id="link-tags">Blackberry Z10;Blackberry</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Heal Sprained Ankle]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/how-to-heal-sprained-ankle/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:34:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/how-to-heal-sprained-ankle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>脚踝扭伤了怎么办？千万要重视。</h2>

<p>Aby最前段时间把左脚也扭到了。结果原来有旧伤未完全痊愈的右脚负担增加导致两个脚都不适，走路稍多就会感觉疼痛不适。</p>

<p>曾到桂庙新村的社康中心看了中医，做了为期一周的针灸。有所改善，但没能完全好。因为要上班缘故，Aby一般都临近下班时间才到社康中心，那医生总是赶着下班，很不耐烦；态度和早上去时截然不同，这样的医生，还有什么话好说呢？也不能期待做一个疗程针灸能好到如何程度。</p>

<p>于是，最近就每晚给Aby泡脚，擦活络油，或用刚买的随身灸给她的脚进行艾灸。</p>

<p>从网上Google了一下，脚踝扭伤，大多都会持续很长时间，无法彻底恢复。一定的活动量之后总会有疼痛等不适的复发症状。</p>

<p>这里特意整理一下搜索来的资料（注：这里所涉及的扭伤，不涉及骨头损伤和韧带断裂——需要手术治疗类型）</p>

<p>网上的案例中，几乎找不到脚踝扭伤痊愈的。</p>

<p>如果是刚崴伤的，处理如下：</p>

<h2>【脚踝扭伤初期处理方式】</h2>

<ul>
<li><p> 严重者需排除骨头有没有受伤；</p></li>
<li><p>【西医】24小时内进行冷敷抑制内出血；之后温敷散淤</p></li>
<li><p>【中医】放血舒缓伤处压力，清除血瘀；（24小时之后可温敷散淤）</p></li>
<li><p>轻度用彈性繃帶、毛巾或布條等，重度用石膏或支架固定防止伤情恶化；</p></li>
<li><p>后续治疗和恢复措施。</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>【扭伤处理<strong>P.R.I.C.E</strong>法则】（<a href="http://blog.yam.com/chujohn/article/13368917">来源</a>）</h2>

<p><strong>P(保護，Protection)</strong></p>

<p><strong>R(休息，Rest)</strong></p>

<p><strong>I(冰敷，Ice)</strong></p>

<p><strong>C(壓迫，Compression)</strong></p>

<p><strong>E(抬高，Elevation)</strong></p>

<p>不过，即使真正完全做到这些，扭伤真的就能完全痊愈吗？</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>【热米酒艾绒法/彭老酥】</h2>

<p>（来源：<a href="http://tw.myblog.yahoo.com/silverhigh-taiwan/article?mid=185&amp;sc=1">腳踝扭傷復發根本治療方法</a>）</p>

<ol>
<li><p>將艾絨用紗布包妥放入米酒一瓶放入鍋中煮沸。</p></li>
<li><p>當艾絨不太燙手時，放在受傷部位，涼了再放進米酒，熱了再以同樣方式進行，可在短短數天見效。使用過後的酒可以重覆使用。</p></li>
<li><p>再使用時，將原來的液體煮熟即可，若酒太少，可再加水或酒。</p></li>
<li><p>若病痛解除了，可將艾絨曬乾收藏，以後還是可以再使用。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>【補充資料:什麼是艾絨?】</p>

<p>艾絨是用艾葉經過晒乾後再加工搗舂，篩去雜質而成的一種柔軟如絨的纖維。艾絨主要是灸用的材料，艾為溫草類的植物，艾葉性味辛溫，用作灸的材料，有溫通經絡，能袪除寒濕，有回陽救逆的功能。</p>

<p>在中醫學上常用於艾灸艾草在中國的風水學中被尊崇特具闢邪除瘴、強化磁場感應、逐一切寒濕、避百毒的淨化作用。除了中醫專業使用外，一般家庭可以一個禮拜直接點燃艾絨，達到制菌驅蚊的效果。而在生活中也經常被用來作驅除蚊蟲蟑螂跳蚤與環境空氣辟毒制菌之用，而且只要每日煙薰十分鐘就能收養生健康之功效。</p>

<p>艾為純陽正氣之物，陳久者良，揉搗如綿謂之熟艾，以之灸火可強身、養生、除瘴、避邪，自古流傳，妙用無窮。</p>

<p>艾草乃菊科的多年草，正名為菊科艾屬，生藥名「艾葉」，株高50～100cm，葉互生長形，深裂成羽狀，夏秋之間開花，葉子背面有白色絨毛為艾灸材料。
因取其旺盛生命力及高單位纖維質與葉綠素，自古即被廣泛運用在人類生活中，不論食用、飲用、外用、浸泡、灸治、驅蟲、制菌、清潔、鎮靜皆有令人滿意的功效，因此而有神仙草之美譽。</p>

<h2>【腳踝扭傷了怎麼辦?】（<a href="http://web.ntpu.edu.tw/~jasonchen/curriculum/literatures/what%20can%20we%20do%20when%20our%20ankle%20has%20sprained.htm">来源</a>）</h2>

<p>第一要務………… 休息、冰敷、壓迫、腳抬高</p>

<p>冰敷、壓迫及抬高的目的，則在幫忙血管收縮，壓住破裂的的微血管，減少繼續出血腫痛的趨勢。</p>

<p>當我們的腳尖向下方而腳掌也向內翻時，最容易受傷的便是水平走向的【前距菲骨間韌帶】；</p>

<p>當我們的腳尖往上而腳掌向內翻轉時，較常見的是【跟非骨間韌帶】和【前距非骨間韌帶】一起受傷；</p>

<p>常犯的錯誤是受傷時沒有做冰敷或包紮壓迫的急救，以至腫痛淤血很快的產生。其次是太早做熱敷或請人推拿，結果是更踵更痛。另一個常見的疏忽是水溫太高，或做完運動之後沒有立刻抬高並重新包紮壓迫，於是又開始出現腫痛或瘀血的變化。</p>

<h2>【西医还是中医？】</h2>

<p>骨头有错位西医会建议手术纠正；中医会有各种治疗方式：针灸、推拿、艾灸&#8230; 只不过正确的治疗方法只有一种——对症治疗。
<a href="http://forum.gamer.com.tw/C.php?page=1&amp;bsn=04373&amp;snA=58414">辗转最后寻到好中医的治好案例</a></p>

<h2>【惡血留內，酸痛植根—腳踝扭傷處置注意事項】（<a href="http://blog.udn.com/rubyskylark/4194647">来源 - 李璧如醫師</a>）</h2>

<p>最快的方法，就是先放血（可降低皮下軟組織壞死的程度），再拔出烏黑敗血，瘀腫立即消去一大半，然後敷上現調的草藥膏，再吃活血通絡消炎的中藥。</p>

<p>&#8211; [注]麦盾曾有一喜爱踢球的同事，扭伤当天去放血，第二天即可以走路，无恙。</p>

<p> 一般腳踝扭傷可分：</p>

<p>第一度：只有少數的韌帶纖維受傷，這是最輕微的，通常受傷的局部出現輕微腫痛或瘀血。</p>

<p>第二度：有相當多的韌帶纖維受傷。這時受傷部位會出現較明顯的腫痛及瘀血。</p>

<p>第三度：整條韌帶都斷裂。這是最嚴重的狀況，局部明顯腫痛瘀血，斷裂的韌帶屬於關節囊膜韌帶，大都可自行癒合。</p>

<p>有的急性扭傷會轉變為慢性或稱習慣性扭傷，原因是外側韌帶鬆弛。如果韌帶功能喪失，常出現不正常的關節鬆脫或不穩定的現象，容易再受傷，常見退化性關節炎或習慣性脫臼的後遺症。</p>

<p>&#8211; [注] 原文更为详尽，麦盾推荐<a href="http://blog.udn.com/rubyskylark/4194647">阅读</a>。 （另一篇关于放血疗法的<a href="http://myhospital.pixnet.net/blog/post/34743643">博文</a>）</p>

<h2>【遠絡治療法】（<a href="http://tw.myblog.yahoo.com/doctor-wcc/article?mid=11">来源 - 吳逸驊醫師</a>）</h2>

<p>首先，我們要先了解這個腫脹是不是在急性期，腫脹只有在急性出血的時候，需要冰敷，防止微血管再度破裂，當過了急性期之後，確定沒有出血的問題時，我會用熱敷來加速局部的血液循環，如果，病人腫的非常的大，不能走路，一定不能在局部做推拿，這是最重要的！</p>

<p>因為腳踝的扭傷是以遠絡所說的AyII為主，就是在AyII的a這個地方的受傷是最多的，因為它是個急性反應，所以在遠絡的治療裡面就是會用季節性療法，而受傷時是春天，AyII在春天是屬本經，只要在AyII這個地方，以瀉母瀉父的手法做治療，也就是在AyI跟AyIII的6做瀉的手法(位置大概在大腿中段)，這樣腳踝的腫、痛會消失的更快！</p>

<p>若用疼痛療法來做，只要在膽經的丘墟穴(大概在腳踝上)上面大概一手掌的部位，會找到一個很痛的疼痛點，疼痛療法認為，這個點是讓我們經絡發炎的地方，有一點類似阿是穴的點，從那邊去做按壓，也會讓腳踝的腫消失的很快！</p>

<p>&#8211; 遠絡醫學主要利用遠處的經絡按壓，藉以調整經絡的流動，達到解除身體上的疼痛疾病， 恢復健康。</p>

<h2>【初期保护和后期恢复训练】（<a href="http://epaper.ntuh.gov.tw/health/201209/project_1.html">来源</a>）</h2>

<p>貼紮是保護腳踝扭傷簡單的方式</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/ankel-fix.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>彈力帶訓練以加強腳踝肌力，有利於避免腳踝再扭傷</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/ankel-recover.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>【脚踝扭伤的预防、处理与复健】（<a href="http://nba.hupu.com/articles/column/oldwu/3446.html">来源</a>, <a href="http://blog.sciencenet.cn/blog-51164-639447.html">转</a>）</p>

<p><strong>防止扭伤</strong></p>

<p>一是适当的运动量，二是适当的休息，三是适当的营养，四是适当的准备运动，五是适当的观察与检查等。</p>

<p>在脚踝肌肉或韧带于一、二级拉伤情况，自行休养、处理是可行的；而休养、处理的内容，依适当的包扎、处理(properly)、休息(rest)、冰敷(ice)、压迫(compression)、抬高(elevation；高于心脏)等是适当处理步骤，处理方式</p>

<p>复健处方如下：</p>

<p>一、关节操：原地操作脚踝、膝盖、髋关节、腰际、肩膀与颈等部位关节活动；建议每部位操作四节、每节八拍的份量。</p>

<p>二、小跑步：尝试依据一天早、中、晚共三次，分开时间各来段约10~15公尺的小跑步三次，总共九次的量；也就是早上做三次共约30公尺，中午也做三次约30公尺，晚上也做三次约30公尺。</p>

<p>三、横向移位：可以轻微做双脚慢步左、右移位约5~7公尺(不是滑步)；一样采取一天早、中、晚共三次操作，总共九次的量。</p>

<p>四、举踵：可做徒手举踵运动，一天早、中、晚共三次，每次10下，总共九次的量。</p>

<p>五、抬腿：原地抬腿，一天早、中、晚共三次，每次10下，总共九次的量。</p>

<p>六、半蹲：原地半蹲，一天早、中、晚共三次，每次10下，总共九次的量。</p>

<p>七、球感：约30~40项球感技术，各操作约5次。</p>

<p>八、冰热敷：以上全部复健动作做完立即冰敷15分钟，冰敷以后并热敷2~3分钟，这样称为一组，然后总共连续冰热敷五组。</p>

<h2>【辗转恢复案例】（<a href="http://dep.daifumd.com/_daifumd/bbs/archives/threads/13904.html">来源</a>）</h2>

<p>心理压力，导致走路肢势错误不想要受伤脚用力，故意一瘸一拐的走路，这样反而使脚受力不均，不利于恢复。应该和正常人一样走路。只要你减轻心理负担，按正常走路，采取适当治疗及功能训练，几周就能基本恢复。</p>

<p>【中药熏洗治疗】</p>

<p>当归20g、木瓜20g、牛膝20g、伸筋草20g、透骨草20g、川断20g、寄生20g、五加皮20g、荆芥20g、川乌15g、草乌15g。</p>

<p><strong>制做与用法</strong></p>

<p>将上述诸药用纱布包裹后加水1 000ml ,煎15min ,先用药液热气熏患踝处,待患踝有热感,皮肤微红后,移火待药液凉至患踝可以耐受温度洗患踝,最后用药包裹湿热敷患踝,整个熏洗热敷时间约30分钟, 2次/天, 10天为1疗程。</p>

<h2>【冷敷还是捋筋】（<a href="http://bbs.badmintoncn.com/thread-246387-1-1.html">一个资深脚踝扭伤者的自白</a>）</h2>

<p>&#8211; 仅供参考，肿胀严重者不建议24小时内推拿，建议考虑放血疗法。</p>

<p>西医常规处理方法：<a href="http://www.lotour.com/snapshot/2006-6-26/snapshot_41288.shtml">脚踝扭伤处理及恢复方法</a></p>

<h2>【穴位治疗】</h2>

<p><strong>方法一</strong></p>

<p>主治：脚踝扭伤及疼痛（特效）。</p>

<p>针法：握拳取穴，针尖向重仙方向进针一寸至一寸五分。</p>

<p>运用：该穴治疗踝痛用扭伤，十四经无出其右者，针则健侧取穴。并活动患侧，该穴为杨维杰所创用。笔者在应用时，发现若在大指掌骨黑白肉际处寻压压痛点以定位，不唯则疗效更胜杨氏小节穴一筹，更治脚后跟疼痛。且疗效极著，非杨氏小节穴所能比拟）。</p>

<p><strong>方法二</strong></p>

<p>脚踝扭伤，在手大鱼际处可找到一压痛点，按十分钟即可减痛大半，两三次即可痊愈。左脚伤按右手，右脚伤按左手。</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/ankel-xuewei.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>鱼际：手太阴肺经穴。在手拇指本节(第1掌指关节)后凹陷处，约当第1掌骨中点桡侧，赤白肉际处。手太阴肺经的荥穴。</p>

<p>鱼际 - 定位在手拇指本节（第一掌指关节）后凹陷处，第一掌骨桡侧中点赤白肉际处。</p>

<p>按压昆仑与照海，一样可以消肿。</p>

<p>扭伤用大陵特好</p>

<p>董氏奇穴的“小节穴”，同样取对侧，进针后平行于第一掌骨向腕关节方向平刺一寸半，患者扭伤的踝部会出现异样温热感，令患者活动患部，往往肿消痛止，取效甚速。</p>

<p>外踝养老阳池，内踝大陵</p>

<h2>【总结】</h2>

<p>扭伤按照西医处理方式，在网上尚未搜索到有完全恢复的案例（不排除好了就不提了）。中医处理方式也只有少数放血疗法有短期恢复的案例，也有其他处理方式，但痊愈者不多。多数为减缓症状类。</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">脚踝扭伤</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Print the Schengen VISA Application Form in A3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/02/print-the-schengen-visa-application-form-in-a3/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T00:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/02/print-the-schengen-visa-application-form-in-a3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are preparing the documents for the Schengen VISA to Italy &amp; France.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s such a big project for a 15 days journey, and it will be our first time to Europe &#8211; attracted by its cultrue, landscape &amp; fresh air :p</p>

<p>Here the tips to print the Italy VISA application form in a A3 paper. Yes, I mean the printer settings(打印机设置):</p>

<h2>First,</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>Page Size（页面尺寸）: A4</p></li>
<li><p>Output Size（输出尺寸）: A3</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Second,</h2>

<ul>
<li>Layout（布局）: 2 in 1</li>
</ul>


<h2>Third,</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>Double Side（双面打印）</p></li>
<li><p>Short Edge （短边装订）</p></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h2>Last!</h2>

<ul>
<li>Print pages（打印页面）: <strong>4,1,2,3</strong></li>
</ul>


<p>The point is we could specify the order of pages.</p>

<p>这就是打印A3意大利申根签证申请表的打印机设置了。希望对大家有所帮助。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SSH Connect to BB10 Device]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/02/ssh-connect-to-bb10-device/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T00:23:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/03/02/ssh-connect-to-bb10-device</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How to connect to your BB10 device or simulator?</p>

<h2>Step 1:</h2>

<p><strong>Turn on Development Mode</strong></p>

<h2>Step 2: </h2>

<p><strong>Creating an RSA2 key</strong></p>

<pre><code>ssh-keygen -t rsa -b 4096
</code></pre>

<p>and choose a name as you like, here using <strong>rsa-bbx</strong></p>

<h2>Step 3: </h2>

<p><strong>Start Connect Service</strong></p>

<pre><code>blackberry-connect -targetHost 169.254.0.1 -devicePassword 1234 -sshPublicKey rsa-bbx.pub
</code></pre>

<p>keep this console there.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Step 4:</h2>

<p><strong>Make the SSH connection</strong></p>

<p>start another console, make the ssh connection</p>

<pre><code>ssh devuser@169.254.0.1 -i rsa-bbx
</code></pre>

<p>If you are connecting to a simulator, find the IP at the bottom of simulator window.</p>

<p>NOTICE: Make sure the file <strong>rsa-bbx</strong> and <strong>rsa-bbx.pub</strong> is in current path, or you could use its full path.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Code - BBC]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-code-bbc/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T22:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-code-bbc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Code</strong>: A mysterious code underpins the world. But what does it mean and what can we learn from it? Marcus du Sautoy takes us on an odyssey to uncover the code and reveal its meaning.</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/the-code.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b00zs6sl/episodes/guide">Episode guide</a></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Numbers</h2>

<p>1/3 Marcus du Sautoy reveals how significant numbers apear throughout the natural world.</p>

<h2>Shapes</h2>

<p>2/3 Marcus du Sautoy uncovers the patterns that explain the shape of the world around us.</p>

<h2>Prediction</h2>

<p>3/3 Marcus du Sautoy discovers what the code can say about our future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost All Camera Photos in My Nexus 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/02/20/lost-all-camera-photos-in-my-nexus-7/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-20T20:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/02/20/lost-all-camera-photos-in-my-nexus-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My 8G Nexus 7, No rooted, Updated to android Jelly Bean 4.2.2 at 18 Feb.</p>

<p>Now all photos in folder DCIM/Camera, were lost - Now way to restore currently, and vanish in the air.</p>

<p>The first lost was found yesterday, there were only 5 photos left.</p>

<p>The day, I debug an simple PhoneGap app in android with Developer Mode and USB debugging turned on.</p>

<p>When I reach my PC at home, connected the device with USB cable, turned on Developer Mode and USB debugging. And try a few restore software, but all failed to show the &#8220;Internal Storage&#8221;, so I gave up. But then I found the photos lost again - only one photo file left now. What the hell happened?</p>

<p>Today, I tried to find out a solution, but nothing could help.</p>

<p>At last, turn on the photo sync and backup the two large thumbdata in folder DCIM/.thumbnails/, one is 303MB, another one is 1.01GB.</p>

<p>My photos! Vanish in Nexus 7 updated to Jelly Bean 4.2.2 and Google could not provide any help on it.</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">Nexus 7</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
