<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-01T08:23:28+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living Unit]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/04/01/living-unit/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-01T07:19:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/04/01/living-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这里说的Living Unit，原指个人，后发觉其实对于一个公司或者机构、组织也是如此。</p>

<p>活个体的构成从原始的单细胞生物，到人类个体，家庭，公司机构，并没有太大的区别，只是规模，资源和能力种类差异。</p>

<p>以下的胡思乱想均来自对个人能力思考的延伸。</p>

<p>任何一个活个体（Living Unit）构成为3个部分：1）<strong>自有资源</strong>；2）<strong>自有能力</strong>；3）<strong>关联场景</strong>。</p>

<h2>自有资源</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>物品</p></li>
<li><p>空间</p></li>
<li><p>介品 （如货币等）</p></li>
<li><p>本体</p></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h2>自有能力</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>资源能力：拥有种类、数量，存储，运输，交换，整合。</p></li>
<li><p>知识（广度，深度，关联）</p></li>
<li><p>问题处理（发现，分析，解决）</p></li>
<li><p>沟通（表达，理解）</p></li>
<li><p>总结，预测</p></li>
<li><p>本体维持、升级</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>关联场景</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>创造培养关联的场景</p></li>
<li><p>维护和强化良性场景</p></li>
<li><p>关联资源</p></li>
<li><p>关联能力</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/asset-ability-connect.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>根据活个体的构成，其发展分为两方面：1）<strong>本体强化</strong>；2）<strong>关联强化</strong>。</p>

<h2>本体强化</h2>

<p><strong>学习</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>外部能力的复制，再造</p></li>
<li><p>外部实践中总结</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>实践</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>根据资源和能力输出的反馈对本体进行修正和调整</li>
</ul>


<h2>关联强化</h2>

<p><strong>建立关联</strong></p>

<ul>
<li><p>通过本体输出创建关联场景</p></li>
<li><p>接入外部关联场景</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>维护关联</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>保持关联场景的良性状态</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>强化关联</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>吸引更多连接接入已有关联场景</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>关联输入</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>从关联及输出中增强自有资源/自有能力的拥有量。</li>
</ul>


<p>不管是对于个人或者机构组织，或者是简单的生物个体，其在环境中生存和发展都必须具备条件。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Wear]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/android-wearable-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T22:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/android-wearable-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/wear/">Android Wear</a> SDK makes Android apps connected with wearable devices. The <a href="http://moto360.motorola.com/">Moto 360</a> is coming.</p>

<p>First, <a href="http://developer.android.com/wear/preview/start.html">Sign Up</a> for the Developer Preview.</p>

<p>You could joining the <a href="http://g.co/androidweardev">Android Wear Developers</a> Google+ Community.</p>

<p>Then, you will get an email providing link of example and <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/com.google.android.wearablepreview.app">Android Wear Preview App</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Third, you need to download <a href="https://developer.android.com/sdk/">Android SDK</a> and start the emulator for Android Wear, one is Round, another is Square both 1.7&#8217;.</p>

<p>Connect the wear emulator with the Android Wear Preview app, then your android device notifications will be shown in the emulator screen.</p>

<blockquote><p> Android Wear extends the Android platform to a new generation of wearable devices.</p>

<p> Small, powerful devices, worn on the body. Useful information when you need it most. Intelligent answers to spoken questions. Tools to help reach fitness goals. Your key to a multiscreen world.</p></blockquote>

<p>There&#8217;s a <a href="www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/19/apk-teardown-download-you-can-try-the-android-wear-launcher-on-your-device-now-heres-whats-inside/">wear launcher</a> about 3.8MB,</p>

<p>and another Wear Preview App apk (named Android_Wear_Beta.apk, 600+KB) for those incompatible andriod devices.</p>

<blockquote><p> The Android Wear Preview app is compatible with Android 4.3 and higher and is not available for the Android emulator.</p></blockquote>

<p><span id="link-tags">Android Wear Preview;Wear Preview App apk</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A false linkable text sample]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/a-false-linkable-text-sample/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T05:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/a-false-linkable-text-sample</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found a link in a Google+ post failed to be opened someday. It&#8217;s awkful, right? It&#8217;s on Google+! The Google - who leads the web tech.</p>

<p>Then I confirmed the same false link sample showing up in BlackBerry 10.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve double checked it in my WeChat under Android - it&#8217;s there too. But not in the WeChat for BlackBerry 10.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The false link sample is like this:</p>

<p><strong>(http://mindon.github.io?testing)&#8230;something-else</strong></p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a snapshot from Google+</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/false-link.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The case is showing up almost everywhere - we are using the same library to detect links.</p>

<p>Our test team and I could not accept this result in WeChat for BlackBerry 10, then here comes my customized linkable text detecting code in JavaScript.</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/mindon/9317393.js"></script>


<p>It helps to avoid this issue and provides you the customized possibility.</p>

<p><span id="link-tags">WeChat;BlackBerry 10;Google+</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A callstack trace for QML js]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/a-callstack-trace-for-qml-js/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T05:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/20/a-callstack-trace-for-qml-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>QNX RTOS is a awesome OS. That&#8217;s where BlackBerry 10 comes from.</p>

<p>The last year (2013), we&#8217;d spent lots of time on the WeChat for BlackBerry 10.</p>

<p>QML tech is good for an mobile app UI, using JavaScript. And there&#8217;s no <code>console.trace()</code> in QML to trace the callstacks, here&#8217;s mine:</p>

<!--more-->




<script src="https://gist.github.com/mindon/9524222.js"></script>


<p><span id="link-tags">RTOS;BlackBerry 10;QML</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A UI Unit]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/16/a-ui-unit/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-16T09:33:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/16/a-ui-unit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What kind of basic abilities should be with an UI unit?</p>

<p>As a web developer, an UI includes: Data, DOM, CSS, JavaScript.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s Data, Data Container, Display Style, Interactions.</p>

<p>First, an UI needs datum: 1) Static data;  2) Dynamic data [Optional]</p>

<!--more-->


<p>For dynamic data, it needs these abilities:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Receive initialization data, it may be tranfered from another UI unit.</p></li>
<li><p>Transfer data to another UI unit;</p></li>
<li><p>Subscribe data changes;</p></li>
<li><p>Publish data changes.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Interactions may change datum, data containers or styles.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>UI enter/exit events</p></li>
<li><p>UI active/disactive events</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[QML Features Should be in BlackBerry 10 OS]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/15/qml-features-expected-in-blackberry-10-os/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-15T18:51:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/15/qml-features-expected-in-blackberry-10-os</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m one of developers of WeChat BB10 version. Mainly charge on QML UI and interactivities with app APIs.</p>

<p>BB10 WeChat may be one of the most complex bb10 apps in BlackBerry World.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s features should be in BB10 QML, which I implemented in the WeChat mobile app for BB10.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>QML actived event</p></li>
<li><p>QML closed event</p></li>
<li><p>QML Data Share Methods: a) Method to tranfer data from QML A to B ( open B from A ); b) Methods to set/get/clear app shared data in QML.</p></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li><p>QML reuse or not ( A - B - C - D: if open QML B from D, close D and C, reuse B )</p></li>
<li><p>QML asyn publish/subscribe methods</p></li>
<li><p>Flag to turn off auto-translation in system language ( Dialog, Back and Invocations )</p></li>
<li><p>Support mutil-image previewer (zoomable) with invocation.</p></li>
<li><p>Letters scrollbar</p></li>
<li><p>A method to call js methods in QML from ListItem</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If BlackBerry 10 want more better apps, Its QML should provide features above. Or in a js library for QML.</p>

<p><span id="link-tags">BB10;BlackBerry;WeChat;QML</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic Abilities of Intelligent]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/15/basic-abilities-of-intelligent/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-15T18:21:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/15/basic-abilities-of-intelligent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>智能的基本能力：</p>

<ul>
<li><p>对于情景有很灵活的反应；</p></li>
<li><p>充分利用机遇；</p></li>
<li><p>弄懂含糊不清或彼此矛盾的信息；</p></li>
<li><p>认识到一个情境中什么是重要的因素，什么是次要的；</p></li>
<li><p>在存在差异的情景之间能发现它们的相似处；</p></li>
<li><p>从那些由相似之处联系在一起的事物中找出差别；</p></li>
<li><p>用旧的概念综合出新的概念，把它们用新的方法组合起来；</p></li>
<li><p>提出全新的观念。</p></li>
</ul>


<p> 从《GEB集异璧》里对智能的描述项，对比一下自己，能力上还是有很多不足的地方，比如：充分利用机遇；以及认识一个情境中的重要和次要因素方面就存在不足。其它的应该还算不错了。</p>

<p> 注：《GEB集异璧》中文版2013年第7版了，很厚的神书一本，近千余页。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Lost of MH370]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/10/the-lost-of-mh370/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T07:14:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/10/the-lost-of-mh370</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Sunday, March 09, 02:43 PM MYT +0800 Malaysia Airlines MH370 Flight Incident&#8221;</p>

<p>马来西亚航空公司证实MH370航班于三月九号凌晨2点40分与苏邦空中交通管制台失去联系。MH370航班由波音777-200机型执飞，该航班于三月九号凌晨0点41分由吉隆坡起飞前往北京，原计划于北京时间早晨6点30份抵达北京首都国际机场。该航班总共运载239人 - 其中包括227名旅客（2名婴儿）及12名机组人员。航班的乘客来自于14个国家。</p>

<p>有老人、小孩；他们之中有艺术家，工程师和佛法信徒，经验丰富的飞行员，机组人员。</p>

<p>二百多条生命，在过去的几十个小时里牵动这全球人们的心。11国政府联合，出动了数十架飞机，数十艘船只进行搜索，至今无果。</p>

<!--more-->


<blockquote><p> 马航MH370航班在失去联系前，当时位于北纬4.7073度，东经102.5278度，航向东北方向25°，飞行速度468节（867公里/小时），飞行高度10668米。</p>

<p> 飞机当时刚刚结束起飞后的爬升，正转入万米高空的稳定平飞状态，距离起飞的吉隆坡国际机场204公里，保持25度的北偏东角度向北京飞行。即将从新加坡飞航情报区，转入胡志明飞航情报区管制范围。</p></blockquote>

<p>We are keep praying for the lives on MH370. 我们一直在为MH370上的生命在祈福，期待奇迹的出现。</p>

<p>估计已经有无数人对这起离奇的空中事故提出了各种分析和议论，在强大的揪心+好奇心的驱动下，我也尝试一下以自己的没有边缘的想象力来分析一下。</p>

<p>说起飞机离奇失踪，很多人印象里自然会和百慕大三角关联起来。我是小学时候看过《飞碟之谜》的，不管大家如何看待，这些事情的确激发了无数人的好奇心和想象。对的，就是某些人眼里的“路边摊文学”里的东西。</p>

<p>近年来做产品开发，一直有一个看法：要释放所有束缚，秉着一切皆有可能的态度来分析产品。现在，释放一下想象力吧。</p>

<p>首先，飞机是突然消失的。我们目前的结论是，飞机没有来得及发出求救信号。没错，这是可能性之一。另外一种可能是，飞机已经发出了求救信号，但由于莫名干扰，导致信号无法到达接收端。</p>

<p>其次，飞机消失前曾有折返行为。这种行为的可能之一：飞机是肯定已经发出了求救或者报告，无奈没有接收到回复，自行折返。另外一种可能是不明力量漩涡导致飞机呈螺旋式运动。</p>

<p>再者，曾有飞机与MH370联系，信号遭到莫名干扰，频道不正常。</p>

<p>综合各种可能，可以发现：1）通讯信号，雷达信号收到即时的干扰和屏蔽；2）飞机有异常的空间运动行为；3）飞机是一定有发送求救信号的。</p>

<p>那么，MH370到哪去了呢？澄清一点，我并不是炙热韩剧《来自星星的你》的观众。对于时空的了解也不仅限于“路边摊文学”。</p>

<p>时空发生扭曲，或是虫洞或这黑洞，都是有可能的。没有否定的证据之前，不要根据常识来否定事情。毕竟，这是一次离奇的空中事故。</p>

<p>按基督的理念，是天使召集了这群优秀的人们去了天堂。阿门。</p>

<p>佛法的解释，是天宫缺员，招募了一群天将。</p>

<p>拿假护照的两个外星人启动了乾坤大挪移的空间转移技术，劫持了这架MH370&#8230;</p>

<p>不瞎扯了，我们来看看MH370的可能位置：海面搜索工作目前还没有任何足信证据证明飞机已经坠落海上。可能一：飞机完整地沉入海底，这个难度很高。不过我们来想象一个难度更高的——飞机因为重力异常，掉入了太空。</p>

<p>据说，有乘客家属拨通手机了，或是QQ依旧在线。也就是说，手机依旧在卫星通讯范围之内。至于海底，手机防水应该没有那么好，海水不浅吧？信号肯定不好，且海水早就把手机毁掉了。所以，要不飞机就飞哪的陆地上坠毁了；要不就象《海底两万里》里的，被海底某个神秘的东西装了；要不，就是掉入了太空。</p>

<p>要让飞机的高度突然降为零，1）真掉下来可以做到；2）信号异常可以做到；3）设备毁坏可以做到。</p>

<p>对于我以上的胡扯八道，只是让我们来抛开一切思维和常识的束缚，来分析MH370可能的命运和出事的原因。毕竟，现有的知识暂时还不能给出一个答案。</p>

<p>最后，祈祷，为MH370，期待奇迹的出现。</p>

<p>机上所有人员的亲属们，节哀。大家继续为MH370祈福。</p>

<p><span id="link-tags">MH370;百慕大三角</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[UltimEyes: to Improve Your Vision?]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/06/ultimeyes-to-improve-your-vision/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-06T06:19:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/06/ultimeyes-to-improve-your-vision</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The UltimEyes, is a mobile app for <strong>iPad</strong> series with <strong>retina</strong> only.</p>

<blockquote><p> “ULTIMEYES® is a non-invasive interactive program designed specifically to improve vision by optimizing visual processing in just four simple 25-minute sessions per week for a total duration of eight weeks.”</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p>It is said that it has potential to improve vision! That&#8217;s an app i expected to see long time ago. Now it comes one, but the UltimeEyes Pro requests a serial number and UltimeEyes is saling  almost 6 US$, that&#8217;s 40RMB on iTune - a little bit high price for an app you don&#8217;t know much.</p>

<p>University of California, Riverside neuroscientist Aaron Seitz, who created the software, shared recent results with Current Biology, with eye-popping results:</p>

<blockquote><p> “Seitz worked with 19 players on the University of California, Riverside, baseball team, and showed that his app UltimEyes lengthened the distance at which the players could see clearly by an average of 31 percent. After using the app for 30 25-minute intervals, players saw an improvement that pushed many of them beyond normal 20/20 vision, including seven who attained freakishly good 20/7.5 vision—meaning that at a distance of 20 feet, they were clearly seeing what someone with normal vision could see at no farther than 7.5 feet away.”</p></blockquote>

<p>The game is showing you some fuzzy patterns that you try to identify as quickly as possible from a similarly colored background. Faster speeds and repetition “teach” the brain to better process visual stimulation quicker, which may result in improved vision at farther distances.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s more like a brain game than an eyes training.</p>

<p>To train the eyes themself, it should be a device with at least two parts: one near, one far - to switch status of the eyeballs and its control muscles around.</p>

<p>Is the app will work for most people around the world? We are staring all kinds of screens all day long. It&#8217;s such an important thing to keep our eyes sharp and clear.</p>

<p><a href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2012/04/26/the-eye-limits-the-brains-learning-potential/">The eye limits the brain&#8217;s learning potential</a></p>

<p><span id="link-tags">UltimEyes;iPad;Retina;iTune</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[时间和先进]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/time-and-advanced/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T12:26:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/time-and-advanced</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>某些无知的人否定一些东西的时候，总喜欢拿已知的知识和时间是否更靠近现在来作为判断标准。</p>

<p>其实，我们应该意识到3点：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>科学技术一直都是往未知的方向发展的；</p></li>
<li><p>即使是时间也没有否定未知的能力；</p></li>
<li><p>人类的知识还是非常有限的。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>不多说，对比一下 21世纪 Touch Bionics 用尽最先进的科学技术生产的智能仿生手 i-LIMB Hand 和大自然数百万年前生产的人类手</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/ilimb-pulse.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://www.sdmuseum.com/lx_show.aspx?id=5737&amp;cid=60">“手”的进化</a></p>

<p>在绝大多方面，现代医学的技术和人体自身的修复能力还是不能同日而语的，要认识几百万年进化的成果还需不少时日的。</p>

<p>人类的科技还在持续不断发展，而且已经取得了难以置信的成果，然后，相对于大自然和浩瀚宇宙来说，还只是沧海一粟，和大自然数十亿年的积累和进化对比，距离不是一点点。不要再自以为是地否定未知，特别是拿时间来衡量是否先进了。</p>

<p>展望一下医疗的终极未来：身体修复方案和知识共享，并能够自行修复任何损伤和破坏。</p>

<ol>
<li><p>身体能够自动积累和改善修复方案；</p></li>
<li><p>身体能够自行根据修复方案修复问题；</p></li>
<li><p>身体能够自动分享和获取修复方案，并根据自身状况有效调整修复方案；</p></li>
<li><p>身体根据修复方案引领自身寻找修复资源或获取协助；</p></li>
<li><p>身体对环境的威胁给出预警和建议。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>从这5点看来，目前的医疗科技还是相当落后的，挖据身体的潜能，读懂身体的状态指示，协助身体自身的修复才是医疗的未来。</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">Touch Bionics;i-LIMB Hand;手的进化</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[科技+健康生活环境]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/tech-helps-needed-for-a-good-health/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T12:08:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/02/tech-helps-needed-for-a-good-health</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>居住在一个大城市里，对生活环境的获取和牺牲都是必然的，科技在这方面能帮到的并不多。</p>

<p>健康的生活环境，以下几点是必须的：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>清新干净空气</p>

<p>这个貌似非常困难，大环境看来，工业/汽车是最大的威胁。</p>

<p>小环境看来，窗户还做不到只让空气进出，把灰尘和有害毒物挡在窗外或直接消化掉。</p></li>
<li><p>安静</p>

<p>环境噪音主要来自汽车，这个也是大环境，暂时是无法消灭的。</p>

<p>小环境来看，对付噪音污染，可以安装隔音玻璃窗，或者搬家，要不就塞住自己的耳朵，此外也别无他法。</p></li>
<li><p>黑夜</p>

<p>大环境光污染更是没办法了，部分昼夜的城市的必然产物。</p>

<p>小环境，拉遮光窗帘还是可以解决的。</p></li>
<li><p>干净安全的饮水和食品</p>

<p>大环境下这个东西只能靠社会良心了。</p>

<p>小环境，可以自己种，或者多花些钱和精力找安全和有良心的来源。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>要对付这些环境对健康的威胁，所谓高速发达的科学技术还是无能为力的。确切地说，这些威胁都来自科技发展的副效应。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>目前唯一能够解决所有这些问题的办法就是，搬到一个远离科技，有大片绿树隔离的村落。</p>

<p>或者，期待科技更进一步，提供更可行的避免过滤尘灰、空气污染、噪音和光污染、食品污染的技术方案。（其实希望并不大，看看北京突破500的PM2.5就知道了）</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">光污染;食品污染;噪音污染;PM2.5</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[在地铁出口离世的年青女子]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/the-young-woman-died-at-the-exit-of-metro/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T20:10:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/the-young-woman-died-at-the-exit-of-metro</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>两个星期前的周一（2月17日，2014年）的上午10点29分，在我居住的地方南边约5公里，靠近海边的地铁站——水湾站C出口，一位年仅35岁的未婚女子倒下了，再也没有起来。</p>

<p>一个留英归来在IBM工作的女子生命逝去，其父母已年迈七八十，白发人送黑发人。这不能不说是一个令人心酸、心寒、心痛的悲剧。</p>

<p>女子从倒下到专业救护人员到场，经历了50分钟左右，得不到及时抢救是丢掉性命的关键。</p>

<p>又一条宝贵的生命就这样离去了，给我们带来了什么样的反思呢？</p>

<p>从一个程序员的角度，是系统出故障了，对于这样的状况失去了修复能力。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>人类社会，作为生态系统的一部分，应该具有高度的自我修复能力，就如人类的身体本身一样。</p>

<p>虽说人类的科技能力已经发展飞快，但是女子身上的手机救不了她的性命，随身带者的笔记本电脑也没有任何帮助…</p>

<p>系统故障在于，没有作出最快最有效的能够救助女子性命的响应。附近没有可提供救助的服务，可能有（据说附近20米左右有一间中医理疗店）但获取需要救助信息的人没能有效并及时地把需要救助的信息带到可能提供救助服务的点。</p>

<p>救助信息传到120救助中心，救助人员到达中间过程消耗了30分钟以上，这中间对于出现状况女子的生命来说，每一分每一秒都是至关重要的。</p>

<p>理想的救助系统响应应该是怎样的呢？</p>

<ol>
<li><p>女子倒下，马上激活周边目击行人；</p>

<p>这次事故中，激活救助行为是在3分钟的点，响应迟钝。</p></li>
<li><p>目击人群可能能力：a）普通人：传播需要救助信息到救助服务点；b）半专业人士：提供有利于救助的即时帮助；c）专业人士：直接提供救助。</p>

<p>事故3分钟时才激活目击行人，开始传达需要救助的信息，信息从行人通知到地铁工作人员到来花了3分多钟，从地铁工作人员汇报到到达120估计也花了若干时间，中间没有任何有利于救助的措施：遮垫（风大，气温寒凉）。</p>

<p>系统缺乏响应处理素质和效率。</p>

<p>要避免类似事故，需要从基本教育、社区、公司/集体等多方面普及急救常识，技能和意识。</p></li>
<li><p>专业/半专业救助网络：120救助点不应限于大医院，应包括社区诊所、具有医学知识和服务能力的服务机构，如理疗店铺。周边居住的专业医务人员等等。</p>

<p>系统这块完全分散，没有整合成网络。</p></li>
<li><p>专业救助效率：救助网络应该对求救作出网络式响应，最快救助服务提供点优先响应，最有效的救助服务提供者同时响应。</p></li>
</ol>


<p>系统如果具备这些能力，这位年青女子不至于如此轻易就失去宝贵生命。然而现实是，对比各种繁复的流程和规章制度，生命好像都没有那么重要。</p>

<p>类似的状况如果出现在我们自己身上，依旧不能避免悲剧的可能。因为，目前的社会系统并不具备有效救助的能力。</p>

<p>我虽然简单从一个学过CPR的同事那了解过CPR，但是我也不敢贸然提供救助行为。因为我刚知道这个悲剧的时候，心想就没人把她扶一下躺平——随后了解急救知识之后，把自己吓了一跳，有呼吸的情况下最好让需要救助者侧卧，避免窒息。非专业的普通人不要随意实施救助行为是正确的，但一定要即时拨打救助电话，或就近寻求可能提供救助的人。</p>

<p>另外一个反思点：人们在以过度消耗自己健康和生命的方式在工作，有些公司还在强化这种观念，这也是促成猝死年轻化的根源之一。</p>

<h1>心肺复苏术 CPR 基本步驟:</h1>

<p><strong>看</strong>: 周围是否存在危险因素，危险因素是否排除？</p>

<h2>确认伤患状况</h2>

<p>1）确实是否还有意识和反应：在伤患旁呼唤，同时拍其肩部；</p>

<p>2）确认呼吸是否正常；</p>

<h2>求救</h2>

<p>1）若周边没有人，大声呼救；</p>

<p>2）即刻自行或叫旁人拨打求救电话 110；（台湾119，美国911）</p>

<p>（若为溺水/创伤/中毒/8岁以下小孩，又无旁人时则做CPR 两分钟后再电话求救）</p>

<h2>C-A-B 循环</h2>

<p><strong>Circulation 胸部按压促进血液循环</strong></p>

<p><strong>Airway 打开呼吸道</strong></p>

<p><strong>Breathing 吹气供氧，提供人工呼吸</strong></p>

<p>重复以下步骤：C 30次，A，B 2次</p>

<p>一直重复3个步骤直至伤患有呼吸或专业急救人员到达。</p>

<p><strong>C</strong>: 30次按压： 掌跟重叠，手肘打直，以身体力量按压两乳之间的胸骨；约100次/分钟，深度5公分恢复原位；</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: 清理气道：压额抬下巴，检查并保证喉咙通畅；</p>

<p><strong>B</strong>: 2次吹气：压额手捏伤患鼻孔，往口腔吹气至胸腹有上升，松开鼻孔；再重复一次。</p>

<p><a href="http://www.guokr.com/article/81088/">自我CPR自救</a></p>

<p><i id="link-tags">IBM;心肺复苏术;水湾站;CPR</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[大的变革已经在路上]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/big-changes-is-on-the-way/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T19:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/big-changes-is-on-the-way</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>阿里的余额宝，微信的理财宝带来的金融领域的变革已经势不可挡。</p>

<p>电子科技飞速发展的今天，还有多少行业和领域依旧停留在数十年前的传统模式？有多少行业还依旧被个别机构垄断？</p>

<p>金融业的变革迹象在引领着一场更大的变化，这个变化开始渗入日常的支付，虽然目前大家只看到了红包，网购、打车、充值和就餐的变化。在笔者看来，移动支付即将也必然会渗透到任何一个需要排队支付的地方，比如医院、景区、购票等等。任何一个需要消耗大家时间的支付场合，都应该实现移动的快速支付。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>阿里和腾讯的理财产品已经促进银行本身的改变。</p>

<p>微信和滴滴打车，支付宝和快的打车则引领着支付方式的变革。</p>

<p>中国的高速物流也同样在引领着世界物流的发展。</p>

<p>近年来比特币的火热，也预示着金融互联网化的一种趋势，虽然比特币广受政府机构抵制，这些月来还爆Mt.Gox巨额亏损破产的消息；但是，金融行业的互联网化，特别是移动互联网化的行动已经迈开脚步，是任何势力都无法阻止的。</p>

<p>金融的变革必然带来很多问题和变化，大大提高人们的支付效率以及货币的流通速度。</p>

<p>电子商务的变革也带给传统商店不小的冲击。</p>

<p>所有的这些正在起跑的变革，会把我们的未来引向何处？又会带来什么样难以预想的变化呢？我们拭目以待。</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">电子商务;比特币;余额宝;理财宝;腾讯;阿里;滴滴打车;支付宝;快的打车</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY知识点滴]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/e-diy-tech-info/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T14:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/03/01/e-diy-tech-info</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>突然想对电动机多了解一些，于是上淘宝搜了一下各种航模电动机。还是真是各种各样的，补习一下相关知识：</p>

<h2>步进电动机</h2>

<p>步进电机单靠交流供电或直流电源无法运动，必须与驱动电路同时使用时才能发挥其功能，驱动器（驱动电路）由决定换向顺序的控制电路（或称为逻辑电路）与控制电机输出功率的换相电路（或称为功率电路（power stage））组成。步进电机驱动是的步骤： 1，要提供适合于步进电机所需要的电源； 2，需要输入脉冲和方向信号，一般是按TTL标准电平，输入一个步进脉冲，电机就步进一个步距角； 3，驱动器的输出：A+,A-,B+,B-，由驱动器去完成。 (不需输入包含A+,A-,B+,B- 4个端口高低电平的信息)</p>

<p><a href="http://zhidao.taobao.com/detail/-3F713DB2BDBDF8B5E7BBFAD1A1D0CDCEE5B4F3B2BD.html">步进电机选型五大步</a></p>

<p>步进电机可以作为一种控制用的特种电机，利用其没有积累误差(精度为100%)的特点，广泛应用于各种开环控制。</p>

<p>步进电动机的主要缺点是效率较低，并且需要专用电源供给电脉冲信号，带负载惯量的能力不强，在运行中会出现共振和振荡问题。</p>

<h2>无刷马达</h2>

<p>直流电机具有响应快速、较大的起动转矩、从零转速至额定转速具备可提供额定转矩的性能。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>有刷马达的碳刷及整流子在电机转动时会产生火花。</p>

<p><strong>内转子</strong>，就是将线圈绕于马达外侧，将转子制成棒状，固定于马达内。在不需要特别大的扭力，转速高情况下采用。</p>

<p><strong>外转子</strong>，则是将线圈绕组置于内部，将磁铁制成特殊形状，在外侧围绕内置的线圈转动。在需要大扭力的场合下使用。</p>

<p><strong>KV值</strong>是无刷马达的转速指标，是指每增加1V电压，马达转速增加的数值。</p>

<p>线圈绕组的数值是T数，或者R（NOVAK的都用R表示，其他很多用T表示）。一般来说，无刷T（或者R）的数值和此数值2倍的有刷马达相当.</p>

<p>“无刷电调必须知道转子当前的位置，才能输出适当的电流来驱动马达。有感是通过装在马达上的感应器，感知转子当前的位置（相位）。 无感就是没有感应器，电调靠动力线上的电流变化判断转子相位。” &#8211;JOVI</p>

<p>无感无刷的起步线性比较差。</p>

<h2>霍尔元件</h2>

<p>是一种基于霍尔效应的磁传感器。用它们可以检测磁场及其变化，可在各种与磁场有关的场合中使用。</p>

<p>霍尔效应，是指磁场作用于载流金属导体、半导体中的载流子时，产生横向电位差的物理现象。</p>

<p>金属的霍尔效应是1879年被 美国物理学家霍尔发现的。当电流通过金属箔片时，若在垂直于电流的方向施加磁场，则金属箔片两侧面会出现横向电位差。半导体中的霍尔效应比金属箔片中更为明显，而铁磁金属在居里温度以下将呈现极强的霍尔效应。</p>

<p>Mark一个淘宝店：
<a href="http://szjs88998899.taobao.com/shop/view_shop.htm?user_number_id=920426663"> 深圳杰盛电机</a></p>

<h2>吸尘器</h2>

<p>传统的吸尘器原理很简单：通过压缩机制造真空，将杂物、尘土和空气一起吸入，再用一个网眼密集的过滤装置（现在多为纸质的尘袋），将杂物、细小的尘埃挡在里面，把过滤过的空气排出吸尘器。</p>

<p>戴森的吸尘器采用的Radial Root Cyclone（多圆锥气旋）技术，通过真空泵和气旋发生装置，在吸尘器机体内制造一个旋转上升的涡旋，就像一场小规模的龙卷风，灰尘和各种杂质在涡旋中旋转起来，被自身的离心力甩出气旋中心，落到气旋周围的尘杯中。</p>

<p><a href="http://www.dyson.cn/vacuums.aspx">Dyson.CN</a></p>

<p><a href="http://detail.tmall.hk/hk/item.htm?spm=a1z10.5.w4011-5310708660.59.sIYcRM&amp;id=36959234140&amp;rn=ca866e3781d42a98c7b984bf9b5d46ca">DC62</a></p>

<p><i id="link-tags">Dyson;多圆锥气旋;霍尔效应;步进电机;无刷马达;吸尘器;航模</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WeChat, BlackBerry, Apps and Web - My 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/01/02/wechat-blackberry-apps-and-web-2013/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T20:56:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2014/01/02/wechat-blackberry-apps-and-web-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s the begining of 2014.</p>

<p>How about my 2013?</p>

<h2>Mindon Labs</h2>

<p>I&#8217;ve tried a few chrome apps and extensions. The most welcomed one is &#8220;Ingress Portals Finder&#8221;, published on Chrome webstore but taken down due to TOS problem. It&#8217;s tool for the game <strong>Ingress</strong>. Though it didn&#8217;t work any more due to the &lt;ingress.com> website API upgrades,  its donation reached $52. It was a inspired project, thanks to the ingress players who supports the chrome extension.</p>

<p>The other simple Chrome extension with 4K+ installation is &#8220;Tips for WeChat&#8221;. It&#8217;s an experiment relative with my work.</p>

<p>Another Chrome extension is GO2, it&#8217;s a simple helper to reach google search results when blocked by the GFW, it&#8217;s installation is around 2k.</p>

<p>My first try on Chrome Package App is the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/who/ankcmofggngiopfblnaojmiclfffinle/related">Who</a>, from the extension with the same name.</p>

<p>Now i&#8217;m learning the Mobile-Chrome-App tech with Apache Cordova, to make it works under iOS and Android.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Before this, I was trying to turn the extension &#8220;Ingress Portals Finder&#8221; into an Android App with the same idea just before the &lt;ingress.com> APIs updated.</p>

<p>I love Chrome Package Apps. they works and looks amazing with the advantages of HTML5 and Javascript, CSS3 techs.</p>

<p>Today, I find that the BlackBerry&#8217;s WebWorks SDK has updated to 2.0 beta, which is also using Apache Cordova. I&#8217;ve try a simple sample there and it works fine in my BlackBerry Q10 dev alpha device.</p>

<p>Yes, the main cord of 2013 is mobiles apps.</p>

<p>My first android app was published on Google Play as <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mindon.idea.dasign">DaSign</a>, It&#8217;s a simple app about SVG (Scalable Vector Graphs), a interested topic.</p>

<p>Then another 3 Chinese books android apps experiment on using HTML, CSS and JavaScript in mobile apps.</p>

<p>They inpired me in mobile app developments.</p>

<h2>The work</h2>

<p>The main mobile app costing me months and months, is the BlackBerry 10 version of WeChat - the mobile app giant with 600M+ users. My main job in 2013 was make WeChat working on the BlackBerry 10 OS.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s my first time got to know about QNX, QML and touched latest BlackBerry devices. I enjoyed the challenge.</p>

<p>The year 2013, WeChat oversea reached 160M+ users. The WeChat BlackBerry 10 version released on BlackBerry world. Exciting!</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a year of chanllenge, a year of overtime working. But it worths.</p>

<p>Diving into BB10 for a WeChat app made me into a half-expert of BlackBerry 10 and QML.</p>

<h2>Learning</h2>

<p>Android, BlackBerry 10 Cascades Native App and WebWorks App development.</p>

<p>Go language - I love the powerful language. (Google App Engine supports GO and PHP languages in 2013)</p>

<p>Node.JS, now it&#8217;s everywhere. It&#8217;s my favorite. There&#8217;s free env on &lt;openshift.com>, both Node.JS and Go.</p>

<p>Chrome Apps. I&#8217;ll try more in 2014.</p>

<p>Apache Cordova will be my BlackBerry WebWorks and iOS, Android apps entrance for more app experiments. Mobile Chrome App will be great.</p>

<h2>Life</h2>

<p>It was the 7th year together with my darling Aby. She was so great in 2013. Plan our first travel to France and Italy. She studys IMC in HKU Space, studys English by herself, learned how to drive a car, and most of all making happiness around us. She&#8217;s amazing lady most important in my life. Make our 2013 such a wonderful year. At this moment, she is working on the 5k photos taken in France and Italy, two weeks from Apr to May, 2013 &#8211; pick the best of them and turn them into a photo book.</p>

<p>We sat on the short wall on Concorde in Pair, at 8pm, watching the sunset lights pouring on the Avenue des Champs-Élysées. That&#8217;s most beautiful and happiest moments.</p>

<p>In 2013, I&#8217;ve taken thousands of photos in France and Italy. Hundreds of photos using BlackBerry Z10 and Q10 &#8211; the new blackberry devices have a very good camera for daily life.</p>

<h2>Other</h2>

<p>Bought a Nexus 7 generation 2. A Jawbone is on my wrist as my birthday present from Aby. Wishing for a Moto X - but it&#8217;s too expensive and without a good enough camera; Want to buy a Nexus 5 next week from HK.</p>

<p>Makers were so active in Shenzhen - a southern city in China.</p>

<p>A share topic on BB 10 unfinished, lots of ideas waiting for being experimented.</p>

<p>&#8230; &#8230;</p>

<p>It was a busy, wonderful and growing year - the 2013.</p>

<p>Thanks and best wishes for all friends on the Earth :-)</p>

<p><i id="link-tags">BlackBerry 10;Blackberry;Mobile Chrome App;Node.JS;WeChat;QNX;QML;HKU Space;Chrome Package App;Apache Cordova</i></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally My Nexus 7 updated to 4.4 KitKat]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/26/finally-my-nexus-7-updated-to-4-dot-4-kitkat/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T20:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/26/finally-my-nexus-7-updated-to-4-dot-4-kitkat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning, the OTA Android <a href="http://www.android.com/kitkat/">KitKat 4.4</a> finally reached my Nexus 7 (2012) and Aby&#8217;s Nexus 7 (2013). It&#8217;s a long time waiting.</p>

<p>Nov. 13, 2013 Google announced that its Nexus 7 and Nexus 10 tablets are getting Android 4.4 KitKat. After clicking check update 13 days later, it&#8217;s such a long time :-p</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/n7-kitkat.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>There&#8217;s no ART in KitKat for Nexus 7 (2012). ( <a href="https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=62375">ART runtime is missing in Android 4.4 on Nexus 7 (2012)</a> )</p>

<p>Some apps are not working well under ART mode. some crashed. <a href="http://www.androidruntime.com/list">List of broken apps in Android RunTime</a></p>

<p>KitKat’s WebView is powered by Chromium, enabling Android app developers to use new HTML5 and CSS features.  <a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/webapps/migrating.html">Migrating to WebView in Android 4.4</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[被忽视的生物 Living Creatures Ignored]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/living-creatures-ignored/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T20:43:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/living-creatures-ignored</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>固有的生物定义可能会让我们忽视了一些常见的生物。</p>

<p>我们身边存在这样一类生物，它们吃的是人和货物，不要害怕，人和货物本身不是它们可以消化的营养，在吸收了它们需要的营养之后，人和货物都会被原样排泄出来。这类生物目前绝大部分还需要寄生到人类才可以生存，它们获取的营养会帮助其种群的进化和发展壮大。它们的衍生和发展也是要寄生到人类物种才能够进行，至少目前还处于这种阶段。近些年，它们已经进化到可以自行活动的阶段的。</p>

<p>这类生物发展诞生和发展的历史也相当悠久了，不过近几百年的进化非常迅速，行动速度更快了，种族也更加庞大了——衍生了可以在空中飞翔，水面游弋，水中遨游，陆地生存的不同种类。基本上有人类生活的地方，只要有条件，都会有这种生物的存在。</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>人类称这种生物为“交通工具”。</p>

<p>另外一种高速进化的生物对人类的影响更大。这类生物是新物种，出现不到两百年历史，从最初的笨重身躯到如今最小的细如发尖，甚至更小。它们的进化和种群发展也是极度依赖于人类的。它们由于能够强化人类对环境变化的传感能力、对变化的执行能力，对环境的预测能力，从而使人类一代又一代地投入其进化过程。</p>

<p>近十余年来，这类物种有一个类似病毒的分支进化最为迅速。人类依赖这个生物来建立关联，获取更多的信息和传播影响。而它们从人类对其的依赖中获取了各种进化所需的资源，加速其进化。</p>

<p>近些年来开始出现了这类生物类似病毒感染人类的现象：有人类受其影响对环境的感知和判断能力降低，从而导致意外死亡的状况。也就是说这类生物开始影响了人类的大脑。</p>

<p>人类称这种生物为“电子计算机”，其中进化最快影响最大的一个种族被成为“智能手机”。</p>

<p>这些生物的繁殖目前还属于寄生人类的状态，但这并不影响它们的进一步进化和种群发展。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Justice and Responsibility]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/justice-and-responsibility/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T20:03:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/11/09/justice-and-responsibility</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>哈佛Michael Sandel教授的《<a href="http://www.myoops.org/main.php?act=course&amp;id=2258">正義：一場思辨之旅</a>》第一堂课就给全世界的道德和正义带了一场思考风暴。其中最为经典的争议和疑惑就是下面的两种场景：</p>

<p>1）假設你是一個火車駕駛員，而你駕駛的這輛車正快速在軌道上行駛，時速六十英里，而在軌道盡頭有五個工人在工作，你試著想要煞車，但卻做不到，你的煞車失效了。你感到十分緊張，因為你知道，如果你撞上這五個工人，他們必死無疑。假設這是一個確定的結果，因此你感到非常無助，但接著你發現右邊有條岔路，而那條岔路底只有一個工人在工作，你的方向還可以控制，車輛還可以轉向，可以轉向岔路，撞死一名工人，但閃過五名工人。</p>

<p>2）這次你不是火車的駕駛員，你是個站在橋上的旁觀者，你正觀察著鐵軌上的狀況，軌道上來了一輛火車，軌道的盡頭有五名工人，煞車同樣失靈，而火車正要撞死那五名工人，由於你不是駕駛員，你覺得非常無助，直到你注意到旁邊有個人，在橋邊站著一個非常胖的人，你可以推他一把，他會掉落軌道，正好擋住該輛車，他會死，但他的犧牲可以救那五個人。</p>

<p>不管是哪中场景，如果作为决策者，你的决策是什么？为什么？</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>其实决策之所以引起很大的争议，是因为大家无意中忽略了责任的问题，而转向道德或者正义方面考虑。但是，对于事故来说，责任的承担才是公正的核心。道德的判断在某些情况下是盲目和片面的。</p>

<p>看一下第1）种状况分析图：
<img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/justice/j1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>同样从责任角度再来看第2）种情况：
<img src="http://mindon.github.com/images/blog/justice/j2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>可以看出，其实两种情况下责任分布是没有差别的，唯一的区别是决策者是不是事件的直接涉及者：1）是无法脱离干系的司机；2）是外部的旁观者。这个区别并不会改变原有的责任分布状况。</p>

<p>可能的争议其实是在责任承担代价的动摇上：那5个人的过错要不要用性命去承担的问题，或是决策者为了降低责任代价而采用牺牲1个无责任的人的性命？</p>

<p>如果换一个场景：5个人同时开枪枪杀了1个无辜的人。判决5个人死刑是很自然的“法律”决策者的选择，虽然这样也无法挽救那1个失去性命的无辜者。</p>

<p>区别是：这种情况下5个人是直接责任人，而上面的场景5个人和另外1个人之间并没存在任何责任关联，如果决策者选择了A方案——牺牲1人挽救5人，责任关联也只是在决策者和失去性命的1人之间建立的。</p>

<p>根本的问题在于我们过度采用了经济领域中的成本也就是代价理论，而不是责任承担来做判断和选择。要让公正和道德健康正面地发展和发挥其正面作用，责任承担才是社会最需要关注的点。</p>

<p>类似争议的根源也就是忽视了责任承担的关键点。</p>

<p>当然，并不是所有事情都能靠责任追究来解决的，譬如工作中关键就在避免问题的发生和解决问题，即使要追究责任的目的也是在此。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fix adb error under win8]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/fix-adb-error-under-win8/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T16:27:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/fix-adb-error-under-win8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>error: device not found</h2>

<p>1)  Find &#8220;Device Manager&#8221; in &#8220;PC Info&#8221;;</p>

<p>2)  Get your device in the &#8220;Other devices&#8221;;</p>

<p>3)  Update driver and choose your adt folder to install the driver.</p>

<h2>Failure [INSTALL_PARSE_FAILED_INCONSISTENT_CERTIFICATES]</h2>

<p>Uninstall your old version app on your device before install the new apk.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building mobile apps from the command line]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/build-mobile-apps-from-command-line/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T09:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2013/09/15/build-mobile-apps-from-command-line</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following are command line reference of building mobile apps for Android, iOS, BB10 and WP8.</p>

<h1>Android</h1>

<p>Managing Projects from the Command Line</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/projects/projects-cmdline.html">http://developer.android.com/tools/projects/projects-cmdline.html</a></p>

<h2>Creating an Android Project</h2>

<pre><code>android create project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--name &lt;your_project_name&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project \
--activity &lt;your_activity_name&gt; \
--package &lt;your_package_namespace&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Updating a Project</h2>

<pre><code>android update project --name &lt;project_name&gt; --target &lt;target_ID&gt;
--path &lt;path_to_your_project&gt;
</code></pre>

<h2>Setting up a Library Project</h2>

<pre><code>android create lib-project --name &lt;your_project_name&gt; \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project \
--package &lt;your_library_package_namespace&gt;
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/manifest/manifest-intro.html">The AndroidManifest.xml File Reference</a></p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Updating a library project</h2>

<pre><code>android update lib-project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project
</code></pre>

<h2>Referencing a Library Project</h2>

<pre><code>android update project \
--target &lt;target_ID&gt; \
--path path/to/your/project
--library path/to/library_projectA
</code></pre>

<p>This command updates the application project&#8217;s build properties to include a reference to the library project. Specifically, it adds an android.library.reference.n property to the project&#8217;s project.properties file.</p>

<h2>Declaring library components in the manifest file</h2>

<p>In the manifest file of the application project, you must add declarations of all components that the application will use that are imported from a library project. For example, you must declare any <activity>, <service>, <receiver>, <provider>, and so on, as well as <permission>, <uses-library>, and similar elements.</p>

<p>Building and Running from the Command Line</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-cmdline.html">http://developer.android.com/tools/building/building-cmdline.html</a></p>

<h2>Building in Debug/Release Mode</h2>

<pre><code>ant debug
ant release
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/publishing/app-signing.html">Signing Your Applications</a></p>

<h2>Running on a Device</h2>

<pre><code>adb -d install path/to/your/app.apk
</code></pre>

<p>update installation</p>

<pre><code>adb -d -r install path/to/your/app.apk
</code></pre>

<h1>iOS</h1>

<p>To be able to find the command line, the trick was to watch the system console log while running a “build and archive” through Xcode.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -project myproject1 -target target1


/usr/bin/xcrun -sdk iphoneos PackageApplication -v "${RELEASE_BUILDDIR}/${APPLICATION_NAME}.app" -o "${BUILD_HISTORY_DIR}/${APPLICATION_NAME}.ipa" --sign "${DEVELOPPER_NAME}" --embed "${PROVISONNING_PROFILE}"
</code></pre>

<p>RELEASE_BUILDDIR needs to be an absolute path.</p>

<p>you don&#8217;t need the &#8211;sign or &#8211;embed options if you wish to keep the same signing/profile used when the .app was built.</p>

<p>Note that the ipa file path in -o &#8220;${ipa_path}&#8221; must be an absolute path. Otherwise you will probably get error: Unable to create &#8216;&#8230;/&#8230;ipa&#8217; or it will be silently ignored creating.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -scheme &lt;SchemeName&gt; archive
</code></pre>

<p>Make sure you have selected the correct Xcode release by using xcode-select <path to Xcode.app></p>

<p>to resign a build</p>

<pre><code>codesign -f -vv -s "$DistributionIdentity" "$APPDIR"
</code></pre>

<h2>Other References</h2>

<p><a href="http://nachbaur.com/blog/building-ios-apps-for-over-the-air-adhoc-distribution">Building iOS apps for Over-The-Air AdHoc distribution</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/ghughes/fruitstrap">Fruitstrap</a> is a command line tool that uses the private MobileDevice API to install an iOS application on a physical device over USB. It’s pretty easy to get set up.</p>

<pre><code>xcodebuild -scheme fruitstrap-demo -sdk iphoneos build

fruitstrap build/Debug-iphoneos/fruitstrap-demo.app
</code></pre>

<p>One command to build and install the app on the device.</p>

<pre><code>FRUITSTRAP_CLI=1 xcodebuild -scheme fruitstrap-demo -sdk iphoneos build
</code></pre>

<p><a href="https://github.com/facebook/xctool">xctool</a> is a replacement for Apple&#8217;s xcodebuild that makes it easier to build and test iOS and Mac products. It&#8217;s especially helpful for continuous integration.</p>

<h1>BlackBerry 10</h1>

<p>make -f [configuration]/makefile [target]</p>

<p><a href="http://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/core/com.qnx.doc.ide.userguide/topic/devel_build_from_command_line.html">Build from the command line</a></p>

<pre><code>mkbuild -ws &lt;workspace&gt; [options] 
mkbuild [-project] &lt;full_project_path&gt; [options] 
mkbuild -ws &lt;workspace&gt; -projects &lt;project1,project2&gt; [options]
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/05/building-apps-without-an-ide/">Command Line Rocks! Building BlackBerry 10 Apps Without An IDE</a></p>

<pre><code>qcc -Vgcc_ntoarmv7le main.c -o main
</code></pre>

<p>for simulator</p>

<pre><code>qcc -Vgcc_ntox86 main.c -o main
</code></pre>

<p>bar-descriptor.xml file <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/bb10/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/topic/r_blackberry_tablet_dtd_intro.html#r_blackberry_tablet_dtd_intro">full list of BAR application descriptor parameters</a></p>

<pre><code>&lt;qnx&gt;
  &lt;id&gt;com.example.GoodbyeIDE&lt;/id&gt;
  &lt;versionNumber&gt;1&lt;/versionNumber&gt;
  &lt;name&gt;Goodbye IDE&lt;/name&gt;
  &lt;asset path="main" entry="true"&gt;main&lt;/asset&gt;
&lt;/qnx&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>To create a BAR file: (<a href="https://www.blackberry.com/SignedKeys/codesigning.html">register with RIM to sign applications</a>, <a href="https://developer.blackberry.com/native/documentation/bb10/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/com.qnx.doc.native_sdk.devguide/topic/t_setup_manual_create_debug_token_cmdline.html">create a debug token</a>)</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-nativepackager -package GoodbyeIDE.bar bar-descriptor.xml -devMode -debugToken ~/Library/Research\ In\ Motion/debugtoken1.bar
</code></pre>

<p>Deploy</p>

<pre><code>blackberry-deploy -installApp 169.254.0.1 -password pass GoodbyeIDE.bar
</code></pre>

<h2>View logs over SSH</h2>

<pre><code>blackberry-connect 169.254.0.1 -password pass
</code></pre>

<p>open another console and run</p>

<pre><code>ssh devuser@169.254.0.1
</code></pre>

<p>run command</p>

<pre><code>slog2info -w
</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/05/command-line-rocks-part-2/">Command Line Rocks! Part 2 – Adding Multiple Source Files and Libraries</a></p>

<p><a href="http://devblog.blackberry.com/2013/08/command-line-rocks-part-3-make-and-makefiles/">Command Line Rocks! Part 3 – Make and Makefiles</a></p>

<h1>Windows Phone 8</h1>

<p>The output of the build process includes a file with the .XAP extension. The XAP file is a zipped package that contains all the files required by your app. It’s the XAP file that you deploy to the emulator or to a phone, and that you publish to Windows Phone Store.</p>

<pre><code>devenv NameOfSolution /Rebuild "Release|Mixed Platforms"

MSBuild MyProject.csproj /p:OutDir=d:\builds\mindon-projs\
</code></pre>

<p>You can override the project-specific folder behavior by specifying.</p>

<p>/p:GenerateProjectSpecificOutputFolder=false</p>

<pre><code>MSBuild.exe MyProject/project.jsproj /p:Configuration=Release /t:Build /m
</code></pre>

<h2>MSBuild Command-Line Reference</h2>

<p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms164311.aspx">http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms164311.aspx</a></p>

<p><a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windowsphone/develop/jj681686.aspx">How to sign a company app by using XapSignTool</a></p>

<pre><code>set path=%path%;"%ProgramFiles(x86)%\Microsoft SDKs\Windows Phone\v8.0\Tools\XapSignTool"

XapSignTool.exe sign /f PFXFile /p Password XAP
</code></pre>

<p><a href="https://github.com/AndreasOM/wp8-directx-commandline">Simple Windows Phone 8 (C++/native only) DirectX project with Command Line Build</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
