<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-03T14:45:54+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Really Can Catch Lightning in a Bottle]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/you-really-can-catch-lightning-in-a-bottle/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T14:41:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/you-really-can-catch-lightning-in-a-bottle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>一群材料学家发现，从工业玻璃中抽出极细的一根玻璃丝，可以用来储藏和释放惊人的电量。</p>

<p>这事听起来有点荒诞，但其结果经过证明，确是千真万确。一群材料学家发现，从工业玻璃中抽出极细的一根玻璃丝，可以用来储藏和释放惊人的电量。把玻璃丝夹在两块金属板之间用作为电容器的一部分，该玻璃丝可为像心脏震颤器等设备提供大量的能量，甚至可以为新一代电动汽车提供能量。</p>

<p>【译言网】全文: <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/289907/255207">捕捉瓶中闪电</a></p>

<p>Here&#8217;s something that sounds preposterous but as it turns out, it&#8217;s actually true. Take a very thinly drawn piece of industrial glass, and you can use it to store and release a surprising amount of electricity, a group of materials scientists has found. When sandwiched between two metal plates as part of a device called a capacitor, the glass slivers could provide large bursts of energy for devices such as heart defibrillators, and they could even help power the next generation of electric vehicles.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Usually a rectangular plate of material, capacitors are essential to electronics because they can perform tasks that batteries can&#8217;t. Each contains a material called a dielectric, which can store electrical energy and then release it in a large burst. Capacitors are much faster than batteries at charging and releasing electricity, which makes them ideal for providing the pulses of power required by camera flashes and diesel engine starters. They can also endure millions of cycles of charging and discharging, compared to mere thousands of cycles for conventional rechargeable batteries.</p>

<p>To meet the power demands of modern devices, researchers have been looking for materials that can store more and more electricity. That&#8217;s where the use of industrial glass comes in. Industrial glass is stronger and more durable than the glass in household windowpanes and mirrors, and it&#8217;s more resistant to repeated chemical reactions. Materials scientists at Pennsylvania State University, University Park, have now found that an extremely thin piece of the industrial glass called barium boroaluminosilicate&#8211;which is used in flat-panel TV displays&#8211;can hold more than twice as much electrical charge as polypropylene, which is currently the most common material for high-energy capacitors.</p>

<p>Reporting online this week in Materials Letters, the researchers say they used samples of the glass about 50 micrometers thick, or about half the diameter of a human hair, which they etched in acid until the samples eroded to a thickness of only 10 to 20 micrometers. Then they hooked the samples to two electrodes and applied an increasing voltage to test the material&#8217;s breakdown strength: its ability to withstand electrical energy. When the material reached this breakdown limit&#8211;at about 22,000 volts&#8211;the stored energy was released in what resembles &#8220;a lightning bolt conducting through air,&#8221; says co-author Nicholas Smith.</p>

<p>The ability of the glass to hold so much charge renders it &#8220;of prime interest to people who make capacitors and other energy storage devices,&#8221; Smith says. He adds that the low cost of the material adds to its attractiveness, because researchers have been looking mainly at materials, such as specialty polymers and nanocomposites, that tend to be more expensive.</p>

<p>This could be a breakthrough, says chemical engineer Richard Wool of the University of Delaware, Newark. Wool, who specializes in the chemistry of glass, says the ability of the material to combine high energy storage and high breakdown strength, as well as its low cost, gives it an advantage over currently used materials.</p>

<p>Orignal form <strong>Science Magazine</strong> <a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2009/05/05-02.html">You Really Can Catch Lightning in a Bottle</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty and the Beast: <span>The rare moment a tornado and a rainbow come head to head in Colorado sky</span>]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/beauty-and-the-beast-the-rare-moment-a-tornado-and-a-rainbow-come-head-to-head-in-colorado-sky/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T14:06:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/beauty-and-the-beast-the-rare-moment-a-tornado-and-a-rainbow-come-head-to-head-in-colorado-sky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这是一个罕见的瞬间：一条美丽的彩虹和猛烈的暴风云的短兵相接在天空中创造了一副绚丽的景象。</p>

<p>当巨大的龙卷风开始覆盖美国科罗拉多州上方的天空时，人们大部分都已经关好了门窗。</p>

<p>但是当龙卷风的威胁变小时，一群幸运的风暴追逐着们看到了罕见的一幕：一条彩虹看上去似乎和龙卷风仅仅相隔了几英里。</p>

<p>【译言网】全文: <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/281379/254395">美女与野兽：美国科罗拉多州天空的罕见瞬间——龙卷风与彩虹的短兵相接</a></p>

<p>This is the rare moment a beautiful rainbow and violent storm cloud came head to head creating a stunning scene high in the sky.
As the monster tornado began to dominate the skies over Colorado, USA, most people would have been locking their doors and windows.
But as the threat diminished one lucky group of storm chasers saw the rare sight of a rainbow and tornado seemingly just a few miles apart.</p>

<p><img src="http://mindon.github.com/law-ms/tornado-rainbow.jpg" alt="Tornado and Rainbow " />
Rare sight: As the monster tornado began to dominate the skies over Colorado, USA, most people would have been locking their doors and windows, but one lucky group of storm chasers saw the rare sight of a rainbow and tornado</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The magnificent moment was captured by dedicated Dutch storm chaser Peter Gude, 47, who couldn&#8217;t believe his eyes as he spotted the unusual scene.</p>

<p>With the month of March looming, United States tornado chasers are already watching the Southeast as a nasty storm brews with the potential to spin off a batch of tornadoes.</p>

<p>But if funnel clouds develop Thursday or Friday as some forecasters believe, they won&#8217;t be the first.</p>

<p>This tornado season got an early and deadly start in late January when two people were killed by separate twisters in Alabama.</p>

<p>Preliminary reports showed 95 tornadoes struck last month, compared with 16 in January during a particularly stormy 2011.</p>

<p>The season usually starts in March and then ramps up for the next couple of months, but forecasting these storm seasons is even more imprecise than predicting hurricane seasons.</p>

<p>Tornadoes are too small and too short-lived for scientists to make seasonal predictions.</p>

<p>They don&#8217;t develop like blizzards and hurricanes, which are easier to project.</p>

<p>They pop in and pop out. The storms that give them birth may last only a few hours. Hurricanes and blizzards are lumbering beasts that spend days moving across the satellite maps.</p>

<p>When a hurricane approaches, coastlines get days warning to evacuate.</p>

<p>With a tornado, if the weather service can let people know 20 minutes in advance, it&#8217;s considered a victory.</p>

<p>&#8216;The Joplin (Missouri) tornado (that killed 158 people last May) wasn&#8217;t violent until just about the time it got to the hospital,&#8221; said Harold Brooks, a research scientist at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&#8217;s National Severe Storms Laboratory, in Norman, Oklahoma.</p>

<p>&#8216;Even when you&#8217;re in the field, there are still times when you&#8217;re surprised by the intensity of the event and how quickly it started.&#8217;</p>

<p>If a forecast for a hurricane or blizzard is off by a mile, it&#8217;s still bad weather. But a mile difference means no damage in a tornado, Brooks said: &#8216;It&#8217;s so much finer in time and space on the tornado, it does make it a harder problem.&#8217;</p>

<p>It takes a piece of debris only a few seconds to fly around an entire tornado; it takes hours to circle a hurricane. But tornadoes, though smaller, can have stronger winds.</p>

<p>Since 1950, there have been 58 tornadoes in the U.S. with winds exceeding 200 mph; six last year alone. Only three hurricanes have made U.S. landfall with winds more than 155 mph.</p>

<p>Original from <strong>MailOnline</strong> <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/sciencetech/article-2105422/Beauty-Beast-The-moment-twister-rainbow-battle-space-sky.html">Beauty and the Beast: The rare moment a tornado and a rainbow come head to head in Colorado sky</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why China Will Have an Economic Crisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/why-china-will-have-an-economic-crisis/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T13:23:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/why-china-will-have-an-economic-crisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p>投资过剩，房产泡沫，政府负债，银行坏账。 昌盛的国家各有各的繁华，而危机笼罩下的国家，却都是相似的。 都是些老生常谈，争来争去逃不出了钱字。 作者虽非经济学专业人士，但也详尽阐述了一个西方人对于中国经济的看法。
【译言网】全文: <a href="http://select.yeeyan.org/view/205314/255491">时代周刊：为什么中国将发生经济危机</a></p>

<p>The view in most of the world is that China is indestructible. Shrugging off the crises multiplying elsewhere, China seems to surge from strength to strength, its spectacular growth marching on no matter what headwinds may come. It appears inevitable that China will overtake a U.S. mired in debt and division to become the world’s indispensable economy. Those businessmen and policymakers looking to the future believe China’s “state capitalism” may be a superior form of economic organization in dealing with the challenges of the modern global economy.</p>

<p>My answer to all of this is: think again.</p>

<p>I don’t doubt for a second that China will be a major economic superpower with an increasingly influential role in the global economy. In many respects, it already is a superpower. But that doesn’t mean the economy is free from problems, a good number of them created by the very statist system lauded by pundits in the U.S. and Europe. And in my opinion, if China doesn’t change course, and in a big way, the country will experience an economic crisis.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I’ve been thinking about China’s economic future, and the likelihood it will face some sort of terrible collapse, for some time, but I have until now been reluctant to come out with my views so strongly. The reason is that it is very difficult to tell what’s really going on in the Chinese economy. Data is sparse or unreliable. And China is in certain ways unique in economic terms — has history ever witnessed a giant of such massive proportions ascend so quickly in the global economy? Valid precedents are hard to find. Then there is the issue of timing. It is easy to say China will have a crisis; it is almost impossible to say when that might happen. Next month? Next year? Next decade? The fact is China could continue as it is for some time to come. So, in other words, when you make the type of prediction I just have, you have a good chance of getting it just plain wrong.</p>

<p>But the more time I spend in China, the more convinced I am that its current economic system is unsustainable. Yes, economists who specialize in China can give you all sorts of reasons why the country is supposedly different, and thus the regular rules of economics don’t necessarily apply. But one simple thing I always say about economics is that you can’t escape math. If the numbers don’t add up, it doesn’t matter much how big your economy might be or how fast it is growing or how heavy a role the state might play. And China has lots of numbers that just don’t add up.</p>

<p>A big part of the bad math is created by China’s state capitalism. China has adopted a form of the Asian development model, invented by Japan and followed, to varying degrees, by many rapid-growth countries around East Asia. The model, very generally speaking, functions like this: 1) capitalize on low wages to spark growth through exports and industrialize quickly with hefty amounts of investment, 2) guide the whole process with the hand of the state, 3) employ industrial policies and state-directed finance to progress into more and more advanced sectors. This system generates fantastic levels of economic growth for a while, but then eventually, it crashes. Japan had its meltdown beginning in 1990 (and it hasn’t escaped two decades later); South Korea, the country that copied Japan’s model most closely, experienced its crisis in 1997-98.</p>

<p>What happens? The model is based on what Alice Amsden, in her study of the Korean economy, called “getting prices wrong.” To spur on the high levels of investment necessary to generate rapid growth, the model depends on state-directed subsidization to make investing in certain industries or sectors more attractive and less risky than it otherwise would be. Cheap credit is made available for industry, or the state outright orders money to be invested in certain preferred projects. The exchange rate is controlled to encourage exporters. All sorts of subsidies, for energy, exports and so on, are dished out. Banks are not commercially oriented but act to a great degree as tools of government-development policy. All of these methods funnel money, private and public, into industrialization, creating the astronomical growth rates we see again and again in Asia.</p>

<p>The problem here is that prices can’t stay wrong indefinitely. There is a good reason why classical economists are always so focused on allowing markets to find the correct price level. In that way, markets send the proper signals to potential investors on where money should or should not go. If those price indicators are skewed, so is the direction of resources. The Asian model, by playing around with prices, eventually creates tremendous distortions, in which money is wasted and excess capacity is generated. Subsidized companies don’t have to generate returns in the same way as unsubsidized firms, and that leads them to make bad investment decisions to build factories and buildings that are unnecessary and unprofitable. As a result, loans go bad and banking sectors buckle. That’s exactly what happened in both Japan and Korea. Though their crises were tipped off in very different ways — the bursting of an asset bubble in Japan, an external shock in Korea — the reason both countries collapsed was the same: weak banks, indebted companies, silly investments.</p>

<p>China is indulging in all of the same excesses as Japan and Korea, and then some. The level of investment in China, at nearly 50% of GDP, is lofty even by Asian standards. The usual argument made in defense of such astronomical investment in fixed assets is that China is a large developing country that needs all of the buildings and roads it is constructing. Qu Hongbin, the very smart chief China economist at HSBC, made that very argument in a recent study:</p>

<blockquote><p>There is a popular view in the market that China has overinvested and therefore can no longer rely on investment to sustain its growth. We disagree. China’s investment-to-GDP ratio is indeed very high (46%) … [But] China is only half way through the process of urbanisation and industrialisation. It still needs to invest more to cope with the rising demand for rail, hospitals and industrial plants. The recent infrastructure boom has boosted the country’s transport capacity, but China’s railway network is still shorter than that of the US in 1880 … In economic terms, we estimate that China’s capital stock per worker is only about 8% of that of the US and 15% of that of Korea. In other words, China’s capital accumulation is still far from reaching the stage of having diminishing returns; we believe the country needs to invest more, rather than less.</p></blockquote>

<p>I completely agree. Yet the issue is not whether China needs more investment. The issue is whether China is getting the types of investment it requires. The fact that investment levels can be so high and yet the economy is so deficient in certain key aspects makes me think the answer is no. We can see that in the continued problem of excess capacity in China, in which companies go hog wild building too many factories in certain industries, often with borrowing from state banks. That has happened in steel and solar panels, for example. The country is investing hundreds of billions in high-speed railways even though ticket prices are beyond the reach of most Chinese, while many major Chinese cities don’t have subways.</p>

<p>A good part of this misdirected investment seems to be headed into the property sector. Real estate development has become the key driving force of Chinese economic growth. In theory, China’s very rapid urbanization makes such construction a necessity — but that depends on what is being built. In Wenzhou, a real estate agent recently offered free BMWs to anyone who bought a high-end apartment — a clear sign of overbuilding — while there is an obvious shortage of housing affordable for most Chinese. On either side of my Beijing apartment building are three big malls that hardly ever seem to see real shoppers. Rents for top-quality office space in Beijing are now pricier than in New York City — despite the fact that China’s capital is one big construction zone. Many of the buildings going up are of a quality unsuitable for major corporations.</p>

<p>Even worse, much of the investment in China is being financed with debt. The level of debt in the Chinese economy has been rising with frightening speed. Rating agency Fitch estimates bank credit in 2011 was equivalent to 185% of the country’s GDP — an increase of 56 percentage points in a mere three years. Though that surge has not yet had a significant negative impact on China’s banks, many analysts fret that banks will eventually experience a rise in nonperforming loans. In an indication of what is to come, the Financial Times reported recently that the government has ordered banks to roll over the $1.7 trillion of loans owed by local governments. If true, this tells us two key things: 1) these governments invested money raised from banks in projects that are not generating the returns necessary to pay them back and 2) the quality of loans on the banks’ books are more questionable than official statistics suggest. On top of that, the fact that local governments amassed so much debt in the first place shows a complete lack of rule of law in China’s financial sector. Technically, local governments aren’t permitted to borrow money at all. Meanwhile, as government entities run up loans they can’t pay, many small companies, especially private ones, are unable to raise sufficient funds and remain starved of capital.</p>

<p>So we can see the pieces of a crisis falling into place: excessive, misguided investment, including a giant property boom, propelled on by debt and the decisions of government bureaucrats. Sound familiar? A crisis, of course, is not inevitable — if China’s leadership takes action and reorients the direction of the economy. The positive thing is that at least some top policymakers understand the need to change. In policy pronouncement after policy pronouncement, the government pledges to reform. The problem is that China’s government is not taking its own advice. The economy needs to rebalance away from investment and exports to a more consumption-driven growth model with a primary focus on quality of growth, not high rates at any cost. That’s not happening, or not happening quickly enough. Yes, the Chinese consumer is gaining in global importance, but savings in China remains too high and consumption as a percentage of GDP still way too low. Steps that the government could take to spur on the needed rebalancing — reducing lofty taxes on many imported goods, for example — are nowhere to be found. More importantly, the government is doing nothing to set prices right. The currency remains firmly controlled, interest rates unreformed. So investors within China are still acting based on the wrong price signals.</p>

<p>Why won’t China’s policymakers pursue more fundamental reform? They are afraid that growth might slip. Sure, the latest five-year plan targets 7% annual GDP growth, but it seems to me that every time growth drops under double digits, the leadership goes into panic mode and revs up the economy again. GDP surged 8.9% in the fourth quarter of 2011, but that’s not fast enough for China’s leaders. They’ve already started loosening credit again — slathering yet more debt onto the economy.</p>

<p>When I bring up these issues with China watchers, I’m usually scolded — Beijing’s policy mandarins have it all figured out, I’m informed. It is true that China’s policymakers have done a superior job managing the rapidly changing economy in recent years. But as any stock investor knows all too well, past performance does not ensure future performance. Back in the 1970s and ’80s, analysts in the West considered Japan’s bureaucrats near supermen as well. Now the stodgy Japanese bureaucracy is considered one of the main impediments to an economic revival. Chinese bureaucrats today suffer from the same problem that led Japanese bureaucrats astray — they believe the economy can be managed by fiat. The tools of classical economics — getting prices right — are secondary. Why guide an economy with abstract measures like interest rates when you can just tell the banks what to do?</p>

<p>That attitude is what killed Japan’s economic miracle, and now I see China slipping toward the same fate. Japan could not escape the forces of basic mathematics. China can’t either, no matter how brilliant its policymakers might be. When would a meltdown happen? It is interesting to play with a bit of history. Both Japan and Korea suffered their crises roughly 35 years after the Asian development model was switched on — the early 1950s to ’89 in Japan, and 1962 to ’97 in Korea. That puts a China crisis at around 2014-15 or so. I’m not predicting a firm date here. What I am saying is that China is running out of time to fix the problems of its economy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[穴位按摩方法(Acupressure)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/02/acupressure-hands-tech/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-02T22:07:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/02/acupressure-hands-tech</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>穴位按摩有多种方法．常用的有按、拿、推、揉等，并不是每个身体部位适合所有的方法，需要根据病症不同，选择相应的刺激方法。</p>

<h2>掌平推法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：手掌在身体部位上做直线单方向移动。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：力道缓和，接触身体面积大，慢慢平推，使手掌的热度传至皮肤。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：行气活血，多用于治疗腰腿痛，肩背痛，颈椎病，胸腹胀痛等症。</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>指按法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：用指腹由轻到重，逐渐用力按压在被按摩的穴位上。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：适合全身各处的穴位，有通经活络，放松肌肉的作用。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：用食指按压，中指叠放在食指上，这样中指起到了很好的固定作用。</p>

<h2>四指摩法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：四指并拢，用指腹在相应的部位上，有规律地来回摩动。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：提高皮肤温度，加速血液循环，散淤消肿，调理脾胃，理气和中。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：摩法非常轻柔，在按摩开始和结束的时候采用，让人感受不到压力，放松心情。</p>

<h2>指揉法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：手指指腹在局部皮肤做轻柔和缓的回旋揉动。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：可增强肌肉和真皮组织的弹性，并具有活血散淤，缓解痉挛，减轻疼痛的作用。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：按揉穴位时，应略感到疼痛，这样是深压缓揉，保健效果会更好。</p>

<h2>拿捏法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：手掌和手指挤压身体部位。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：减少皮下脂肪，振奋精神，疏通经络，祛风散寒。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：双手深抓肉，像拧毛巾一样向两个方向用力，此法有减少皮下脂肪的作用。</p>

<h2>扣打法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：两手自然并拢，在按摩部位上轻轻拍打。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：促进气血运行，消除疲劳和调节神经肌肉兴奋性。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：轻拍是腕关节带动手掌拍打，重拍是以肘关节带动，不要用力过大。</p>

<h2>抖法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：双手或单手握住肢体末端，微微用力连续做小幅度的上下抖动。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：抖法能够很好地放松疲劳的肌肉，灵活僵硬的关节。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：肢体抖动时如波浪一样，由末端逐步传到身体中心。</p>

<h2>指叩法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：指尖、拳背、掌侧小鱼际击打一定部位。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：疏通经络，活血化淤，安神醒脑。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：除了用手指叩击，还可以借用一些工具如按摩棒等，击打手无法触及的部位。</p>

<h2>拳击法</h2>

<p><strong>方法</strong>：双手自然握拳，利用手腕的力量击打身体部位。</p>

<p><strong>功效</strong>：促进血液循环，镇定神经。</p>

<p><strong>小技巧</strong>：击打疼痛部位时，力度要适中，但击打松弛的肌肉时就要增加力度了。</p>

<div id="google_translate_element"></div>


<script>
function googleTranslateElementInit() {
  new google.translate.TranslateElement({
    pageLanguage: 'zh-CN',
    gaTrack: true,
    gaId: 'UA-28048168-2',
    layout: google.translate.TranslateElement.InlineLayout.SIMPLE
  }, 'google_translate_element');
}

(function() {
  var job = document.createElement('script'); job.type = 'text/javascript'; job.async = true;
  job.src = 'http://translate.google.com/translate_a/element.js?cb=googleTranslateElementInit';
  var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(job, s);
})();
</script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Allie Narrations in 《Taken》]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/allie-narrations-in-taken/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-01T22:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/01/allie-narrations-in-taken</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>M</strong>y mother always talked to me a lot about the sky. She liked to watch the clouds in the day and the stars at night&#8230;especially the stars. We would play a game sometimes; a game called &#8220;What&#8217;s Beyond the Sky?&#8221; We would imagine darkness or a blinding light or something else that we didn&#8217;t know how to name. But of course, that was just a game. There&#8217;s nothing beyond the sky. The sky just is, and it goes on and on, and we play all of our games beneath it.</p>

<p><strong>P</strong>eople are lonely in this world for lots of different reasons. Some people have something in their disposition. Maybe they were just born too mean, or maybe they were born too tender. But most people are brought to where they are by circumstance, by calamity or a broken heart or something else happening in their lives that wasn&#8217;t anything they planned on. People are lonely in this world for lots of different reasons. The one thing that I do know is, it doesn&#8217;t matter what any one of them might tell you&#8211;nobody wants to be alone.</p>

<p><strong>S</strong>ome people have given up all hope of anything in their lives every changing. They just go on with it day by day, and if something were to come along and make things different they probably wouldn&#8217;t even notice it right off, except for that kind of nervous feeling you get in your stomach. My mom and I used to call that &#8220;the car trip feeling&#8221;, because it was how I&#8217;d feel whenever I knew we were going to go somewhere far away or something new.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>T</strong>hat summer, a lot of things had happened that people couldn&#8217;t explain. There had been lights in the sky and stories in the paper about saucers crashing. John had come, and then he had gone. For a while, life went back to being life, and almost everyone forgot the things that that summer had brought with it from out of the sky.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>hen you&#8217;re a kid, all you ever want is for the stories your mom reads you to be true. You think you can crawl inside the world that&#8217;s in every book and live in the pictures on every page, but deep down you know that this isn&#8217;t something that could ever happen. And it&#8217;s knowing that the magic isn&#8217;t quite there, that it&#8217;s just over the next hill or maybe in the next story, that makes you feel safe in your bed at night. You really wouldn&#8217;t want it to be any other way.</p>

<p><strong>T</strong>here are times when it seems like the whole world is afraid&#8230;when the fear is something you have to live with day in day out. When people get scared, they do a lot of different things. They fight, or they run, they destroy the thing they&#8217;re afraid of, or they put a lot of distance between it and them&#8230;make it something you can shoot at with a friction-action gun.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>y father liked to say that there were these things in life that didn&#8217;t make any sense, and they could never make any sense, and if you were anywhere near smart, you knew that. But your job was not to give up, to keep on trying to make sense out of them anyway, trying to understand things that could never be understood. I guess maybe people will always find different names for their answers, but the one thing is, their questions will always be the same.</p>

<p><strong>C</strong>hristmas is all about hope. Kids hope for new toys. You get older, and the toys get bigger, but the hope stays the same. Some people might hope for peace on Earth or maybe for a better tomorrow, whatever their idea of that might be, but most people still just want something bright and shiny and new.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>hy do people want so desperately not to be alone? Why is it more comforting to think you are being watched than to know that no one at all is watching? And why, really, does that make us any less alone? In the end, if there are others out there, then wouldn&#8217;t we be, all of us, still alone together?</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>hen you&#8217;re little, you like to think you know everything, but the last thing you really want is to know too much. What you really want is for grownups to make the world a safe place where dreams can come true and promises are never broken. And when you&#8217;re little, it doesn&#8217;t seem like a lot to ask.</p>

<p><strong>P</strong>eople believe what they want to believe. They find meaning where they can, and they cling to it. In the end, it really doesn&#8217;t matter what&#8217;s a trick and what&#8217;s true. What matters is that people believe.</p>

<p><strong>P</strong>eople like to examine the things that frighten them, to look at them and give them names, so saints look for God, and scientists look for evidence. They&#8217;re both just trying to take away the mystery, to take away the fear.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>e all like to think that we have some control over the events in our lives, and a lot of the time we can fool ourselves into thinking that we really are in charge. But then something happens to remind us that the world runs by its own rules and not ours and that we&#8217;re just along for the ride.</p>

<p><strong>Y</strong>ou know in cartoons, the way someone can run off a cliff and they&#8217;re fine, they don&#8217;t fall until they look down? My mom always said that was the secret of life. Never look down. But it&#8217;s more than that. It&#8217;s not just about not looking. It&#8217;s about not ever realizing that you&#8217;re in the middle of the air and you don&#8217;t know how to fly.</p>

<p><strong>T</strong>he world is made up of the big things that happen and the small ones. And the part that&#8217;s so unfair is that we call them &#8220;big&#8221; and &#8220;small,&#8221; because when something happens to you, when you lose something or someone that you really care about, that&#8217;s all there is. The world may be blowing up around you, but you don&#8217;t care about that. You don&#8217;t care about that at all.</p>

<p><strong>I</strong> have this idea about why people do the terrible things they do. Same reason little kids push each other on the schoolyard. If you&#8217;re the one doing the pushing, then you&#8217;re not going to be the one who gets pushed. If you&#8217;re the monster, then nothing will be waiting in the shadows to jump out at you. It&#8217;s pretty simple, really. People do the terrible things they do because they&#8217;re sacred.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>e&#8217;re all standing on the edge of a cliff, all the time, every day, a cliff we&#8217;re all going over. Our choice isn&#8217;t about that. Our choice is about whether we want to go kicking and screaming or whether we might want to open our eyes and our hearts to what happens once we start to fall.</p>

<p><strong>W</strong>hat makes us human? That we can think? That we can feel sorrow and pain? Maybe. That we can laugh? I hope so. We can hurt and we can laugh, and we know a past and a present, and in some ways a future. Maybe what makes us human is that we know just enough to think and know where we&#8217;re going.&#8221;</p>

<p><strong>I</strong> asked my dad once about his dad, my grandfather. I knew he&#8217;d had some hard times, but I didn&#8217;t know a lot more than that. I said to my dad &#8216;I guess maybe he was kind of lost&#8217;. &#8216;Not lost, really,&#8221; my dad said, &#8216;but for a while, he was definitely bewildered.</p>

<p><strong>I</strong> remember my mom telling me that she only went to church once, with her mother on Easter Sunday. When the minister said that the Kingdom of Heaven was within her, that scared her half to death. It meant it was all up to her. People want the comfort of strong arms. They look to the voices in their heads. To drugs. They look to the sky.</p>

<p>ever played tig tag toe with a chicken -Chad</p>

<div style="float:right">
<script type="text/javascript"><!--
google_ad_client = "ca-pub-6997921015773263";
/* git-post-body2 */
google_ad_slot = "9585845910";
google_ad_width = 468;
google_ad_height = 60;
//-->
</script>
<script type="text/javascript"
src="http://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/show_ads.js">
</script>
</div>


<p><strong>W</strong>hen I was very little, my mother would read nursery rhymes to me. I always hated &#8220;Humpty Dumpty.&#8221; That&#8217;s a very scary poem. No one knows how to put it back together again—not all the king&#8217;s horses or all the king&#8217;s men. No one wants to think that there&#8217;s anything in the world that could fall apart that badly, but of course&#8230;anything can. I guess that&#8217;s what&#8217;s so scary about &#8220;Humpty Dumpty.&#8221;</p>

<p><strong>I</strong> had done what I could. I tried to make the soldiers think that their plan to use me as bait hadn&#8217;t worked, that I had been taken away. I thought that if I could make them believe that I was gone, then they wouldn&#8217;t bother me anymore and I could go back to who I used to be. But too much had happened to all us by then for anything to go back to how it was.</p>

<p><strong>P</strong>eople talk a lot as if the most important thing in life is to always see things for what they really are. But everything we do, every plan we make is kind of a lie. We&#8217;re closing our eyes and pretending the day won&#8217;t ever come when we won&#8217;t need to make any more plans. Hope is the biggest lie there is, and it is the best. You have to keep going as if it all mattered, or else we wouldn&#8217;t keep going at all.</p>

<p><strong>H</strong>ow do you let someone go? How do you understand that that&#8217;s alright, that everything changes? How do you find a way for that to make you feel good about life instead of breaking your heart? The hardest thing you&#8217;ll ever learn is how to say good-bye.</p>

<p><strong>T</strong>hey will be coming soon, coming to try to stop what was going to happen next. But maybe they could be stopped. Maybe something could happen that would make it hard for them to do what they wanted to do.</p>

<p><strong>I</strong> don&#8217;t know what will happen next. I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to be, what I&#8217;m going to learn, but what I do know is this—life, all life, is about asking questions, not about knowing answers. It is wanting to see what&#8217;s over the next hill that keeps us all going. We have to keep asking questions, wanting to understand. Even when we know we&#8217;ll never find the answers, we have to keep on asking the questions.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>y mother always talked to me a lot about the sky. She liked to watch the clouds in the day and the stars at night&#8230;especially the stars. We would play a game sometimes, a game called &#8220;What&#8217;s Beyond the Sky?&#8221; We would imagine darkness or a blinding light or something else that we didn&#8217;t know how to name. But of course, that was just a game. There&#8217;s nothing beyond the sky. The sky just is, and it goes on and on, and we play all of our games beneath it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GoAgent -- Make your own fast proxy with GAE]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/goagent-make-your-own-fast-proxy-with-gae/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T23:44:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/goagent-make-your-own-fast-proxy-with-gae</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在这个神奇的国家里，有很过好东西被阻止了，很多烂东西倒是放进来了。不想自己的大脑成为次品，还是要多学习新知识的，那就缺少不了Proxy这东西。</p>

<p>GoAgent 确实是个不错的东西，之前用过LocalProxy，总有些奇怪的原因导致不能用。最近在同事的微博看到了GoAgent，搭了一下，速度还真不错 :D</p>

<!--more-->


<p>我是装有GAE SDK的，自行上传App的，没有使用 GoAgent 提供的 uploader.bat。
这里简单记录一下用GAE（Google App Engine）搭建GoAgent Proxy的要点：
（最权威的指南还是去 <a href="http://code.google.com/p/goagent/">http://code.google.com/p/goagent/</a> 看最好了:p ）</p>

<ol>
<li>要装有Python2.7</li>
<li>GAE里建的APP要是新的才会支持 High Replication Datastore</li>
<li>设置 app.yaml 里的 appid</li>
</ol>


<p>配合 Chrome 的插件 <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/dpplabbmogkhghncfbfdeeokoefdjegm">Proxy SwitchySharp</a> 效果相当好，推荐！</p>

<p>最新GoAgent Snapshot 网址 <a href="http://repo.or.cz/w/goagent.git/">http://repo.or.cz/w/goagent.git/</a></p>

<div id="google_translate_element"></div>


<script>
function googleTranslateElementInit() {
  new google.translate.TranslateElement({
    pageLanguage: 'zh-CN',
    gaTrack: true,
    gaId: 'UA-28048168-2',
    layout: google.translate.TranslateElement.InlineLayout.SIMPLE
  }, 'google_translate_element');
}

(function() {
  var job = document.createElement('script'); job.type = 'text/javascript'; job.async = true;
  job.src = 'http://translate.google.com/translate_a/element.js?cb=googleTranslateElementInit';
  var s = document.getElementsByTagName('script')[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(job, s);
})();
</script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web-Drawing Throwdown: Paper.js Vs. Processing.js Vs. Raphael]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-dot-js-vs-processing-dot-js-vs-raphael/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T23:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-dot-js-vs-processing-dot-js-vs-raphael</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before drawing anything in a browser, ask yourself three questions:</p>

<h2>Do you need to support older browsers?</h2>

<p>If the answer is yes, then your only choice is Raphaël. It handles browsers all the way back to IE 7 and Firefox 3. Raphaël even has some support for IE 6, although some of its underlying technology cannot be implemented there.</p>

<h2>Do you need to support Android?</h2>

<p>Android doesn’t support SVG, so you’ll have to use Paper.js or Processing.js. Some rumors say that Android 4 will handle SVG, but the majority of Android devices won’t support it for years.</p>

<h2>Is your drawing interactive?</h2>

<p>Raphaël and Paper.js focus on interaction with drawn elements through clicking, dragging and touch. Processing.js doesn’t support any object-level events, so responding to user gestures is very difficult. Processing.js can draw a cool animation on your home page, but the other tools are better for interactive applications.</p>

<p>Paper.js, Processing.js and Raphaël are the leading libraries for drawing on the Web right now. A couple of others are up and coming, and you can always use Flash, but these three work well with HTML5 and have the widest support among browser vendors.</p>

<p>Choosing the right framework will determine the success of your project. This article covers the advantages and disadvantages of each, and the information you need to make the best choice.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>All of the code in this article is open source and can be run on the demo page that accompanies this article.</p>

<p>[Note: Have you already pre-ordered your copy of our Printed Smashing Book #3? The book is a professional guide on how to redesign websites and it also introduces a whole new mindset for progressive Web design, written by experts in the industry for you. Pre-order now and add your name into the book!]</p>

<h2>Overview</h2>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th> </th>
<th align="center"> Paper.js </th>
<th align="center"> Processing.js </th>
<th align="center"> Raphaël.js</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Technology </td>
<td align="center"> canvas tag </td>
<td align="center"> canvas tag </td>
<td align="center"> SVG</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Language </td>
<td align="center"> PaperScript </td>
<td align="center"> Processing script </td>
<td align="center"> JavaScript</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Browsers </td>
<td align="center"> IE 9 </td>
<td align="center"> IE 9 </td>
<td align="center"> IE 7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mobile </td>
<td align="center"> Yes </td>
<td align="center"> Yes </td>
<td align="center"> iOS only</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Model </td>
<td align="center"> Vector and raster </td>
<td align="center"> Raster </td>
<td align="center"> Vector</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Size </td>
<td align="center"> 56 KB </td>
<td align="center"> 64 KB </td>
<td align="center"> 20 KB</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<p>It’s all JavaScript once the page runs, but the frameworks take different paths to get there. Raphaël is written directly in JavaScript, but Paper.js uses PaperScript, and Processing.js uses its own script. They all support Firefox, Chrome and Safari, but Internet Explorer is an issue — Paper.js and Processing.js use the canvas tag and thus require IE 9.</p>

<div style="float:right">
<script type="text/javascript"><!--
google_ad_client = "ca-pub-6997921015773263";
/* git-post-body2 */
google_ad_slot = "9585845910";
google_ad_width = 468;
google_ad_height = 60;
//-->
</script>
<script type="text/javascript"
src="http://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/show_ads.js">
</script>
</div>


<p>PaperScript is a JavaScript extension that makes it possible to write scripts that don’t pollute the global namespace. This cuts down on JavaScript conflicts. PaperScript also supports direct math on objects such as Point and Size: you can add two points together as if they were numbers.</p>

<p>Processing.js is based on a framework named Processing, which runs in the Java Virtual Machine. You define int and float instead of var, and you can use classes with Java-style inheritance. While the Processing.js script looks a little like Java, it’s more like JavaScript and doesn’t require many of the more complex features of Java.
Using all three libraries is easy if you have some familiarity with JavaScript.</p>

<p>Full article could be found from <em>Zack Grossbart</em>&#8217;s <a href="http://coding.smashingmagazine.com/2012/02/22/web-drawing-throwdown-paper-processing-raphael/">Web-Drawing Throwdown: Paper.js Vs. Processing.js Vs. Raphael</a></p>

<p>with demos <a href="http://zgrossbart.github.com/3gears/">http://zgrossbart.github.com/3gears/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 Things You Didn't Know About... Magnetism]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-dot-dot-dot-magnetism/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-24T13:37:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/24/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-dot-dot-dot-magnetism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li><p>Magnetism is familiar to every fifth grader, but describing it can confound even the most brilliant physicist.</p></li>
<li><p>Take the case of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Feynman">Richard Feynman</a>. When asked to explain magnetism, he <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wMFPe-DwULM">urged his BBC interviewer to take it on faith</a> (video). After seven minutes of stonewalling, he finally said, “I really can’t do a good job, any job, of explaining magnetic force in terms of something else that you’re more familiar with because I don’t understand it in terms of anything else that you’re more familiar with.”</p></li>
</ol>


<!--more-->


<ol>
<li><p>He did break down and try for a few seconds before abandoning the attempt. Those seconds were packed with oversimplifications: “All the electrons [in a magnet] are spinning in the same direction.”</p></li>
<li><p>But who better than Feynman would have known that not all electrons spin in the same direction?</p></li>
<li><p>And they don’t actually spin. “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spin_%28physics%29">Spin</a>” is just a physicist’s term for the little magnetic north and south poles baked into every electron. The orientation of those poles defines the direction of the electron’s (somewhat imaginary) rotation.</p></li>
<li><p>Why does every electron have those poles? As soon as someone finds out, we’ll get back to you.</p></li>
<li><p>Here is what we do know. Within an atom, each electron is usually paired with an opposite- oriented electron so that their magnetic pulls cancel each other out.</p></li>
<li><p>But if some of the electrons are unpaired, they can be induced to move around so that their poles line up, creating a net magnetic field. The arrangement of the electrons in metals makes them particularly open to magnetic peer pressure.</p></li>
<li><p>DIY refrigerator magnet: Apply an external magnetic field to some hot metal. Cool it so the aligned electrons get frozen in place. Slap on your local plumber’s business card, and—voilà!</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/653297/yinyang">Yin Seeks Yang</a> for Magnetic Relationship. All magnets have north and south poles, and opposite poles attract: North poles seek south poles seek north poles seek south poles seek . . .</p></li>
<li><p>You are standing on a magnet right now. The earth’s magnetic field is created by electric currents in an ocean of molten iron at its core. That’s why the north pole of a compass needle points . . . er . . . why north? Since north poles are attracted to south poles, the “north” arrow on your compass actually points toward the earth’s south magnetic pole, which is the one up north. Got it?</p></li>
<li><p>And the earth’s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/North_Magnetic_Pole">magnetic south</a> (aka “north”) pole isn’t even precisely at the geographic north pole. Right now it is in the Arctic Ocean, near northern Canada.</p></li>
<li><p>Worse still, it is constantly drifting in response to currents in the earth’s core. It is moving toward Siberia at a rate of up to 35 miles per year, according to the U.S. Geological Survey. Hey, shift happens.</p></li>
<li><p>Ancient mariners navigated by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lodestone">lodestone</a>, naturally occurring magnetic rocks.</p></li>
<li><p>Where lodestones come from is another mystery of magnetism. Some geologists think they are created when lighting strikes iron-rich rocks.</p></li>
<li><p>Microbes, birds, and some other animals have magnetic crystals inside their bodies that allow them to orient themselves.</p></li>
<li><p>That is probably why <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loggerhead_sea_turtle">loggerhead turtles</a> can migrate 8,000 miles in unfamiliar waters while humans can get lost looking for the restroom at Olive Garden.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetic_resonance_imaging">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</a> (MRI) machines generate a field 60,000 times as intense as the earth’s to vibrate the hydrogen atoms in your body; in response, the atoms emit radio waves that are analyzed to produce a map of your insides.</p></li>
<li><p>Using a sensor the size of a sugar cube, researchers from the <a href="http://www.nist.gov/index.html">National Institute of Standards and Technology</a> can <a href="http://www.nist.gov/pml/div688/magnetic_101310.cfm">track the magnetic pattern of a human heart</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>The signal is faint, but the good news is that science has proved attraction is quantifiable. Word up, Hallmark.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>from <a href="http://discovermagazine.com/2011/jul-aug/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-magnetism">http://discovermagazine.com/2011/jul-aug/20-things-you-didnt-know-about-magnetism</a></p>

<p>Chinese version (中文: 关于磁&#8211;你所不知道的二十件事) <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/159732/253517">http://article.yeeyan.org/view/159732/253517</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water Walking]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/water-walking/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T13:53:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/23/water-walking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A water layer was sprinkled with Thymol Blue, which established the Marangoni convection responsible for the evident fine-scale texture. The layer was lit from below, giving the flow a natural luminescence. Stopping vortices shed during the deceleration phase of the strider&#8217;s motion are evident in Figure 2.  The dipolar vortices shed by the driving legs during each stroke are evident in Figure 3, and mark the path of the strider. The starburst in Figure 3 is associated with the relatively large particle of thymol blue evident at its centre: the Thymol Blue reduces the local surface tension, thus prompting surface divergence that clears the surface of blue dye.  The water striders are light-seeking, and so drawn to the starbursts.</p>

<p><img src="http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/icarus.jpg" alt="Water Walking" /></p>

<p>Read detail from <a href="http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/striderweb.html">http://www-math.mit.edu/~dhu/Striderweb/striderweb.html</a>
<a href="http://www.me.gatech.edu/hu/">http://www.me.gatech.edu/hu/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dive into Node.JS]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/dive-into-node-dot-js/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T15:29:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/dive-into-node-dot-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Node.js is a platform built on Chrome&#8217;s JavaScript runtime for easily building fast, scalable network applications. Node.js uses an event-driven, non-blocking I/O model that makes it lightweight and efficient, perfect for data-intensive real-time applications that run across distributed devices.
<a href="http://nodejs.org">http://nodejs.org</a></p>

<!--more-->


<p>Felix&#8217;s Node.js Guide
<a href="http://nodeguide.com/">http://nodeguide.com/</a></p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/beginner.html">Node.js Beginner Guide</a>
If you are new to node.js, this guide will take you from hello world to deploying your first app.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/style.html">Node.js Style Guide</a>
The general JavaScript style I recommend to use with node.js. A lot of this is personal preferences, but hopefully rather consistent.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/community.html">Node.js Community Guide</a>
Get to know some of the node.js community and find out where they hang out.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://nodeguide.com/convincing_the_boss.html">Node.js Convincing The Boss Guide</a>
Find out where node.js makes sense, and how to get management to see the benefits.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>NodeJS – The what, why, how and when
<a href="http://blog.xebia.com/2011/08/16/nodejs-the-what-why-how-and-when/">http://blog.xebia.com/2011/08/16/nodejs-the-what-why-how-and-when/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Images Optimization]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/web-images-optimization/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T15:16:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/web-images-optimization</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Use PNG! with ImageMagick</p>

<h2>GIF Animation</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://www.lcdf.org/gifsicle/">GitSlice</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  gifsicle -o  test-optimized.gif test.gif</p>

<h2>PNG</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://pmt.sourceforge.net/pngcrush/">PNGCrush</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  pngcrush -rem alla -brute -reduce test.jpg test-optimized.jpg</p>

<h2>JPEG</h2>

<p>Tool: <a href="http://jpegclub.org/jpegtran/">JPEGTran</a>
Command:</p>

<p>  jpegtran -optimize -progressive -copy none -outfile test-optimized.jpg test.jpg</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Reference from <a href="http://www.welefen.com/image-optimization.html">前端优化之图片优化自动化</a></p>

<p>12 Really Useful Image Optimization Tools For Web Designers
<a href="http://www.webdesignbooth.com/12-really-useful-image-optimization-tools-for-web-designers/">http://www.webdesignbooth.com/12-really-useful-image-optimization-tools-for-web-designers/</a></p>

<p>Optimizing Web Graphics: Compression
<a href="http://www.webreference.com/dev/graphics/compress.html">http://www.webreference.com/dev/graphics/compress.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Picking the right NoSQL Database]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/nosql-databases/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T13:22:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/nosql-databases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NoSQL = Not Only SQL</p>

<p><a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/271351/239915">8种Nosql数据库系统对比</a></p>

<p><a href="http://kkovacs.eu/cassandra-vs-mongodb-vs-couchdb-vs-redis">Cassandra vs MongoDB vs CouchDB vs Redis vs Riak vs HBase vs Membase vs Neo4j comparison</a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.monitis.com/index.php/2011/05/22/picking-the-right-nosql-database-tool/">Picking the right NoSQL database tool</a></p>

<h2>Key-values Stores</h2>

<p>Tokyo Cabinet/Tyrant, Redis, Voldemort, Oracle BDB</p>

<p>Content caching (Focus on scaling to huge amounts of data, designed to handle massive load), logging, etc.</p>

<p>Strengths: Fast lookups
Weaknesses: Stored data has no schema</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Column Family Stores</h2>

<p>Cassandra, HBase, Riak</p>

<p>Distributed file systems</p>

<p>Strengths: Fast lookups, good distributed storage of data
Weaknesses: Very low-level API</p>

<h2>Document Databases</h2>

<p>CouchDB, MongoDB</p>

<p>Web applications (Similar to Key-Value stores, but the DB knows what the Value is)</p>

<p>Strengths: Tolerant of incomplete data
Weaknesses: Query performance, no standard query syntax</p>

<h2>Graph Databases</h2>

<p>Neo4J, InfoGrid, Infinite Graph</p>

<p>Social networking, Recommendations (Focus on modeling the structure of data - interconnectivity)</p>

<p>Strengths: Graph algorithms e.g. shortest path, connectedness, n degree relationships, etc.
Weaknesses: Has to traverse the entire graph to achieve a definitive answer. Not easy to cluster.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mindon GitHub Blog Start]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/mindon-github-blog-start/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T16:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/02/20/mindon-github-blog-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Frameworks &amp; tools for web developer.</p>

<p>Javascript, NodeJS, Chrome App, CorelDraw plug-in &#8230;</p>

<p>Learning web tech &amp; apply them to solve daily problems!</p>

<p>Air off, Mind on ~ :-) 2012</p>

<p>with following tech &amp; tools:
Git tool
github pages
Ruby &amp; Ruby DevKit
RubyGem
Octopress</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
