<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mindon | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/categories/mindon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-19T07:11:25+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[开心，怒气和烦恼]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/19/happy-angry-and-worries/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T06:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/19/happy-angry-and-worries</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>开心：开放的心，放开的心。</p>

<p>怒气：基本上源于对相关不相关的人要求过多或者过高。</p>

<p>烦恼：大概都来自对自己过多或者过高的要求。</p>

<p>让心充满阳光，你才会体会到世界的美好；</p>

<p>让心充满好奇，你才会感受到世界的奇妙；</p>

<p>让心放空，你才能接收更多的幸福。</p>

<p>世界是丰富多彩的，未来是变幻莫测的。</p>

<p>宽容和感恩之心是走向未来的必备食粮。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Next Mobile Phone and BlackBerry 10.3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/19/my-next-mobile-phone-and-blackberry-10-dot-3/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-19T06:21:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/19/my-next-mobile-phone-and-blackberry-10-dot-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I updated my BlackBerry Q10 Dev Device to BlackBerry OS 10.3.0.738, It was from the 10.3.0.1154 autoloader.</p>

<p>It's flat styled - it looks much better.</p>

<p>But its camera shot method is changed to an android style, it's bad - it's a great part of the camera in BlackBerry 10 devices. Taking photo and its NFC are the features I enjoy everyday.</p>

<p>Yes, I'm using a BlackBerry mobile phone, a dev device not for sell. Last mobile phone I bought for myself is a Nokia, now it's such a tiny one. Here they are</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/mobiles.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I'm always waitting for my next mobile phone.</p>

<p>iPhone? Yes, it's a great mobile phone, but I still find no reason for it - at least there's not enough reasons right now. Even the iPhone 6 - hmm, It's great and with a high price and not sell in China mainland yet :)</p>

<p>I was planning to buy a Nexus 4, then a Moto X, then a Next 5...</p>

<p>Google services is blocked in mainland China.</p>

<p>You may say a VPN may works - but I don't like it.</p>

<p>You may say a hosts with a rooted device works - But I don't like it either.</p>

<p>Before a mobile device hit my heart, I will still prefer my dev version BlackBerry Q10.</p>

<p>I have a Nexus 7(2013) and a Kindle, they are awesome devices.</p>

<p>But choosing a mobile phone, I could wait.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[那些恼人的尘灰]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/18/dust-in-a-old-building/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-18T22:32:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/09/18/dust-in-a-old-building</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>前两天台风“海鸥”的飞过，让周末刚大扫除干净的房子又满是尘灰。我们家在一栋有些老的高楼里，一到刮大风的时候就不知道哪刮出的尘灰，弄得到处都是，每次我都会想：要是有个一大的吸尘器，把整栋楼吸吸尘就好了 :p</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/dust.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>有一定年限的房子，积尘和设计上缺陷带来的漏水问题一直是让人头大的问题，有什么技术和办法能改善一下呢？</p>

<p>有待探讨。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[西少爷.肉夹馍，开分店啦]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/about-xishaoye-roujiamo/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T17:41:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/about-xishaoye-roujiamo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这个周日（Aug 23, 2014），<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/12500068.htm">西少爷肉夹馍</a>望京分店要开业了。这个肉夹馍品牌今年可算是IT圈里的热门话题。主题团队均来自BAT等大公司的离职员工——他们传递出一种信息：选择的自由，奋斗的激情，学习的能力和感染的力量。</p>

<p>孟兵，是个我没有认识和见面之前就能感受到他行动能力的小伙子。他在T工作期间，学习和工作都异于常人地努力和拼命，而且方向很明确和坚定。</p>

<p>昨天微信上看到他的分店开张的消息，可以感觉到他在一步步朝着自己的目标前行，很棒！</p>

<p>其实写这篇日志，不是因为他的新店开张，而是因为看到“肉夹馍”几个字，有点造字的一个想法，作品是……</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="/images/blog/r.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>要表达什么？嗯… 不解释。不同的人理解产生不同的诠释，才是最有意思的地方。</p>

<p>当然，顺便宣传一下也是要的 :-p</p>

<p>第一个店开在五道口，Aby在北京很熟悉和喜欢的地方，被称为“宇宙的中心”的位置。</p>

<p>第二个店：8-24（本周日）上午10：30，西少爷望京凯德Mall店准时开业！（地下一层扶梯正对第3家店）这个新店会有三种新品，据说“牛馍王”就是其中之一。免费送馍是他们店的传统了，附近的大公司工卡也能免费领。</p>

<p>祝他们生意兴隆 :-) 西少爷们，加油！</p>

<p>IT码农的才能不仅仅是Coding，我们强大的学习能力，适应能力和其他行业能力也是不容忽视的。Fighting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seeing is Not Always Believable]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/seeing-is-not-always-believable/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T16:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/seeing-is-not-always-believable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"This is an illusion that's so good it's hard to believe it's an illusion. When the black and white lines disappear, it's easy to see the rectangles are moving at constant speed.  But before that they seem to be taking turns, and pausing when they reach each new line."</p>

<p>The original illusion image is a gif. I cannot believe it's a true illusion - it may be a gif animation trick. So I decided to check on the gif animation inside - frame by frame: It's a true illusion! Amazing!</p>

<p>To clean your doubt. I make a interactive image for this illusion:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><svg id="illus" width="600" height="250"></svg></p>

<ol>
    <li> click vertical bars to switch between bars and pure background color;</li>
    <li> click the color block to restart animation</li>
</ol>




<script src="http://mindon.github.io/lib/snap.svg-min.js"></script>


<script>
var s = Snap('#illus');
var p = s.path("M10 0 v250 h10 v-250z").attr({
  fill: "#000000"
}).pattern(0, 0, 20, 250);

s.rect(0,0,600,250).attr({
  fill: p
}).click(function(){
  this.attr({fill: !/url/.test(this.attr('fill')) ? p : '#666666'});
});

var r1 = s.rect(0,60,40,20).attr({
  fill: '#ffff00'
}).click(resetBlocks);

var r2 = s.rect(0,160,40,20).attr({
  fill: '#0000ff'
}).click(resetBlocks);

var blocks = Snap.set(r1, r2);
function resetBlocks() {
  blocks.attr({x:0}).animate({x: 560}, 18000, mina.linear, function(){
    resetBlocks();
  });
}
resetBlocks();
</script>


<p>Still hard to believe? The Illusion -- Seeing is not always believable! Be careful of what you see!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
