<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mindon | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/categories/mindon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-24T22:05:29+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrade winxp from sp2 to sp3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/upgrade-winxp-from-sp2-to-sp3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T17:59:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/upgrade-winxp-from-sp2-to-sp3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've tried more than 3 times before:</p>

<p>to upgrade my HP Mini winxp to sp3</p>

<p>Lots of time spended on this stupid issue -- winxp sp3 upgrade problem.</p>

<p>The problem i faced last time is "A Problem is preventing windows from accurately checking the license". 0x80070002</p>

<p>Who knows what the hell was happening, my winxp is lisenced!</p>

<p>Tons of softwares need sp3 -- something like "Visual C++ 2010 Express".</p>

<p>That's why I need sp3 package installed.</p>

<p>Here are the steps I followed, to upgrade sp3:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>download sp3 package from microsoft
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?displaylang=en&amp;id=24">http://www.microsoft.com/download/en/details.aspx?displaylang=en&amp;id=24</a></p></li>
<li><p>backup following files from windows/system32</p>

<p>   dpcdll.dll <br/>
   pidgen.dll <br/>
   uxtheme.dll<br/>
   wpa.dbl</p></li>
<li><p>Restart my winxp &amp; press F8 to start from safe mode</p></li>
<li><p>Install sp3</p></li>
<li><p>Restart &amp; press F8 to start from safe mode</p></li>
<li><p>Backup new files from sp3 version</p>

<p>   dpcdll.dll <br/>
   pidgen.dll <br/>
   uxtheme.dll<br/>
   wpa.dbl</p></li>
<li><p>Replace these files with the old files backuped in step 2</p></li>
<li><p>Restart</p></li>
<li><p>Done!</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I don't know if my steps make it or the sp3 package is different or something else ...</p>

<p>But i do upgrade my HP Mini windows xp from sp2 to sp3 successfully this time :-)</p>

<p>God bless you!</p>

<p>Thanks for <a href="http://hi.baidu.com/xiaohuibai/blog/item/69fa16f4b7e1e8f77609d7d9.html">this blog</a> (in Chinese) -- I didn't use any files it provides.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magic Code Switching Comment Syntax]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/magic-code-switching-comment-syntax/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T23:58:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/magic-code-switching-comment-syntax</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a kind of c-style code comments to switch two blocks of code for debug or testing.</p>

<pre><code>/*/
  //... Section A (commented)
/*/
  //... Section B (working)
//*/
</code></pre>

<p>By adding one single / at the beginning, it turns into:</p>

<pre><code>//*/
  //... Section A (working)
/*/
  //... Section B (commented)
//*/
</code></pre>

<p>Another simple section comment:</p>

<pre><code>//*/
  //... working
//*/
</code></pre>

<p>remove a single / at the beginning, it turns into:</p>

<pre><code>/*/
  //... commented
//*/
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li><p>Curiosity</p></li>
<li><p>Passion</p></li>
<li><p>Focus</p></li>
<li><p>Fun</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absurd]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/words-that-sound-different/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T20:30:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/words-that-sound-different</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The video from youtube <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R281PhQufHo"><strong>GDC 2012</strong> - Porting your game to NaCl</a>.</p>

<p>When I finished watching this video at noon, I visit the speaker's Google+. There I see this sentence as his motto</p>

<p><strong>Colt McAnlis</strong> -- "If at first, the idea is not absurd, then there is no hope for it"</p>

<p>This is the first time I met the word: <strong>absurd</strong>!</p>

<p>Another article “Man, give it five minutes.”</p>

<p><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes">http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes</a></p>

<blockquote><p>There are two things in this world that take no skill: 1. Spending other people’s money and 2. Dismissing an idea.</p>

<p>Dismissing an idea is so easy because it doesn’t involve any work. You can scoff at it. You can ignore it. You can puff some smoke at it. That’s easy. The hard thing to do is protect it, think about it, let it marinate, explore it, riff on it, and try it. The right idea could start out life as the wrong idea.</p>

<p>So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying it’s too hard or it’s too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.</p></blockquote>

<p>“Your first design may be the best, but you won't know until you can't find a better one.”</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.intercom.io/criticism-and-two-way-streets/">http://blog.intercom.io/criticism-and-two-way-streets/</a></p>

<h2>Working on TikTalk</h2>

<p>This time, when we start a new product. I need a name for it: I choose tiktalk hoping the product could be someting like a drop of water in the ocean of internet: providing a kind of driving force of a website's life.</p>

<p>A name for product is importance to express our idea, activate our creative power to push it forward. (I learn this from the global mail project last year.)</p>

<p>It's a hard work during these 3 weeks:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Design the front-end &amp; back-end frameworks</p></li>
<li><p>Setup service of back-end</p></li>
<li><p>Rewrite front-end codes</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Today, finish front-end demo: a few features in detail, fixing bugs...</p>

<p>TikTalk is working fine! :-)</p>

<p>Next week, making back-end service more stable &amp; flexible is big challenge for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[激情 - Passion]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/10/programmers-are-born-not-made/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-10T14:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/10/programmers-are-born-not-made</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Passion</h2>

<blockquote><p>Sometimes when you give an impressionable young mind (anybody deciding to learn to code, age is irrelevant) two tools and a problem, they will use the two tools to create four more tools. Then they will get on the internets and find some more tools … soon they have twenty tools and what was the problem you wanted me to solve again?</p>

<p>That’s passion!</p>

<p>Pure unadulterated passion for programming. When you can be fascinated, even excited, about this stuff without a need to solve a problem. Hell, even if you are solving a problem that you know is a meaningless exercise … that’s where greatness lies.</p>

<p>It doesn’t matter what age you started coding at – many studies have shown experience is not a predictor of quality in our world – what matters is that you have a passion for this stuff.</p>

<p>Because if you’ve got the passion, then you probably have everything else you need as well.</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://swizec.com/blog/programmers-are-born-not-made/swizec/3369">Programmers are born not made</a></p>

<h2>激情</h2>

<blockquote><p>有时候，当你给一个有上进心的年轻心灵(任何愿意学习编程的人，年龄不是问题)两种工具和一个难题。他会使用这两种工具创造出4种工具。他会搜索互联网，发现更多的工具…很快，他有了20种工具，请问你还让我解决什么问题？</p>

<p>这就是激情！</p>

<p>心无杂念的对编程的激情。没有问题需要解决时仍然对编程入迷，甚至兴奋。甚至把解决一个已知的问题也当作一次普通的练习…这就是卓越之处。</p>

<p>多大岁数才开始学习编程，这并不重要——很多研究显示，在我们这个世界里，编程的工龄并不是水平的指示符——重要的是你对这个行业有个充满激情的心。</p>

<p>因为，一旦有了激情，你就拥有了所有其它的一切。</p></blockquote>

<p>做任何事情，如果没有激情，就没法做得比别人更好！</p>

<p>在IBG数年，有两个同事说的话一直让我印象深刻：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>技术，要有激情！ —— Teddy</p></li>
<li><p>同样的事情，你来做和别人做能有什么不一样？ —— Flying</p></li>
</ol>


<p>今天看到【外刊IT评论】的这篇文章（<a href="http://www.aqee.net/programmers-are-born-not-made/">一个人是否能成为程序员是上天注定的</a>），深有感触！特以此文自勉。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For my darling: Aby]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/for-my-dear-aby/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T13:15:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/for-my-dear-aby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aby, 在一起的日子里，你带来了丰富多彩的生活，让我每天都能体会到幸福的滋味。谢谢你，宝贝。</p>

<p>最想对你说的还是那三个字 :-) <a href="http://mindon.appspot.com/i-love-u">I love you</a>。其实，用多少种语言也难以表达这种从心底溢出的感情。</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/red-rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>我生病的这段日子，你用心研究各种食材，每天想尽办法做营养、美味又适合我吃的饭菜。</p>

<p>——每天回家都能吃上热乎乎的美食，还有什么比这更幸福呢？</p>

<p>你所做的，远不止美食和各式各样的滋补靓汤，或是美味的馄饨、吐司面包、通心粉这些早餐…</p>

<p>还有无法数清的细微照顾和用心付出。</p>

<p>这点点滴滴，让我无时无刻都感受到幸福的温暖。</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/purple-rose.jpeg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>缘分让我们由千里之外到相聚在一起，转眼数年飞逝——过去幸福快乐的分分秒秒，会永远留在记忆中，也会在未来继续精彩。</p>

<p>我们旅游的足迹会继续洒落在世界各地，世界的风景和美食也会越来越多汇合到温暖小家的照片墙上。</p>

<p>在这特别的日子里，想对你说：</p>

<h2>有你在身边，真好！</h2>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/light-up-rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>衷心祝愿我们家的Aby每天都健健康康，美丽和快乐！</p>

<p>节日快乐！有你就有欢乐:-)</p>

<blockquote><p>I love you more and more each day, as time goes by.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/roses.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>You are my flowers in spring,</p>

<p>Bring me fresh and happiness.</p>

<p>You are my rains in summer,</p>

<p>Keep me far from desert and dust.</p>

<p>You are my wind in autumn,</p>

<p>Bring me the golden harvest.</p>

<p>You are my sunlight in winter,</p>

<p>Warm me up in the cold morning.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>写给我们家的Aby —— 聪明能干、美丽勤劳的女主人，</p>

<p>—— 麥盾，二零一二年三月八日，深圳</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
