<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mindon | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/categories/mindon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-23T18:09:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[西少爷.肉夹馍，开分店啦]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/about-xishaoye-roujiamo/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T17:41:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/about-xishaoye-roujiamo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>这个周日（Aug 23, 2014），<a href="http://baike.baidu.com/view/12500068.htm">西少爷肉夹馍</a>望京分店要开业了。这个肉夹馍品牌今年可算是IT圈里的热门话题。主题团队均来自BAT等大公司的离职员工——他们传递出一种信息：选择的自由，奋斗的激情，学习的能力和感染的力量。</p>

<p>孟兵，是个我没有认识和见面之前就能感受到他行动能力的小伙子。他在T工作期间，学习和工作都异于常人地努力和拼命，而且方向很明确和坚定。</p>

<p>昨天微信上看到他的分店开张的消息，可以感觉到他在一步步朝着自己的目标前行，很棒！</p>

<p>其实写这篇日志，不是因为他的新店开张，而是因为看到“肉夹馍”几个字，有点造字的一个想法，作品是……</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="/images/blog/r.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>要表达什么？嗯… 不解释。不同的人理解产生不同的诠释，才是最有意思的地方。</p>

<p>当然，顺便宣传一下也是要的 :-p</p>

<p>第一个店开在五道口，Aby在北京很熟悉和喜欢的地方，被称为“宇宙的中心”的位置。</p>

<p>第二个店：8-24（本周日）上午10：30，西少爷望京凯德Mall店准时开业！（地下一层扶梯正对第3家店）这个新店会有三种新品，据说“牛馍王”就是其中之一。免费送馍是他们店的传统了，附近的大公司工卡也能免费领。</p>

<p>祝他们生意兴隆 :-) 西少爷们，加油！</p>

<p>IT码农的才能不仅仅是Coding，我们强大的学习能力，适应能力和其他行业能力也是不容忽视的。Fighting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seeing is Not Always Believable]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/seeing-is-not-always-believable/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-23T16:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/23/seeing-is-not-always-believable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"This is an illusion that's so good it's hard to believe it's an illusion. When the black and white lines disappear, it's easy to see the rectangles are moving at constant speed.  But before that they seem to be taking turns, and pausing when they reach each new line."</p>

<p>The original illusion image is a gif. I cannot believe it's a true illusion - it may be a gif animation trick. So I decided to check on the gif animation inside - frame by frame: It's a true illusion! Amazing!</p>

<p>To clean your doubt. I make a interactive image for this illusion:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><svg id="illus" width="600" height="250"></svg></p>

<ol>
    <li> click vertical bars to switch between bars and pure background color;</li>
    <li> click the color block to restart animation</li>
</ol>




<script src="http://mindon.github.io/lib/snap.svg-min.js"></script>


<script>
var s = Snap('#illus');
var p = s.path("M10 0 v250 h10 v-250z").attr({
  fill: "#000000"
}).pattern(0, 0, 20, 250);

s.rect(0,0,600,250).attr({
  fill: p
}).click(function(){
  this.attr({fill: !/url/.test(this.attr('fill')) ? p : '#666666'});
});

var r1 = s.rect(0,60,40,20).attr({
  fill: '#ffff00'
}).click(resetBlocks);

var r2 = s.rect(0,160,40,20).attr({
  fill: '#0000ff'
}).click(resetBlocks);

var blocks = Snap.set(r1, r2);
function resetBlocks() {
  blocks.attr({x:0}).animate({x: 560}, 18000, mina.linear, function(){
    resetBlocks();
  });
}
resetBlocks();
</script>


<p>Still hard to believe? The Illusion -- Seeing is not always believable! Be careful of what you see!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Programming Language: Swift]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/22/the-programming-language-swift/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-22T06:37:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/22/the-programming-language-swift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Swift是苹果公司今年推出的新编程语言。花了差不多两个星期看完iBooks里官方的《The Swift Programming Language》之后，感觉Swift简单易用的脚本式语法，灵活性，扩展性，清晰严格的规范确实是集成了很多语言的优点。</p>

<p>Swift + LLVM，如果再有跨平台的开发环境的话，纯从编程语言的角度来看，是具有替代C++，PYTHON，Java的强大实力。</p>

<p>不过现实是目前如此庞大的软件开发人群，要投入到一种新的即使是设计精良的编程语言，必然是一个长期的过程，而且需要需求的必要性来驱动。</p>

<p>如果Swift做不到别的语言不可替代的事情，不管语言设计本身好到什么程度，应用和推广始终会是硬伤。</p>

<p>愿Swift能顺利成长壮大，发挥威力！ :-p</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WordPress, Golang & Swift]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T11:47:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/08/10/wordpress-golang-and-swift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"WordPress is web software you can use to create a beautiful website or blog. We like to say that WordPress is both free and priceless at the same time."  -- <a href="http://wordpress.org/">wordpress.org</a></p>

<p>It's welcomed worldwide with lots of themes and plugins to enpower its features and functions. WordPress has more than ten years history. But I setup and got into its details only at the end of June this year.</p>

<p>Customize one of its theme to our style, separated it into two versions - one is readonly without admin features as the live product for public, the other is the full version accessible only for internal network.</p>

<p>Cache, Share to facebook and sitemap.xml for SEO is also important features you cannot miss.</p>

<p>Make the blog online in 2 weeks, fixing bugs, improve SEO and share time to time in another 3 weeks.</p>

<p>Now, simple plugins, update themes, shortcode features, wordpress editor - tinymce plugin, facebook share metas ... that's what i got from the one month project with WordPress. It's great to get such a project to get into WordPress, from its apache/nginx settings, .htaccess controls to some coding details all by myself.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>At the same time, I got another opportunity to practise <a href="http://golang.org">Go Language</a>. It's a simple internal management website with uploads, mysql database operation, oa authorization, handling JSON and sessions.</p>

<p>My first practice on golang is <strong>tof</strong> -- a simple library to implement OA APIs of our company. In fact, it's a golang version from my former nodejs version.</p>

<p>The "Notify Me" in golang works like a charm. I enjoy coding in go.</p>

<p>I cannot stop learning those wonderful programming techs. I'm reading on the Swift book on iBook. There's lots of coding styles of Swift and Golang are alike. As a Front-End JavaScript developer, It's a enjoyment.</p>

<p>Any opportunity to practise the Swift? I'm so sure there will be one :-)</p>

<p>I like Golang, maybe Swift too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[激活备份的敏思日志]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/restore-my-old-blogms-blogs/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-22T10:35:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.io/blog/2014/06/22/restore-my-old-blogms-blogs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>10年前，开始在敏思博客写日志，并在那里认识了我们家的Aby。不过后来敏思博客网站关闭，我就用一个自己写的工具把日志备份了下来。</p>

<p>昨天用go语言(golang)写了一个读取mht格式的程序，才发现当初备份的日志里，几乎有一半的日志对应的照片和图片没能保存成功，看来mht保存并不是那么靠谱的。还好文字都保存基本没问题。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>这个程序，把MHT文件格式里的文字和图片提取出来，并转成 OCTOPRESS （ 基于Jekyll ）用的markdown日志模板格式和独立图片文件。</p>

<p>总共六百多篇日志，因为很多照片日志图片丢失，清理了一下，最后剩下三百余篇统一放到了BlogMS分类中。</p>

<p>感谢敏思社区，特此文纪念。</p>

<p>（注：原敏思的朋友，如果是用麦盾当初的备份工具备份日志的，需要整理成简单html格式的可联系我，一定会抽空免费为大家处理，不过大部分日志图片/照片保存失败的事情，很抱歉，因为才发现这个问题，所以麦盾也无能为力了。）</p>

<p><span id="link-tags">敏思博客;敏思社区;OCTOPRESS;Jekyll;markdown</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
