<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mindon | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/categories/mindon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-17T23:08:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absurd]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/words-that-sound-different/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T20:30:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/words-that-sound-different</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The video from youtube <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R281PhQufHo"><strong>GDC 2012</strong> - Porting your game to NaCl</a>.</p>

<p>When I finished watching this video at noon, I visit the speaker's Google+. There I see this sentence as his motto</p>

<p><strong>Colt McAnlis</strong> -- "If at first, the idea is not absurd, then there is no hope for it"</p>

<p>This is the first time I met the word: <strong>absurd</strong>!</p>

<p>Another article “Man, give it five minutes.”</p>

<p><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes">http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes</a></p>

<blockquote><p>There are two things in this world that take no skill: 1. Spending other people’s money and 2. Dismissing an idea.</p>

<p>Dismissing an idea is so easy because it doesn’t involve any work. You can scoff at it. You can ignore it. You can puff some smoke at it. That’s easy. The hard thing to do is protect it, think about it, let it marinate, explore it, riff on it, and try it. The right idea could start out life as the wrong idea.</p>

<p>So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying it’s too hard or it’s too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.</p></blockquote>

<p>“Your first design may be the best, but you won't know until you can't find a better one.”</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.intercom.io/criticism-and-two-way-streets/">http://blog.intercom.io/criticism-and-two-way-streets/</a></p>

<h2>Working on TikTalk</h2>

<p>This time, when we start a new product. I need a name for it: I choose tiktalk hoping the product could be someting like a drop of water in the ocean of internet: providing a kind of driving force of a website's life.</p>

<p>A name for product is importance to express our idea, activate our creative power to push it forward. (I learn this from the global mail project last year.)</p>

<p>It's a hard work during these 3 weeks:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Design the front-end &amp; back-end frameworks</p></li>
<li><p>Setup service of back-end</p></li>
<li><p>Rewrite front-end codes</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Today, finish front-end demo: a few features in detail, fixing bugs...</p>

<p>TikTalk is working fine! :-)</p>

<p>Next week, making back-end service more stable &amp; flexible is big challenge for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[激情 - Passion]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/10/programmers-are-born-not-made/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-10T14:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/10/programmers-are-born-not-made</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Passion</h2>

<blockquote><p>Sometimes when you give an impressionable young mind (anybody deciding to learn to code, age is irrelevant) two tools and a problem, they will use the two tools to create four more tools. Then they will get on the internets and find some more tools … soon they have twenty tools and what was the problem you wanted me to solve again?</p>

<p>That’s passion!</p>

<p>Pure unadulterated passion for programming. When you can be fascinated, even excited, about this stuff without a need to solve a problem. Hell, even if you are solving a problem that you know is a meaningless exercise … that’s where greatness lies.</p>

<p>It doesn’t matter what age you started coding at – many studies have shown experience is not a predictor of quality in our world – what matters is that you have a passion for this stuff.</p>

<p>Because if you’ve got the passion, then you probably have everything else you need as well.</p></blockquote>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://swizec.com/blog/programmers-are-born-not-made/swizec/3369">Programmers are born not made</a></p>

<h2>激情</h2>

<blockquote><p>有时候，当你给一个有上进心的年轻心灵(任何愿意学习编程的人，年龄不是问题)两种工具和一个难题。他会使用这两种工具创造出4种工具。他会搜索互联网，发现更多的工具…很快，他有了20种工具，请问你还让我解决什么问题？</p>

<p>这就是激情！</p>

<p>心无杂念的对编程的激情。没有问题需要解决时仍然对编程入迷，甚至兴奋。甚至把解决一个已知的问题也当作一次普通的练习…这就是卓越之处。</p>

<p>多大岁数才开始学习编程，这并不重要——很多研究显示，在我们这个世界里，编程的工龄并不是水平的指示符——重要的是你对这个行业有个充满激情的心。</p>

<p>因为，一旦有了激情，你就拥有了所有其它的一切。</p></blockquote>

<p>做任何事情，如果没有激情，就没法做得比别人更好！</p>

<p>在IBG数年，有两个同事说的话一直让我印象深刻：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>技术，要有激情！ —— Teddy</p></li>
<li><p>同样的事情，你来做和别人做能有什么不一样？ —— Flying</p></li>
</ol>


<p>今天看到【外刊IT评论】的这篇文章（<a href="http://www.aqee.net/programmers-are-born-not-made/">一个人是否能成为程序员是上天注定的</a>），深有感触！特以此文自勉。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For my darling: Aby]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/for-my-dear-aby/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T13:15:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/for-my-dear-aby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Aby, 在一起的日子里，你带来了丰富多彩的生活，让我每天都能体会到幸福的滋味。谢谢你，宝贝。</p>

<p>最想对你说的还是那三个字 :-) <a href="http://mindon.appspot.com/i-love-u">I love you</a>。其实，用多少种语言也难以表达这种从心底溢出的感情。</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/red-rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>我生病的这段日子，你用心研究各种食材，每天想尽办法做营养、美味又适合我吃的饭菜。</p>

<p>——每天回家都能吃上热乎乎的美食，还有什么比这更幸福呢？</p>

<p>你所做的，远不止美食和各式各样的滋补靓汤，或是美味的馄饨、吐司面包、通心粉这些早餐…</p>

<p>还有无法数清的细微照顾和用心付出。</p>

<p>这点点滴滴，让我无时无刻都感受到幸福的温暖。</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/purple-rose.jpeg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>缘分让我们由千里之外到相聚在一起，转眼数年飞逝——过去幸福快乐的分分秒秒，会永远留在记忆中，也会在未来继续精彩。</p>

<p>我们旅游的足迹会继续洒落在世界各地，世界的风景和美食也会越来越多汇合到温暖小家的照片墙上。</p>

<p>在这特别的日子里，想对你说：</p>

<h2>有你在身边，真好！</h2>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/light-up-rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>衷心祝愿我们家的Aby每天都健健康康，美丽和快乐！</p>

<p>节日快乐！有你就有欢乐:-)</p>

<blockquote><p>I love you more and more each day, as time goes by.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/roses.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>You are my flowers in spring,</p>

<p>Bring me fresh and happiness.</p>

<p>You are my rains in summer,</p>

<p>Keep me far from desert and dust.</p>

<p>You are my wind in autumn,</p>

<p>Bring me the golden harvest.</p>

<p>You are my sunlight in winter,</p>

<p>Warm me up in the cold morning.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roses/rose.jpg" alt="Rose" /></p>

<p>写给我们家的Aby —— 聪明能干、美丽勤劳的女主人，</p>

<p>—— 麥盾，二零一二年三月八日，深圳</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[落叶——中西医有感]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/falling-leafs-life-system/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T20:21:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/falling-leafs-life-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>最近，路边有一种阔叶树开始掉叶子了——这种树在三月里的几天内叶子大片大片往下掉，直至全部叶子都掉光。我第一次看到满地叶子、树干光秃秃的时候，还以为世界末日临近了呢——满树的绿叶几天内变黄落了满地。</p>

<p>可是意外的是，再过一个星期，这树又满树的绿叶嫩芽了，长新叶子的速度跟落叶的速度一样——快得令人诧异。</p>

<p>这种现象，要是放到医学里头会是很有趣的事情：</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>西医</h2>

<p>基于检测的西医，发现突然树没叶子了，定会下结论——这树生病了，而且病得非常严重——必需住院治疗了。</p>

<p>住院嘛，主要任务就是检测了——于是，X光、抽液、剥皮取样——一通检测下来，还是没能发现毛病——只能给树输液吧，什么营养液，杀虫剂，生长激素——只要跟长叶子可能相关的措施都施展一遍，还是没有什么效果。</p>

<p>过了几天之后，树又开始长叶子了，于是西医觉得自己的治疗措施起作用了……</p>

<h2>中医</h2>

<p>中医从来不把病症作为割裂的现象来看待，系统分析、强调变化和个体差异、环境和气候影响……是中医的特点。</p>

<p>中医仅仅树生长的规律、特性，便能下结论——这现象是正常的生长代谢的过程，而不是病症，无需采取任何措施。</p>

<h2>思考</h2>

<p>近来天气返潮特别严重，屋里的很多东西由于潮湿开始长霉。Aby有一天就发现浴室里的一个木梳长霉了（此木梳已经很久没有使用了），费了很大的劲才清洗干净，放在阳台晾晒干了。又放回了浴室的篮子里…</p>

<p>这个是典型的类似西医治疗方式的处理：不理会梳子长霉的原因，只对梳子上的异常进行处理——因为没有消除长霉的根源，所以梳子过些日子必然继续长霉——需要继续处理。</p>

<p>然而，中医式的处理则会追究梳子长霉的根源——湿气太重：于是，唯有除湿并晾晒梳子才能让其避免继续或者未来的发霉。对于梳子，脱离湿气重的环境才是最佳的处理方式——放到浴室之外，远离湿气。</p>

<p>虽说，中医的理论体系——系统化、动态化要比机械化和数据硬性的西医治疗模式要先进得多，不过现代城市和社会里，要找个靠谱的中医何其难？于是，我们只会看到西医院里人头攒动——人气旺得很是热闹：人们没有选择，加上洗脑式的社会宣传和推销，庞大的利益链条的推动，这是很自然的现象，也是最可悲的事情。</p>

<p>最近看了N年前一位台湾中医大夫写的书《医钥》：里面描述的台湾医疗现状何尝不是今天大陆医疗的隐忧？</p>

<p>不究病因的依赖抗生素的西医治疗方式下，毛病只会越来越多，越来越无法治疗。悲哉！</p>

<p>推薦閱讀：<a href="http://ishare.iask.sina.com.cn/f/15423125.html">中醫之鑰（6寸版pdf）</a> 彭奕竣 《醫鑰》</p>

<p>----- 麥盾，二零一二年三月六日，深圳</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crush tradition! Photograph things as they are!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/crush-tradition-photograph-things-as-they-are/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T05:24:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/crush-tradition-photograph-things-as-they-are</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henri_Cartier-Bresson"><strong>Henri Cartier-Bresson</strong></a> (August 22, 1908 – August 3, 2004) was a French photographer considered to be the father of modern photojournalism. He was an early adopter of 35 mm format, and the master of candid photography. He helped develop the "street photography" or "real life reportage" style that has influenced generations of photographers who followed.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/blog/henri-cartier-bresson.jpg" alt="Henri Cartier-Bresson" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>I got his name from the Lytro Inventor's light field camera paper yesterday, but I'd saw his photograph long before.</p>

<p>With Google's search result, I know more about him: "The Decisive Moment" (Images à la sauvette)</p>

<blockquote><p>In 1952, Cartier-Bresson published his book Images à la sauvette, whose English edition was titled The Decisive Moment. It included a portfolio of 126 of his photos from the East and the West. The book's cover was drawn by Henri Matisse. For his 4,500-word philosophical preface, Cartier-Bresson took his keynote text from the 17th century Cardinal de Retz: "Il n'y a rien dans ce monde qui n'ait un moment decisif" ("There is nothing in this world that does not have a decisive moment"). Cartier-Bresson applied this to his photographic style. He said: "Photographier: c'est dans un même instant et en une fraction de seconde reconnaître un fait et l'organisation rigoureuse de formes perçues visuellement qui expriment et signifient ce fait" ("Photography is simultaneously and instantaneously the recognition of a fact and the rigorous organization of visually perceived forms that express and signify that fact")</p>

<p><a href="http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%BA%A8%E5%88%A9%C2%B7%E5%8D%A1%E8%92%82%E5%B0%94-%E5%B8%83%E9%9B%B7%E6%9D%BE"><strong>亨利·卡蒂尔－布雷松</strong></a>（Henri Cartier-Bresson，又译“亨利·卡蒂埃－布列松”，1908年8月22日－2004年8月2日）是法国著名的摄影家，年少时学习绘画，1930年开始加入摄影创作，1931年广泛游历各地，作品也开始在报纸、杂志、书籍上陆续发表。偏爱黑白摄影，喜爱莱卡135旁轴相机与50mm标准镜头，反对裁剪照片与使用闪光灯，认为不应干涉现场光线，被誉为20世纪最伟大的摄影家之一及现代新闻摄影的创立人。他同时也是知名的玛格南图片社创办者。他的"决定性瞬间"摄影理论影响了无数后继的摄影人。</p>

<p>“摄影与绘画不同，”布勒松在1957年接受《华盛顿邮报》采访时说， “拍摄的那一秒是个充满创造力的瞬间，你所构建和表达的是生活本身所提供给你的，并且你必须凭直觉判断何时按下快门。按下快门的那一瞬，便是摄影师所创作的，哦......是的，就是那一瞬！一旦你错过，它将不复存在</p>

<p>对于"决定性瞬间"，日本摄影家木村伊兵卫的注释更简单：“决定性瞬间就是光线、构图与感情相一致的瞬间。”</p></blockquote>

<p>“对我来讲，照相机就是一本速写簿，一件工具 -- 是获取直觉的、自发的和令疑问和决心并存的伟大瞬间的工具。一个人要想把有意义的东西带给世界，他就必须能够与他取景框中的事物灵犀相通。这种方式需要精力集中、头脑有素、反应敏锐和对几何结构有良好感觉。拍摄照片既要认清事实本身，又要赋予它视觉感知形式上的意义。它把人的头脑、眼睛和心灵放在了同一条轴线上。”</p>

<pre><code>          -- 亨利·卡蒂埃-布列松
</code></pre>

<p><strong>“打碎陈规，照片中的东西，应该就是它们自己！(Crush tradition! Photograph things as they are!)”</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>马格南的宗旨是：“触摸时代脉搏（“feel the pulse” of the times）”。</p>

<p>马格南的首批拍摄主题是：“生活在任何地方的人们（People Live Everywhere）”、“世界青年（Youth of the World）”、“世界妇女（Women of the World）”和“儿童一代（The Child Generation）”。</p></blockquote>

<p>More...</p>

<p>【译言网】 <a href="http://article.yeeyan.org/view/222604/197644">亨利·卡蒂尔-布雷松的经典摄影</a>
【Fondation Henri Cartier-Bresson】 <a href="http://www.henricartierbresson.org/">http://www.henricartierbresson.org/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
