<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Readings | Mindon.IDEA]]></title>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/categories/readings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mindon.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T15:16:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://mindon.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mindon Feng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[天才在左，疯子在右]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/genius-on-the-left-madness-on-the-right/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T21:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/genius-on-the-left-madness-on-the-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>《天才在做，疯子在右》这书名其实挺早之前就知道了，一直没有动力去读。最近看公司内的一个分享，里面提到了“你也是蘑菇”的案例。这引起了我的兴趣，于是周五晚上就在Kindle上读了一下，没想到一发不可收拾，周六就把整本书看完了。当然，最吸引我的是那些不同的世界观的案例，可以说跟TED很类似，能激发思考。</p>

<p>看到“生化奴隶”这一篇的时候，想起来前段时间在“译言网”上看到过一篇文章“<a href="http://select.yeeyan.org/view/279625/311822">微生物造就人类</a>”——人类不只是人类，同样也是由大量微生物组成的个体。</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.yeeyan.org/upload/image/2012/08/19030420_17652.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>世界观特别的精神病人是很有意思的，即使他们描述的是事实，所谓“正常人”也是不能接受的，因为人们已经把他们放到了“精神病人”这个类别，认同他们相当于把自己也归于此类——这往往是大家所避讳的。</p>

<p>其中有些案例，如果当事人把想法写成PPT，到TED分享，那也是走在科学前沿的IDEA :-)</p>

<p>《天才在做，疯子在右》，作者 高铭，网易读书上链接：<a href="http://data.book.163.com/book/home/009200190005/0000JYfK.html">阅读</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Children Learn What They Live]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/05/19/children-learn-what-they-live/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-19T12:31:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/05/19/children-learn-what-they-live</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>孩子在生活中学习</strong></p>

<p>by <strong>Dorothy Law Nolte</strong>, Ph.D.</p>

<p>美國的著名社會學家及精神治療師，1924年1月12日－2005年11月6日</p>

<p>If children live with criticism, they learn to condemn.</p>

<p>批评中长大的孩子，责难他人。</p>

<p>If children live with hostility, they learn to fight.</p>

<p>敌意中长大的孩子，喜欢争斗。</p>

<p>If children live with fear, they learn to be apprehensive.</p>

<p>恐惧中长大的孩子，常常担忧。</p>

<p>If children live with pity, they learn to feel sorry for themselves.</p>

<p>怜悯中成长的孩子，自怨自艾。</p>

<p>If children live with ridicule, they learn to feel shy.</p>

<p>嘲笑中长大的孩子，容易退缩。</p>

<p>If children live with jealousy, they learn to feel envy.</p>

<p>猜忌中长大的孩子，滋生怨恨。</p>

<p>If children live with shame, they learn to feel guilty.</p>

<p>羞耻中长大的孩子，内疚自责。</p>

<p>If children live with encouragement, they learn confidence.</p>

<p>鼓励中长大的孩子，深具自信。</p>

<p>If children live with tolerance, they learn patience.</p>

<p>宽容中长大的孩子，能够忍耐。</p>

<p>If children live with praise, they learn appreciation.</p>

<p>称赞中长大的孩子，懂得感恩。</p>

<p>If children live with acceptance, they learn to love.</p>

<p>承诺中长大的孩子，学会珍爱。</p>

<p>If children live with approval, they learn to like themselves.</p>

<p>认可中长大的孩子，收获自信。</p>

<p>If children live with recognition, they learn it is good to have a goal.</p>

<p>赏识中长大的孩子，树立目标。</p>

<p>If children live with sharing, they learn generosity.</p>

<p>分享中长大的孩子，慷慨大方。</p>

<p>If children live with honesty, they learn truthfulness.</p>

<p>诚信中长大的孩子，理解真理。</p>

<p>If children live with fairness, they learn justice.</p>

<p>公正中长大的孩子，极富正义。</p>

<p>If children live with kindness and consideration, they learn respect.</p>

<p>尊重中长大的孩子，懂得尊敬。</p>

<p>If children live with security, they learn to have faith in themselves and in those about them.</p>

<p>安定中长大的孩子，信任自己和他人。</p>

<p>If children live with friendliness, they learn the world is a nice place in which to live.</p>

<p>友善中长大的孩子，眼里是美好世界。</p>

<p>Copyright © 1972 by Dorothy Law Nolte</p>

<hr />

<p>Different versions of this poem:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.noogenesis.com/pineapple/Kristone.html">http://www.noogenesis.com/pineapple/Kristone.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good and Bad Reasons for Believing]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/05/19/good-and-bad-reasons-for-believing/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-19T12:04:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/05/19/good-and-bad-reasons-for-believing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(這篇文章找到英文的還真不容易，中文的都沒有註明英文文出處。曾在七年前在敏思博客上轉載過。——麥盾)</p>

<p>by <strong>Richard Dawkins</strong></p>

<p>"Tell a devout Christian that his wife is cheating on him, or that frozen yogurt can make a man invisible, and he is likely to require as much evidence as anyone else, and to be persuaded only to the extent that you give it. Tell him that the book he keeps by his bed was written by an invisible deity who will punish him with fire for eternity if he fails to accept its every incredible claim about the universe, and he seems to require no evidence whatsoever." —SAM HARRIS</p>

<p>NOTE: The following letter was written by Richard Dawkins, one of the world's most respected scientists. It is addressed to his daughter Juliet, who was ten years old at the time. The letter originally appeared as the last chapter of his 2003 book, A Devil's Chaplain. It is reprinted as an appendix in my book, Thank God for Evolution, by permission of the author. I included it for three reasons. First, it powerfully distinguishes the relative value today of, what I like to call, private and public revelation. Second, it provides an invaluable critique of traditional, flat-earth faith, while offering sound guidance for an evidence-based, naturalized faith. Third, it shows why scientific, historical, and cross-cultural evidence provide a far more accurate and useful map of reality than do tradition and authority.</p>

<p>"Good and Bad Reasons for Believing" — by Richard Dawkins</p>

<p>（注：附中文译文）</p>

<!--more-->


<p>“</p>

<p>Dear Juliet,</p>

<p>Now that you are ten, I want to write to you about something that is important to me. Have you ever wondered how we know the things that we know? How do we know, for instance, that the stars, which look like tiny pinpricks in the sky, are really huge balls of fire like the Sun and very far away? And how do we know that the Earth is a smaller ball whirling round one of those stars, the Sun?</p>

<p>The answer to these questions is "evidence." Sometimes evidence means actually seeing (or hearing, feeling, smelling...) that something is true. Astronauts have traveled far enough from the Earth to see with their own eyes that it is round. Sometimes our eyes need help. The "evening star" looks like a bright twinkle in the sky, but with a telescope you can see that it is a beautiful ball -- the planet we call Venus. Something that you learn by direct seeing (or hearing or feeling...) is called an observation.</p>

<p>Often, evidence isn't just an observation on its own, but observation always lies at the back of it. If there's been a murder, often nobody (except the murderer and the victim!) actually observed it. But detectives can gather together lots of other observations which may all point toward a particular suspect. If a person's fingerprints match those found on a dagger, this is evidence that he touched it. It doesn't prove that he did the murder, but it can help when it's joined up with lots of other evidence. Sometimes a detective can think about a whole lot of observations and suddenly realize that they all fall into place and make sense if so-and-so did the murder.</p>

<p>Scientists—the specialists in discovering what is true about the world and the universe—often work like detectives. They make a guess (called a hypothesis) about what might be true. They then say to themselves: If that were really true, we ought to see so-and-so. This is called a prediction. For example, if the world is really round, we can predict that a traveler, going on and on in the same direction, should eventually find himself back where he started. When a doctor says that you have the measles, he doesn't take one look at you and see measles. His first look gives him a hypothesis that you may have measles. Then he says to himself: If she really has measles, I ought to see.... Then he runs through the list of predictions and tests them with his eyes (have you got spots?), hands (is your forehead hot?), and ears (does your chest wheeze in a measly way?). Only then does he make his decision and say, "I diagnose that the child has measles." Sometimes doctors need to do other tests like blood tests or X-rays, which help their eyes, hands, and ears to make observations.</p>

<p>The way scientists use evidence to learn about the world is much cleverer and more complicated than I can say in a short letter. But now I want to move on from evidence, which is a good reason for believing something, and warn you against three bad reasons for believing anything. They are called "tradition," "authority," and "revelation."</p>

<p>First, tradition. A few months ago, I went on television to have a discussion with about fifty children. These children were invited because they'd been brought up in lots of different religions. Some had been brought up as Christians, others as Jews, Muslims, Hindus, or Sikhs. The man with the microphone went from child to child, asking them what they believed. What they said shows up exactly what I mean by "tradition." Their beliefs turned out to have no connection with evidence. They just trotted out the beliefs of their parents and grandparents, which, in turn, were not based upon evidence either. They said things like: "We Hindus believe so and so"; "We Muslims believe such and such"; "We Christians believe something else."</p>

<p>Of course, since they all believed different things, they couldn't all be right. The man with the microphone seemed to think this quite right and proper, and he didn't even try to get them to argue out their differences with each other. But that isn't the point I want to make for the moment. I simply want to ask where their beliefs come from. They came from tradition. Tradition means beliefs handed down from grandparent to parent to child, and so on. Or from books handed down through the centuries. Traditional beliefs often start from almost nothing; perhaps somebody just makes them up originally, like the stories about Thor and Zeus. But after they've been handed down over some centuries, the mere fact that they are so old makes them seem special. People believe things simply because people have believed the same thing over the centuries. That's tradition.</p>

<p>The trouble with tradition is that, no matter how long ago a story was made up, it is still exactly as true or untrue as the original story was. If you make up a story that isn't true, handing it down over a number of centuries doesn't make it any truer!</p>

<p>Most people in England have been baptized into the Church of England, but this is only one of the branches of the Christian religion. There are other branches such as Russian Orthodox, the Roman Catholic, and the Methodist churches. They all believe different things. The Jewish religion and the Muslim religion are a bit more different still; and there are different kinds of Jews and of Muslims. People who believe even slightly different things from each other often go to war over their disagreements. So you might think that they must have some pretty good reasons—evidence—for believing what they believe. But actually, their different beliefs are entirely due to different traditions.</p>

<p>Let's talk about one particular tradition. Roman Catholics believe that Mary, the mother of Jesus, was so special that she didn't die but was lifted bodily into Heaven. Other Christian traditions disagree, saying that Mary did die like anybody else. These other religions don't talk about her much and, unlike Roman Catholics, they don't call her the "Queen of Heaven." The tradition that Mary's body was lifted into Heaven is not a very old one. The Bible says nothing about how or when she died; in fact, the poor woman is scarcely mentioned in the Bible at all. The belief that her body was lifted into Heaven wasn't invented until about six centuries after Jesus' time. At first it was just made up, in the same way as any story like "Snow White" was made up. But, over the centuries, it grew into a tradition and people started to take it seriously simply because the story had been handed down over so many generations. The older the tradition became, the more people took it seriously. It finally was written down as an official Roman Catholic belief only very recently, in 1950, when I was the age you are now. But the story was no more true in 1950 than it was when it was first invented six hundred years after Mary's death.</p>

<p>I'll come back to tradition at the end of my letter, and look at it in another way. But first I must deal with the two other bad reasons for believing in anything: authority and revelation.</p>

<p>Authority, as a reason for believing something, means believing in it because you are told to believe it by somebody important. In the Roman Catholic Church, the pope is the most important person, and people believe he must be right just because he is the pope. In one branch of the Muslim religion, the important people are the old men with beards called ayatollahs. Lots of young Muslims are prepared to commit murder, purely because the ayatollahs in a faraway country tell them to.</p>

<p>When I say that it was only in 1950 that Roman Catholics were finally told that they had to believe that Mary's body shot off to Heaven, what I mean is that in 1950 the pope told people that they had to believe it. That was it. The pope said it was true, so it had to be true! Now, probably some of the things that that pope said in his life were true and some were not true. There is no good reason why, just because he was the pope, you should believe everything he said, any more than you believe everything that other people say. The present pope [1995] has ordered his followers not to limit the number of babies they have. If people follow this authority as slavishly as he would wish, the results could be terrible famines, diseases, and wars, caused by overcrowding.</p>

<p>Of course, even in science, sometimes we haven't seen the evidence ourselves and we have to take somebody else's word for it. I haven't, with my own eyes, seen the evidence that light travels at a speed of 186,000 miles per second. Instead, I believe books that tell me the speed of light. This looks like "authority." But actually, it is much better than authority, because the people who wrote the books have seen the evidence and anyone is free to look carefully at the evidence whenever they want. That is very comforting. But not even the priests claim that there is any evidence for their story about Mary's body zooming off to Heaven.</p>

<p>The third kind of bad reason for believing anything is called "revelation." If you had asked the pope in 1950 how he knew that Mary's body disappeared into Heaven, he would probably have said that it had been "revealed" to him. He shut himself in his room and prayed for guidance. He thought and thought, all by himself, and he became more and more sure inside himself. When religious people just have a feeling inside themselves that something must be true, even though there is no evidence that it is true, they call their feeling "revelation." It isn't only popes who claim to have revelations. Lots of religious people do. It is one of their main reasons for believing the things that they do believe. But is it a good reason?</p>

<p>Suppose I told you that your dog was dead. You'd be very upset, and you'd probably say, "Are you sure? How do you know? How did it happen?" Now suppose I answered: "I don't actually know that Pepe is dead. I have no evidence. I just have this funny feeling deep inside me that he is dead." You'd be pretty cross with me for scaring you, because you'd know that an inside "feeling" on its own is not a good reason for believing that a whippet is dead. You need evidence. We all have inside feelings from time to time, and sometimes they turn out to be right and sometimes they don't. Anyway, different people have opposite feelings, so how are we to decide whose feeling is right? The only way to be sure that a dog is dead is to see him dead, or hear that his heart has stopped, or be told by somebody who has seen or heard some real evidence that he is dead.</p>

<p>People sometimes say that you must believe in feelings deep inside, otherwise, you'd never be confident of things like "My wife loves me." But this is a bad argument. There can be plenty of evidence that somebody loves you. All through the day when you are with somebody who loves you, you see and hear lots of little tidbits of evidence, and they all add up. It isn't a purely inside feeling, like the feeling that priests call revelation. There are outside things to back up the inside feeling: looks in the eye, tender notes in the voice, little favors and kindnesses; this is all real evidence.</p>

<p>Sometimes people have a strong inside feeling that somebody loves them when it is not based on any evidence, and then they are likely to be completely wrong. There are people with a strong inside feeling that a famous film star loves them, when really the film star hasn't even met them. People like that are ill in their minds. Inside feelings must be backed up by evidence, otherwise you just can't trust them.</p>

<p>Inside feelings are valuable in science too, but only for giving you ideas that you later test by looking for evidence. A scientist can have a "hunch" about an idea that just "feels" right. In itself, this is not a good reason for believing something. But it can be a good reason for spending some time doing a particular experiment, or looking in a particular way for evidence. Scientists use inside feelings all the time to get ideas. But they are not worth anything until they are supported by evidence.</p>

<p>I promised that I'd come back to tradition, and look at it in another way. I want to try to explain why tradition is so important to us. All animals are built (by the process called evolution) to survive in the normal place in which their kind live. Lions are built to be good at surviving on the plains of Africa. Crayfish, to be good at surviving in fresh water, while lobsters are built to be good at surviving in the salt sea. People are animals, too, and we are built to be good at surviving in a world full of other people. Most of us don't hunt for our own food like lions or lobsters; we buy it from other people who have bought it from yet other people. We "swim" through a "sea of people." Just as a fish needs gills to survive in water, people need brains that make them able to deal with other people. Just as the sea is full of salt water, the sea of people is full of difficult things to learn. Like language.</p>

<p>You speak English, but your friend Ann-Kathrin speaks German. You each speak the language that fits you to "swim about" in your own separate "people sea." Language is passed down by tradition. There is no other way. In England, Pepe is a dog. In Germany he is ein Hund. Neither of these words is more correct or more true than the other. Both are simply handed down. In order to be good at "swimming about in their people sea," children have to learn the language of their own country, and lots of other things about their own people; and this means that they have to absorb, like blotting paper, an enormous amount of traditional information. (Remember that traditional information just means things that are handed down from grandparents to parents to children.) The child's brain has to be a sucker for traditional information. And the child can't be expected to sort out good and useful traditional information, like the words of a language, from bad or silly traditional information, like believing in witches and devils and ever-living virgins.</p>

<p>It's a pity, but it can't help being the case, that because children have to be suckers for traditional information, they are likely to believe anything the grown-ups tell them, whether true or false, right or wrong. Lots of what the grown-ups tell them is true and based on evidence, or at least sensible. But if some of it is false, silly, or even wicked, there is nothing to stop the children believing that, too. Now, when the children grow up, what do they do? Well, of course, they tell it to the next generation of children. So, once something gets itself strongly believed—even if it is completely untrue and there never was any reason to believe it in the first place—it can go on forever.</p>

<p>Could this be what has happened with religions? Belief that there is a god or gods, belief in Heaven, belief that Mary never died, belief that Jesus never had a human father, belief that prayers are answered, belief that wine turns into blood—not one of these beliefs is backed up by any good evidence. Yet millions of people believe them. Perhaps this is because they were told to believe them when they were young enough to believe anything.</p>

<p>Millions of other people believe quite different things, because they were told different things when they were children. Muslim children are told different things from Christian children, and both grow up utterly convinced that they are right and the others are wrong. Even within Christians, Roman Catholics believe different things from Church of England people or Episcopalians, Shakers or Quakers, Mormons or Holy Rollers, and all are utterly convinced that they are right and the others are wrong. They believe different things for exactly the same kind of reason as you speak English and Ann-Kathrin speaks German. Both languages are, in their own country, the right language to speak. But it can't be true that different religions are right in their own countries, because different religions claim that opposite things are true. Mary can't be alive in Catholic Southern Ireland but dead in Protestant Northern Ireland.</p>

<p>What can we do about all this? It is not easy for you to do anything, because you are only ten. But you could try this. Next time somebody tells you something that sounds important, think to yourself: "Is this the kind of thing that people probably know because of evidence? Or is it the kind of thing that people only believe because of tradition, authority, or revelation?" And, next time somebody tells you that something is true, why not say to them: "What kind of evidence is there for that?" And if they can't give you a good answer, I hope you'll think very carefully before you believe a word they say.</p>

<p>Your loving</p>

<p>Daddy</p>

<p>”</p>

<p>from <a href="http://thankgodforevolution.com/node/1950">http://thankgodforevolution.com/node/1950</a></p>

<p>【关于相信：好的理由和坏的理由】（一个父亲给自己10岁的女儿写的信）</p>

<p>亲爱的朱丽叶：</p>

<p>现在你10岁了，我想写给你一些对你很重要的事情。你是否曾经想过，我们是如何知道那些我们知道的东西？例如，恒星看上去好像在天空中刺出的小孔。我们是如何知道恒星其实是像太阳一样的大火球，并且它们离我们非常远？我们是如何知道地球是绕着这些恒星中的一颗——也就是太阳——运转的更小的球体？</p>

<p>这些问题的答案是“证据”。有时候证据的意思是亲眼看见（或者听见、感觉到、闻到）某事是真的。宇航员航行到了离地球足够远的地方，用他们的肉眼看到了地球是圆的。有时候我们的眼睛需要帮助。“昏星”看上去就像在天空中的明亮的闪光，但是借助一架天文望远镜，你就能看到它是一个美丽的球体——这个行星我们称之为金星。有时候，通过直接的观看（或者听，感觉……）进行学习，这叫做观察。</p>

<p>很多时候，证据并不是一个观察本身，但是观察总是在证据背后支持它。如果发生了一起谋杀，通常没人观察到它（除了凶手和被害者！）。但是侦探能够收集起许多其他的观察，它们可能全都指向一个特定的嫌疑犯。如果一个人的指纹与发现在[凶器]匕首上的指纹相符，这就是他接触过这把匕首的证据。它并没有证明他进行了谋杀，但是当它和其他许多证据联合在一起的时候，它就能起作用。有时候，一个侦探能思考一大堆的观察，然后突然意识到，如果是某某人进行了谋杀，这些观察到的东西就有了条理、可以说得通了。</p>

<p>科学家——发现地球和宇宙中什么是事实的专家——常常像侦探那样工作。他们猜测什么可能是真的（称作假说）。然后他们对自己说：假如它们是真的，我们应该看见某某。这称作预测。例如，如果这个地球是圆的真的是圆的，我们可以预测一个旅行者一直向一个方向运动，最终应该发现他回到了出发点。当一个医生说你患了麻疹了时候，他并不是看你一眼就看出了麻疹。他对你最初的观看，让他产生了一个假说，即你可能患了麻疹。然后，他对自己说，如果她患了麻疹，我应该看到……然后，他针对一系列的预测，用他的眼睛（你的身上起了斑点吗？）、手（你的额头热吗？）和耳朵（听诊肺部有麻疹的表现吗？）进行检验。只有做完这些工作之后，他才能做出决定并说：“我诊断出这个孩子患了麻疹。”有时候医生还需要作其他的检验，诸如验血或者X光。这些检验能帮助它们的眼睛、手和耳朵进行观察。</p>

<p>科学家使用证据学习这个世界的方法，比我在这封短信中说的更机敏也更复杂。但是现在我想继续谈谈证据。证据是相信某事的一个好的理由，它让你对相信某事的坏的理由产生警觉。这些坏的理由叫做“传统”、“权威”和“启示”。</p>

<p>首先说传统。几个月前，我去电视台和大约50个儿童参加一场讨论，电视台邀请这些儿童，是因为他们是在不同的宗教中长大的。一些孩子被作为基督徒培养，其他的作为犹太教徒、穆斯林、印度教徒或者锡克教徒。拿着麦克风的人问了一个又一个儿童他们信什么。他们的回答恰恰显示了我说的“传统”是什么意思。他们的信仰和证据无关。他们只是炫耀着他们的父母和祖父母的信仰——这些信仰同样也不是建立在证据的基础上的。他们这样说道：“我们印度教徒相信某某”； “我们穆斯林相信某某”；“我们基督徒相信的又是某某”。</p>

<p>当然，既然他们全都相信不同的事物，他们不可能全都是正确的。拿着麦克风的人似乎认为这很正确和合适，他甚至不会试图让他们相互争辩他们的不同点。但是这不是我现在想要说论点。我只是想问，他们的信仰从何而来。它们来自传统。传统的意思是，信仰从祖父母传给父母，再传给孩子，然后继续传下去。或者意思是一些书一个世纪一个世纪地流传下去。传统的信仰常常起源于虚无；或许起初是某人创作了它们，就像关于托尔和宙斯的故事。但是它们流传了许多世纪之后，仅仅是因为它们如此古老，所以它们就显得特别。人们相信一些事物，仅仅是因为人们相信这些事物已经很多世纪了。那就是传统。</p>

<p>传统存在的问题在于，不管这个故事创作了多久，它仍然像原始的故事一样真实或者虚假。如果你创作了一个假的故事，让它流传很多个世纪，丝毫不能让它变得更真实！</p>

<p>在英国，许多人接受英国国教的浸礼，但是它仅仅是基督教宗教的一个分支。还有其他分支，诸如俄国东正教、罗马天主教和卫理公会派。他们全都相信不同的事物。犹太人的宗教和穆斯林的宗教更加不同；并且还有不同类型的犹太教徒和穆斯林。一些人相信的东西稍微有点不同，他们因为这种意见不合而进行战争。因此，你也许会认为他们一定有些很好的理由——证据——去相信那些他们所相信的东西。但是，实际上他们不同的信仰完全是因为不同的传统。</p>

<p>让我们谈谈一个特别的传统。罗马天主教相信耶稣的母亲玛利亚非常特别，以至于她没有死，而是活着升上了天堂。其他基督教传统不同意这个说法，它们说玛利亚确实像其他人那样死去了。和罗马天主教不同，其他的教派并不太谈论玛利亚，并且他们也不把她称为“天后”。玛利亚的肉身升入天堂的这个传统并非很古老。圣经没说到她是怎么死的；事实上，这个可怜的女人几乎没有在圣经中被提到。玛利亚的肉身升入天堂的这个信仰，是在耶稣时代之后的6个世纪才被发明出来的。起先，它被人创作出来，创作的方式和任何其他故事一样，比如《白雪公主》。但是，经过数个世纪之后，它变成了一个传统，而人们开始认真接受这个故事，仅仅是因为这个故事已经流传了这么多代。传统越老，就会有更多的人认真接受它。它最终以文字的形式成为正式的罗马天主教信仰，只不过是近来的事——在 1950年。那时候我的年龄和你现在差不多大。但是，这个信仰在1950年并不比在玛利亚死后600年这个信仰被创作出来的时候更真实。</p>

<p>在这封信的末尾我还要谈传统，并且是用另一种方式看待它。但是，首先我必须谈谈另外两个相信某事的坏理由：权威和启示。</p>

<p>权威是相信某事的理由。它的意思是，因为你被某个重要的人告知要相信某事，所以你相信了它。在罗马天主教会，教皇是最重要的人，人们相信他一定是正确的，因为他是教皇。在伊斯兰教会的一派中，重要的人是蓄着胡须的老年男子，称作阿亚图拉。这个国家的许多年轻穆斯林准备进行一场谋杀，仅仅是因为一个遥远国家的阿亚图拉告诉他们这样做（那时候对萨尔曼·拉什迪(Salman Rushdie)的死亡追杀令是很著名的新闻事件。——原注）。</p>

<p>当我说到仅仅是在1950年罗马天主教才最终说他们要相信玛利亚的肉身升入了天堂，我的意思是，在1950年，教皇告诉人们，他们要相信这件事。就是这样。教皇说它是真的，那么它就是真的。现在，或许教皇一生中说的一些事是真的，而另一些是假的。并没有好的理由让你相信他所说的一切，胜过相信其他人说的一切，仅仅是因为他是教皇。现任教皇（1995年）命令他的信徒不要限制生育的数量。如果人们像教皇希望的那样，绝对服从这种权威，结果将是可怕的饥荒、疾病和战争，这都是由人口过多引起的。</p>

<p>当然，甚至在科学中，有时候我们自己没有发现证据，并且我们要接受别人说的东西。我自己没有用肉眼看到光以每秒18.6万英里（30万公里）的速度运动的证据。相反，我相信告诉我光速的那些书。这看起来像“权威”。但是，实际上它比权威好多了，因为写书的人看到了证据，并且任何人无论何时都可以自由地查验证据。那很令人欣慰。但是即便是牧师，也不会声称玛利亚的肉身升入天堂的故事有任何证据。</p>

<p>相信任何事的第三个坏理由称作“启示”。假如你在1950年问教皇，他如何知道玛利亚的肉身在人间消失，进入了天堂，他可能会说上帝已经“启示”给他了。他把自己关在他的房间里，祈祷上帝给他指导。他全靠自己想啊想啊，然后他内心越来越清楚。当教徒内心感到某事一定是正确的，即便没有证据表明它是正确的，他们就把他们的感觉称作“启示”。声称拥有启示的并非只有教皇。许多教徒也这样做。这是他们相信那些他们所相信的事的主要理由。但是这是个好理由吗？</p>

<p>假设我告诉你，你养的小狗死了。你将非常难过，你或许会说，“是真的吗？你怎么知道？它是怎么死的？”现在，假设我回到说：“事实上我并不知道佩佩（Pepe）死了。我没有证据。我只是在内心深处有一个可笑的感觉：它死了。”你会因为我惊吓了你而非常生气，因为你知道一个内心“感觉”本身不是相信一条惠比特犬死了的好理由。你需要证据。我们有时候都有内心感觉，有时候它们是对的，有时候它们不对。总之，不同的人有相反的感觉，那么我们如何认定哪个感觉是正确的？确认一条狗死了的唯一方法，是看到它死了，或者听到它的心脏停止了跳动，或者某人看到或者听到了一些真正的证据表明它死了，这个人告诉了你。</p>

<p>人们有时候说你必须相信内心深处的感觉，否则，你永远也不会相信诸如“我的妻子爱我”这样的事。但是这是一个坏论证。可以有充分的证据证明某人爱你。你和爱你的某人经历的全部时光中，你看到和听到许多小小的珍贵证据，它们加在一起就能说明问题。这不完全是像牧师称之为启示的那种内心的感觉，有一些外在的事物支持内心的感觉：四目相交、温柔的语调、小小的关怀和亲切；这才是真实的证据。</p>

<p>有时候人们内心有一个强烈的感觉，认为某人爱着他们，尽管这不是基于任何证据的。那么，他们很可能是完全错了。有一些人内心强烈感到一个著名的电影明星爱着他们，尽管这个电影明星事实上根本没有见过他们。这样的人的精神有问题。内心感觉必须被证据支持，否则你就不能信任它们。</p>

<p>内心感觉在科学上也很有价值，但是仅仅在它给了你一些想法，你后来通过寻找证据检验了它之后，它才是有价值的。一个科学家对于“感觉”一个想法是对的有种“预感”。这种感觉本身不是相信某事的好理由。但是它可以成为花些时间做个特定实验、或者用一个特定方式寻找证据的好理由。科学家总是用内心感觉获得想法。但是直到这些想法被证据支持，它们才有价值。</p>

<p>我刚才答应你再谈谈传统，并且是用另一种方式。我想试着解释为什么传统对我们如此重要。所有被（一个称为进化的过程）造就的动物都能在这类动物能生存的普通环境中生存。狮子被造就成可以在非洲平原上生存得很好。小龙虾可以在淡水中生存得很好，而龙虾被造就成能在海水中很好得生活。人也是动物，并且我们被造就成能在一个充满了……其他人的世界中很好得生活。我们“游”过“人海”。就像鱼需要用鳃在水中生存，人们需要大脑，大脑让他们能够与其他人打交道。证据海里充满咸水，人海中充满了需要学习的难事。就像语言。</p>

<p>你说英语，但是你的朋友安—凯瑟琳（Ann-Kathrin）说德语。你们都说能让你们“游过”你们各自的“人海”的语言。语言是由传统传递的。没有其它的传递方式。在英国，佩佩是一只狗（dog）。在德国，它是“ein Hund”。这些词哪个都不更正确，或者更真实。它们都只是被传下来的。为了能够善于“在他们的人海中游泳”，儿童需要学习他们自己国家的语言，以及关于他们的人民的其它一些事。这意味着他们必须吸收大量的传统信息，就像吸墨水纸。（记住，传统信息仅仅意味着它们是从祖父母传给父母，再传给儿女的。）儿童的大脑是传统信息的吸收者。并且不能指望儿童把好的和有用的传统信息（例如语言的词汇），从坏的和愚蠢的传统信息（例如相信女巫、魔鬼以及永生的处女的存在）中挑出来。</p>

<p>这很遗憾，但是事情只能是这样，即因为儿童是传统信息的吸收器，他们很可能相信任何大人们告诉它们的事情——不管真伪对错。大人告诉他们的很多东西是真的，并且是基于证据的，或者至少是通情达理的。但是如果大人告诉的某事是假的、愚蠢的，甚至是邪恶的，也没法制止儿童相信它。现在，当儿童长大之后，他们做什么？当然，他们会把它告诉下一代儿童。因此，一旦人们强烈的相信某事——即便它完全是假的，首先也从来没有任何相信它的理由——这件事就能一直存在。</p>

<p>宗教也能发生这种情况吗？相信有一个或者多个上帝、相信天堂、相信玛利亚永生、相信耶稣从来没有一个人类父亲、相信其道者能得到回报、相信葡萄酒变成了血——这些信仰没有一个得到任何好的证据的支持。然而数以百万计的人们相信它们。或许这是因为在年轻得足以相信任何事的年龄，有人要他们相信这些事。</p>

<p>还有数以百万计的人相信截然不同的事，因为在童年有人告诉了他们不同的事。穆斯林儿童被告知的事不同于基督教儿童的。他们长大之后都彻底相信他们是正确的，其他人是错的。即使是在基督教内部，罗马天主教徒、英国国教徒、圣公会教徒、震颤派教徒、教友派教徒、摩门教徒和圣滚者信仰的东西也不一样，并且他们都彻底相信他们是对的，其他人是错的。他们相信不同东西的原因都来自同一个理由，和你说英语、安—凯瑟琳说德语的理由一样。这些语言在他们的国家都可以使用。但是不同的宗教在他们的国家中都是对的，这就不是事实了，因为不同的宗教声称一些事物，但是它们是相互矛盾的。玛利亚不可能既在南爱尔兰的天主教信仰中活着，又在北爱尔兰的新教信仰中死了。</p>

<p>对于这些问题，我们应该怎么做？你做什么都不容易，因为你只有10岁。但是你可以试试这样做。下次有人告诉你听上去很重要的某事的时候，自己想想“这是那种人们或许是因为证据才相信的事吗？或者它是那种人们仅仅是因为传统、权威或者启示才相信的事？”并且，下次有人告诉你某事是真的，为什么不这样问他们：“有什么证据支持它？”如果它们不能给你一个好的答案，我希望你在相信他们说的哪怕一个字之前，先非常仔细地思考一下。</p>

<p>你亲爱的</p>

<p>爸爸</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Others:</strong></p>

<p>李開復 -- “<a href="http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_475b3d560100fc47.html?tj=1">给女儿的一封信</a>”</p>

<p>乐嘉 -- “<a href="http://blog.sina.com.cn/s/blog_4a752e990102e21x.html">写给15岁的女儿 (2012-05-16)</a>”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artist Suspends Objects In Parks Around The World]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/artist-suspends-objects-in-parks-around-the-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T08:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/artist-suspends-objects-in-parks-around-the-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>German artist <a href="http://www.cokonrads.de/">Cornelia Konrads</a> goes around the world installing gravity-defying artworks in natural settings like public parks and private gardens.</p>

<p>Her large-scale installations consist of objects like logs and fences suspended mid-air, giving off the illusion of weightlessness created by an “invisible” force.</p>

<p>Check out her “magical” works displayed in countries like Germany, France and Japan below.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/iv-force/8.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><img src="/images/blog/iv-force/1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/iv-force/3.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/iv-force/4.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/iv-force/5.jpg" alt="" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why China Will Have an Economic Crisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/why-china-will-have-an-economic-crisis/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T13:23:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://mindon.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/why-china-will-have-an-economic-crisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p>投资过剩，房产泡沫，政府负债，银行坏账。 昌盛的国家各有各的繁华，而危机笼罩下的国家，却都是相似的。 都是些老生常谈，争来争去逃不出了钱字。 作者虽非经济学专业人士，但也详尽阐述了一个西方人对于中国经济的看法。
【译言网】全文: <a href="http://select.yeeyan.org/view/205314/255491">时代周刊：为什么中国将发生经济危机</a></p>

<p>The view in most of the world is that China is indestructible. Shrugging off the crises multiplying elsewhere, China seems to surge from strength to strength, its spectacular growth marching on no matter what headwinds may come. It appears inevitable that China will overtake a U.S. mired in debt and division to become the world’s indispensable economy. Those businessmen and policymakers looking to the future believe China’s “state capitalism” may be a superior form of economic organization in dealing with the challenges of the modern global economy.</p>

<p>My answer to all of this is: think again.</p>

<p>I don’t doubt for a second that China will be a major economic superpower with an increasingly influential role in the global economy. In many respects, it already is a superpower. But that doesn’t mean the economy is free from problems, a good number of them created by the very statist system lauded by pundits in the U.S. and Europe. And in my opinion, if China doesn’t change course, and in a big way, the country will experience an economic crisis.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I’ve been thinking about China’s economic future, and the likelihood it will face some sort of terrible collapse, for some time, but I have until now been reluctant to come out with my views so strongly. The reason is that it is very difficult to tell what’s really going on in the Chinese economy. Data is sparse or unreliable. And China is in certain ways unique in economic terms — has history ever witnessed a giant of such massive proportions ascend so quickly in the global economy? Valid precedents are hard to find. Then there is the issue of timing. It is easy to say China will have a crisis; it is almost impossible to say when that might happen. Next month? Next year? Next decade? The fact is China could continue as it is for some time to come. So, in other words, when you make the type of prediction I just have, you have a good chance of getting it just plain wrong.</p>

<p>But the more time I spend in China, the more convinced I am that its current economic system is unsustainable. Yes, economists who specialize in China can give you all sorts of reasons why the country is supposedly different, and thus the regular rules of economics don’t necessarily apply. But one simple thing I always say about economics is that you can’t escape math. If the numbers don’t add up, it doesn’t matter much how big your economy might be or how fast it is growing or how heavy a role the state might play. And China has lots of numbers that just don’t add up.</p>

<p>A big part of the bad math is created by China’s state capitalism. China has adopted a form of the Asian development model, invented by Japan and followed, to varying degrees, by many rapid-growth countries around East Asia. The model, very generally speaking, functions like this: 1) capitalize on low wages to spark growth through exports and industrialize quickly with hefty amounts of investment, 2) guide the whole process with the hand of the state, 3) employ industrial policies and state-directed finance to progress into more and more advanced sectors. This system generates fantastic levels of economic growth for a while, but then eventually, it crashes. Japan had its meltdown beginning in 1990 (and it hasn’t escaped two decades later); South Korea, the country that copied Japan’s model most closely, experienced its crisis in 1997-98.</p>

<p>What happens? The model is based on what Alice Amsden, in her study of the Korean economy, called “getting prices wrong.” To spur on the high levels of investment necessary to generate rapid growth, the model depends on state-directed subsidization to make investing in certain industries or sectors more attractive and less risky than it otherwise would be. Cheap credit is made available for industry, or the state outright orders money to be invested in certain preferred projects. The exchange rate is controlled to encourage exporters. All sorts of subsidies, for energy, exports and so on, are dished out. Banks are not commercially oriented but act to a great degree as tools of government-development policy. All of these methods funnel money, private and public, into industrialization, creating the astronomical growth rates we see again and again in Asia.</p>

<p>The problem here is that prices can’t stay wrong indefinitely. There is a good reason why classical economists are always so focused on allowing markets to find the correct price level. In that way, markets send the proper signals to potential investors on where money should or should not go. If those price indicators are skewed, so is the direction of resources. The Asian model, by playing around with prices, eventually creates tremendous distortions, in which money is wasted and excess capacity is generated. Subsidized companies don’t have to generate returns in the same way as unsubsidized firms, and that leads them to make bad investment decisions to build factories and buildings that are unnecessary and unprofitable. As a result, loans go bad and banking sectors buckle. That’s exactly what happened in both Japan and Korea. Though their crises were tipped off in very different ways — the bursting of an asset bubble in Japan, an external shock in Korea — the reason both countries collapsed was the same: weak banks, indebted companies, silly investments.</p>

<p>China is indulging in all of the same excesses as Japan and Korea, and then some. The level of investment in China, at nearly 50% of GDP, is lofty even by Asian standards. The usual argument made in defense of such astronomical investment in fixed assets is that China is a large developing country that needs all of the buildings and roads it is constructing. Qu Hongbin, the very smart chief China economist at HSBC, made that very argument in a recent study:</p>

<blockquote><p>There is a popular view in the market that China has overinvested and therefore can no longer rely on investment to sustain its growth. We disagree. China’s investment-to-GDP ratio is indeed very high (46%) … [But] China is only half way through the process of urbanisation and industrialisation. It still needs to invest more to cope with the rising demand for rail, hospitals and industrial plants. The recent infrastructure boom has boosted the country’s transport capacity, but China’s railway network is still shorter than that of the US in 1880 … In economic terms, we estimate that China’s capital stock per worker is only about 8% of that of the US and 15% of that of Korea. In other words, China’s capital accumulation is still far from reaching the stage of having diminishing returns; we believe the country needs to invest more, rather than less.</p></blockquote>

<p>I completely agree. Yet the issue is not whether China needs more investment. The issue is whether China is getting the types of investment it requires. The fact that investment levels can be so high and yet the economy is so deficient in certain key aspects makes me think the answer is no. We can see that in the continued problem of excess capacity in China, in which companies go hog wild building too many factories in certain industries, often with borrowing from state banks. That has happened in steel and solar panels, for example. The country is investing hundreds of billions in high-speed railways even though ticket prices are beyond the reach of most Chinese, while many major Chinese cities don’t have subways.</p>

<p>A good part of this misdirected investment seems to be headed into the property sector. Real estate development has become the key driving force of Chinese economic growth. In theory, China’s very rapid urbanization makes such construction a necessity — but that depends on what is being built. In Wenzhou, a real estate agent recently offered free BMWs to anyone who bought a high-end apartment — a clear sign of overbuilding — while there is an obvious shortage of housing affordable for most Chinese. On either side of my Beijing apartment building are three big malls that hardly ever seem to see real shoppers. Rents for top-quality office space in Beijing are now pricier than in New York City — despite the fact that China’s capital is one big construction zone. Many of the buildings going up are of a quality unsuitable for major corporations.</p>

<p>Even worse, much of the investment in China is being financed with debt. The level of debt in the Chinese economy has been rising with frightening speed. Rating agency Fitch estimates bank credit in 2011 was equivalent to 185% of the country’s GDP — an increase of 56 percentage points in a mere three years. Though that surge has not yet had a significant negative impact on China’s banks, many analysts fret that banks will eventually experience a rise in nonperforming loans. In an indication of what is to come, the Financial Times reported recently that the government has ordered banks to roll over the $1.7 trillion of loans owed by local governments. If true, this tells us two key things: 1) these governments invested money raised from banks in projects that are not generating the returns necessary to pay them back and 2) the quality of loans on the banks’ books are more questionable than official statistics suggest. On top of that, the fact that local governments amassed so much debt in the first place shows a complete lack of rule of law in China’s financial sector. Technically, local governments aren’t permitted to borrow money at all. Meanwhile, as government entities run up loans they can’t pay, many small companies, especially private ones, are unable to raise sufficient funds and remain starved of capital.</p>

<p>So we can see the pieces of a crisis falling into place: excessive, misguided investment, including a giant property boom, propelled on by debt and the decisions of government bureaucrats. Sound familiar? A crisis, of course, is not inevitable — if China’s leadership takes action and reorients the direction of the economy. The positive thing is that at least some top policymakers understand the need to change. In policy pronouncement after policy pronouncement, the government pledges to reform. The problem is that China’s government is not taking its own advice. The economy needs to rebalance away from investment and exports to a more consumption-driven growth model with a primary focus on quality of growth, not high rates at any cost. That’s not happening, or not happening quickly enough. Yes, the Chinese consumer is gaining in global importance, but savings in China remains too high and consumption as a percentage of GDP still way too low. Steps that the government could take to spur on the needed rebalancing — reducing lofty taxes on many imported goods, for example — are nowhere to be found. More importantly, the government is doing nothing to set prices right. The currency remains firmly controlled, interest rates unreformed. So investors within China are still acting based on the wrong price signals.</p>

<p>Why won’t China’s policymakers pursue more fundamental reform? They are afraid that growth might slip. Sure, the latest five-year plan targets 7% annual GDP growth, but it seems to me that every time growth drops under double digits, the leadership goes into panic mode and revs up the economy again. GDP surged 8.9% in the fourth quarter of 2011, but that’s not fast enough for China’s leaders. They’ve already started loosening credit again — slathering yet more debt onto the economy.</p>

<p>When I bring up these issues with China watchers, I’m usually scolded — Beijing’s policy mandarins have it all figured out, I’m informed. It is true that China’s policymakers have done a superior job managing the rapidly changing economy in recent years. But as any stock investor knows all too well, past performance does not ensure future performance. Back in the 1970s and ’80s, analysts in the West considered Japan’s bureaucrats near supermen as well. Now the stodgy Japanese bureaucracy is considered one of the main impediments to an economic revival. Chinese bureaucrats today suffer from the same problem that led Japanese bureaucrats astray — they believe the economy can be managed by fiat. The tools of classical economics — getting prices right — are secondary. Why guide an economy with abstract measures like interest rates when you can just tell the banks what to do?</p>

<p>That attitude is what killed Japan’s economic miracle, and now I see China slipping toward the same fate. Japan could not escape the forces of basic mathematics. China can’t either, no matter how brilliant its policymakers might be. When would a meltdown happen? It is interesting to play with a bit of history. Both Japan and Korea suffered their crises roughly 35 years after the Asian development model was switched on — the early 1950s to ’89 in Japan, and 1962 to ’97 in Korea. That puts a China crisis at around 2014-15 or so. I’m not predicting a firm date here. What I am saying is that China is running out of time to fix the problems of its economy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
